\\Empire screen strings

\\Development plans
\*EMDEVPLN DEVELOPMENT PLANS
\*EMNEWPLN ADD NEW PLAN
\*EMPLTCLS PLANET CLASSIFICATION:
\*EMDEVPOL DEVELOPMENT POLICY:
\*EMEMPHAS EMPHASIS:
\*EMADDIFP ADDITIONAL IFP WEIGHT:
\*EMADDPLN ADD PLAN
\*EMCURPLN CURRENT PLANS
\*EMPLTCL2 PLANET CLASSIFICATION
\*EM1STPOL PRIMARY POLICY
\*EM2NDPOL SECONDARY POLICY
\*EM3RDPOL TERTIARY POLICY
\*EMCLRSEL CLEAR SELECTED
\*EMRSQSEL RESCUE SELECTED
\*EMCLRROW CLEAR ROW
\*EMCLRALL CLEAR ALL
\*EMCURCST CURRENT IFP COST:
\*EMLOADPL LOAD DEV PLAN...
\*EMSAVEPL SAVE DEV PLAN...
\*EMDELPLN DELETE PLAN

\\Policies
\*EMPOLICS POLICIES
\*EMPOLCAT SELECT A POLICY CATEGORY:
\*EMPOLPRT POLICY PARTICULARS:
\*EMPOLDTL SELECTED ITEM DETAILS

\\Policy categories
\!EMPOL
\-Colonization
\-Oppressometer
\-Regional Zoning
\-Government Type
\-Labor

\\Policy category choices+descriptions

\\Colonization
\*EMPOLSL1 Select one as the civilization's current expansion / consolidation policy.
\*EMPOL1ON The AI will try to colonize for you based on ships in your Reserves.
\*EMPL1OFF The AI will wait for you to give it orders on where to colonize.
\*EMPL1DSC The colonization AI setting will determine whether or not the AI will send out colony task forces to colonize as soon as they become available in your Reserves. Otherwise the AI will wait for you to tell it which planets to colonize manually. This does not affect how often the AI builds colony ships.

\\Oppressometer
\*EMPOLSL2 Adjust the Oppressometer 
\*EMPL2LOW Currently a setting of %oppressLow% or below is considered low for your empire.
\*EMPL2HGH Currently a setting of %oppressHigh% or above is considered high for your empire.
\*EMPL2DSC The Oppressometer determines how much you oppress your people. The higher you have this setting the more people will become upset but the less likely spies will be able to get in. Setting this at or above the tolerated limit of your government will cause unrest, while setting it below will actually reduce unrest.

\\Regional Zoning
\*EMPOLSL3 Select one as the civilization's regional zoning policy.
\*EMPL3C1S Specialized
\*EMPL3C2S Natural
\*EMPL3C3S Balanced
\*EMPL3DE1 Specialized - Planets governed by this policy will put priority upon developing the most fertile and mineral rich regions as long as the efficiency is 4 or greater. In other regions Industry and Research DEAs will predominantly be built, putting a greater emphasis on research than the other plans. Unfortunately, there is often not enough room to zone Government, Military, or Recreation DEAs except on very large or mineral-poor worlds.
\*EMPL3DE2 Natural - This setting puts the utmost priority upon industry, and consequently mining. Non-resource DEAs are built abundantly in regions with under 7 efficiency, and Development plans are follwed closely. However, this plan can lead to periodic mineral shortages and creates a poor variety of DEAs on anything but the largest planets.
\*EMPL3DE3 Balanced - This policy focuses on Industry but always manages to create a good balance of DEAs on all but the smallest worlds. The Balanced policy always builds a Government, Recreation or Military DEA, but will make exceptions in very resource rich regions. A few rich regions may be used to house non-resource DEAs, using them to their least potential.
\\ Help Text
\*HTREGSP Planets will tend to specialize according to what they're best suited for.
\*HTREGNA Planets will build based on their current needs.
\*HTREGBA Planets will try to be self-sustaining and balance their building.

\\Government Type
\*EMPOLSL4 Select Your Government Type
\*EMPL4DE1 Despotic regimes are good at manufacturing and very strong at protecting national secrets.  Bioharvest at 80%, Mines at 100%, Manufacturing at 120%, Research at 95%, Military at 130%,  Recreation at 95%, Space Ports at 100%, Heavy Foot of Government at +4%, Oppressometer cost at -7%, Optimum Oppressometer at 7, Total Tax at 35%.
\*EMPL4DE2 Monarchies are the strongest manfacturers of all the absolutist governments.  Bioharvest at 80%, Mines at 100%, Manufacturing at 130%, Research at 90%,  Military at 110%, Recreation at 100%, Space Ports at 105%, Heavy Foot of Government at +5%, Oppressometer costs at -6%, Optimum Oppressometer at 5, Total Tax at 37%.
\*EMPL4DE3 Oligarchic regimes are the best absolutist government for research, and suffer less from the heavy foot of government.  Bioharvest at 90%, Mines at 110%, Manufacturing at 100%, Research at 120%, Military at 100%, Recreation at 100%, Space Ports at 105%, Heavy Foot of Government at -1%, Oppressometer costs at +1%, Optimum Oppressometer at 4, Total Tax at 35%. 
\*EMPL4DE4 Constitutional Monarchies are outstanding tax collectors that otherwise tend to perform in an average manner across the board.  Bioharvest at 100%, Mining at 110%, Manufacturing at 110%, Research at 100%, Military at 100%, Recreation at 120%, Space Ports at 100%, Heavy Foot of Government at +0%, Oppressometer costs at +0%, Optimum Oppressometer at 4, Total Tax at 40%.
\*EMPL4DE5 Corporate governments are good at resource acquisition, trading, and keeping unnecessary beaucrocracies to a minimum.  Bioharvest at 120%, Mining at 130%, Manufacturing at 110%, Research at 105%, Military at 80%, Recreation at 110%, Space Ports at 130%, Heavy Foot of Government at -5%, Oppressometer costs at -4%, Optimum Oppressometer at 4, Total Tax at 35%. 
\*EMPL4DE6 Democratic governments are very good at research and recreation, but the openness of their society makes them vulnerable to spies.  Bioharvest at 115%, Mining at 110%, Manufacturing at 110%, Research at 130%, Military at 90%, Recreation at 120%,  Space Ports at 110%, Heavy Foot of Government at -1%, Oppressometer costs at +12%, Optimum Oppressometer at 2, Total Tax at 35%.
\*EMPL4DE7 Parliamentary governments have few weaknesses and are optimized for industrial output.  Bioharvest at 100%, Mining at 120%, Manufacturing at 130%, Research at 105%, Military at 100%, Recreation at 100%, Space Ports at 105%, Heavy Foot of Government at +2%, Oppressometer costs at +9%, Optimum Oppressometer at 3, Total Tax at 35%.
\*EMPL4DE8 Republican regimes are strong manufacturers, and the best representative government at monitoring enemy spies, but poor at tax collecting.  Bioharvest at 100%, Mining at 120%, Manufacturing at 120%, Research at 105%, Space Ports at 95%, Heavy Foot of Government at +2%, Oppressometer costs at +11%, Optimum Oppressometer 5, Total Tax at 30%. 
\*EMPL4DE9 Hives are strong in most areas of government, particularly manufacturing.  They are, however, poor traders and bad tax collectors.  Bioharvest at 115%, Mining at 120%, Manufacturing at 145%, Research at 105%, Military at 140%, Recreation at 85%, Space Ports at 85%, Heavy Foot of Government at -10%, Oppressometer costs at -12%, Optimum Oppressometer 5, Total Tax 30%. 
\*EMPL4DE0 Unification governments are strong in most areas, particularly research and tax collection.  Bioharvest at 110%, Mining at 115%,  Manufacturing at 105%, Research at 155%, Military at 130%, Recreation at 100%, Space Ports at 105%, Heavy Foot of Government at -10%, Oppressometer costs at -10%, Optimum Oppressometer at 4, Total Tax at 40%.
\*EMPL4CHG Change

\\Labor
\*EMPOLSL5 Adjust Your Labor Policy
\*EMPOL5FL Forced Labor: 
\*EMPOL5YS Allowed
\*EMPOL5NO Disallowed
\*EMPL5LOW Currently a slider setting of %laborLow% or below is considered low for your empire.
\*EMPL5HGH Currently a slider setting of %laborHigh% or above is considered high for your empire.
\*EMPL5DSC The forced labor setting either allows or disallows your empire to create forced labor units out of captured population. When the setting is set to allow this occurs automatically, and if it is set to disallowed any currently held units will be freed. The slider adjusts how harshly you work any forced labor units you currently control, but decreases their lifespans the harder they are worked. Forced Labor increases the output of any DEA they are assigned to, but increase pollution levels and may cause resource shortfalls.


