\\ Strings for Planetary enums

\\Bio-diversity
\!BIODV
\-Homogeneous
\-Similar
\-Heterogeneous
\-Diverse
\-Very Diverse

\\Fertility
\!PLFRT
\-None
\-Toxic
\-Hostile
\-Barren
\-Subsistence
\-Hard Scrabble
\-Arable
\-Fertile
\-Alluvial
\-Lush

\\FLU Jobs
!FLUJB
\-Mining
\-Farming
\-Military
\-Industry
\-Recreation
\-Economic
\-Government
\-Social
\-Scientific

\\DEA types
\!DEATP
\-None
\-Bioharvest
\-Mining
\-Industry
\-Research
\-Government
\-Military
\-Recreation
\-Space Port

\\DEA names
\!DEANM
\-Non
\-Bioharvest DEA
\-Mining DEA
\-Industry DEA
\-Research DEA
\-Government DEA
\-Military DEA
\-Recreation DEA
\-Space Port

\\DEA descriptions
\!DEADP
\-Not a valid DEA
\-This DEA produces Food based on the fertility of the region it occupies and AUs from rare bioharvest byproducts based on biodiversity. While generally less profitable and requiring a larger workforce than Mining DEAs, Bioharvest DEAs are inexpensive and become more profitable on a planet with low pollution absorption, high habitability, large populations or low government presence. Unfortunately until the proper technologies are discovered this DEA can not be built on planets of habitability yellow or lower. This DEA requires a moderate amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 50/p
  Base Efficiency is determined by fertility/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 1/p/p

  GDP Income Generated per Bioharvest:/p
  Food Value: 10 AUs/p
  Industrial Value: 5 AUs/p
  Surplus Value: 2.5 AUs/p
  
\-This DEA produces Minerals based on the mineral richness of the region it occupies and AUs from rare mineral byproducts (like gold and gems). Mining DEAs, while expensive, require small workforces to run but can often push the pollution absorption of a planet to its limits. This DEA functions well on planets with high ecosystem density, low populations, and high taxes or governmental presence. This DEA requires a low amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 100/p
  Base Efficiency is Determined by Mineral Richness/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 0.5/p/p

  GDP Income Generated per Mineral:/p
  Food Value: 3.5 AUs/p
  Industrial Value: 7 AUs/p
  Surplus Value: 3.5 AUs/p/p
  Pollution Generated per Mineral: 2

\-This DEA's potential is measured in Cement, which allows and controls the cost of making production points and generates AUs. Manufacturing DEAs tend to be less profitable than other DEAs, especially in resource rich regions, but eventually becomes unsurpassed as technology increases. This DEA functions best on planets with high pollution absorption, large populations or resource richness. This DEA requires a high amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 150/p
  Base Efficiency is 10/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 1.5/p/p

  GDP Cement Value: 5 AUs/p/p
  Pollution Generated per AU Spent on Production: 1
\-This DEA's potential is measured in Test Tubes, which allows and controls the cost of making research points. This DEA requires a low amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 150/p
  Base Efficiency is 10/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 0.5
\-This DEA has two effects: 1) Increases the efficiency of taxation and regional economic infrastructure, and 2) Increases unrest reduction. A Government DEA's sphere of influence depends on which seat of government is located there. For an empire seat, this influence can extend all the way out to adjacent solar systems. Due to its large population requirements this DEA is best suited to planets with high populations, and has large diminishing returns and unrest reduction at lower levels of technology. This DEA requires a high amount of manpower to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 150/p
  Base Efficiency is 1/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 1.5/p/p

  Outreach Extends to Entire Planet
\-This DEA houses military forces that keep the unsavory elements of society under control. A Military DEA greatly decreases unrest on the planet it is built and has a diminishing outreach effect that can extend all the way to adjacent systems. This DEA has the largest unrest reduction effects at lower technology levels, but is eventually surpassed by Recreation DEAs. This DEA is well suited for planets with high employment bonuses or infrastructure. This DEA This DEA requires a moderate amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 100/p
  Base Efficiency is 1/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 1/p/p

  Unrest Reduction Outreach:/p
  No Capacity Improvements: Region/p
  One or Two Capacity Improvements: Planet/p
  Three Capacity Improvements: System/p
  Four Capacity Improvements: Adjacent Systems

\-This DEA provides a place for the weary to relax after a long days toil. An upgraded Recreation DEA can greatly reduce unrest in planets as far as adjacent solar systems. This DEA has a larger unrest reduction effect than Government DEAs while requiring a third of the workforce. Like Military DEAs, this DEA functions best on planets with high employment bonuses and infrastructure. This DEA requires a moderate amount of population to run./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 50/p
  Base Efficiency is 3/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 1/p/p

  Unrest Reduction Outreach:/p
  Zero or One Capacity Improvements: Planet/p
  Two Capacity Improvements: System/p
  Three Capacity Improvements: Adjacent Systems
\-This building allows trade to occur with other Spaceports. Trade generates revenue that can be taxed. Like fax machines, the more Spaceports that are in existence, the more useful they become. Some treaties can even open the borders of different civilizations to trade, providing bonuses to interstellar trade profits, especially if they are of another race./p/p

  Base DEA Cost is 300/p
  Base Efficiency is 3/p
  Employees Required for 100% Productivity is 0.25/p
  Minimum Population Required to Build is 3/p/p

  Interstellar Trade Bonuses:/p
  Different Species Bonus: 50%/p
  Different Civilizations Bonus: 50%
  

\\DEA requests
\!DEARQ
\-No request 
\-Farming DEA request
\-Mining DEA request
\-Industry DEA request
\-Research DEA request
\-Government DEA request
\-Military DEA request
\-Recreation DEA request
\-Space Port request

\\Planet gravity
\!PlGrv
\-Negligible
\-Low
\-Moderate
\-High
\-Extreme

\\For planets screen
\*PLSCGRUN Unknown Gravity
\*PLSCGRA0 Negligible Gravity
\*PLSCGRA1 Low Gravity
\*PLSCGRA2 Moderate Gravity
*PLSCGRA3 High Gravity
\*PLSCGRA4 Crushing Gravity

\\Terrain Type
\!TRTYP
\-Plains
\-Broken
\-Mountains

\\For planets screen
\*PLSCPLAI Plains
\*PLSCBROK Broken
\*PLSCMOUN Mountains

\\Mineral rating
\!MINER
\-Very Poor
\-Poor
\-Average
\-Rich
\-Very Rich
\-Ultra-rich

\\Habitability
\!PLHAB
\-Unknown
\-Paradise
\-Sweet Spot
\-Green 1
\-Green 2
\-Yellow 1
\-Yellow 2
\-Red 1
\-Red 2

\\For planets screen
\*PLSCHAB0 Paradise Hab. Zone
\*PLSCHAB1 Sweet Spot
\*PLSCHAB2 Green 1 Hab. Zone
\*PLSCHAB3 Green 2 Ha. Zone
\*PLSCHAB4 Yellow 1 Hab. Zone
\*PLSCHAB5 Yellow 2 Hab. Zone
\*PLSCHAB6 Red 1 Hab. Zone
\*PLSCHAB7 Red 2 Hab. Zone

\\Planetary types
\!PLTYP
\-Jovian
\-Primordial
\-Protostar
\-Bio-arctic
\-Terra Approxima
\-Venusian
\-Ice Ball
\-Martian
\-VolcanicRock

\\Planet classifications
\!PLCLS
\-No Class
\-All Planets
\-Frontier
\-Secondary
\-Primary
\-Core
\-Red Ring
\-Yellow Ring
\-Green Ring
\-Paradise
\-Sweet Spot
\-Mineral Poor
\-Mineral Rich
\-Low Biodiversity
\-High Biodiversity
\-Small
\-Large
\-Mining
\-Farming
\-Manufacturing
\-Research
\-Military
\-Recreation
\-New
\-Newly Conquered
\-Newly Acquired
\-Ravaged
\-Unrest
\-Besieged
\-Starving
\-Trade
\-Player Defined1
\-Player Defined2
\-Player Defined3
\-Player Defined4
\-Player Defined5

\\Unrest state
\!UNRST
\-Content
\-Unrest Level 1
\-Unrest Level 2
\-Unrest Level 3
\-Revolt
\-Subjugated

\\DEA build status
\!DEABS
\-Planned
\-In Progress
\-Built

\\FLU count formats
\!FLUCF
\-%FLUs% Organic FLU
\-
\-%FLUs% Organic FLUs
\-


