\*Event001 Event: Some Drifting Debris has been discovered which has allowed us to complete the %Value1% project early.
\*Event002 Event: A wandering merchant has sold us plans to the %Value1% project. It's been completed early due to the information we learned.
\*Event003 Event: Debris from a pre-New Orion warship was uncovered.  The debris supplied surprising insight into the %Value1% project.
\*Event004 Event: Many of our scientists have gotten together to share ideas and compare research. The result has been an increase of Research Points Empire wide./p/p
Research Efficiency is Increased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event005 Event: Recent discoveries have resulted in an increase in our empire wide research efforts./p/p
Research Efficiency is Increased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event006 Event: A special symposium of scientists was convened to discuss radical scientific theories.  The new ideas generated by the conference have given research a boost./p/p
Research Efficiency is Increased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event007 Event: A child genius appeared out of nowhere and offered stunning insights into the %Value1% project.
\*Event008 Event: Stunning innovations have resulted in major progress in the %Value1% project.
\*Event009 Event: The debris of an ancient warship offered surprising insights into the %Value1% project.  The origin of the vessel is unknown.
\*Event010 Event: During a symposium of scientists, an argument over research methods broke out. The arguments resulted in new ideas coming to light and an increase in our research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Increased by 25% for up to 5 turns
\*Event011 Event: An accident at a pharmaceutical plant caused experimental drugs to be given to our scientists. The result has been extraordinary breakthroughs in our research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event012 Event: A group of aliens has emerged from nowhere. They have been performing publicly in exchange for aid in returning home. Our unrest has decreased on %Value1%. /p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event013 Event: A washed-out, almost-forgotten entertainer emerged from obscurity with a smash hit.  Her performances have lowered unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event014 Event: Many of our local performers have gained fame and are doing charity concerts. Their performances are lowering unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event015 Event: Alien performers have been performing all over the empire. Their performances have decreased our citizen's unrest./p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event016 Event: A legendary entertainer has been performing for our empire lowering unrest./p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event017 Event: A new artist, specializing in creating antimatter explosions in the sky has appeared. Her performances have reduced unrest for our citizens./p/p
Unrest is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event018 Event: A small program to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success!/p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event019 Event: Good News! The "No Red Tape" program to reduce our Heavy Foot of Government has met with success./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event020 Event: By streamlining our paperwork we've managed to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event021 Event: The moderate "Shorter Lines, Faster Response" program to reduce HFoG met with success./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 8% for up to 5 turns
\*Event022 Event: A moderate program to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 8% for up to 5 turns
\*Event023 Event: Good News! Our recent efforts to streamline our paperwork have resulted in reducing the Heavy Foot of Government!/p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 8% for up to 5 turns
\*Event024 Event: Great News! The recent "Electronic Access For Everyone" campaign to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government was successful./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 12% for up to 5 turns
\*Event025 Event: A major program started recently to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has been successful./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 12% for up to 6 turns
\*Event026 Event: Sir! Our recent attempts to reduce the amount of paperwork we use have resulted in also reducing the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 12% for up to 6 turns
\*Event027 Event: A massive program to lessen our Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 12% for up to 6 turns
\*Event028 Event: The massive "Automated Administration" campaign to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government was a brilliant success./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 20% for up to 10 turns
\*Event029 Event: Our reduction in paperwork has resulted in also reducing the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
Heavy Foot of the Government is Decreased by 20% for up to 10 turns
\*Event030 Event: Miners demanding higher pay have gone on strike.  Mining production on %Value1% has been reduced./p/p
Mining Efficiney is Reduced by 25% for up to 5 turns
\*Event031 Event: A coalition of miners on %Value1% have gone on strike reducing our mining production./p/p
Mining Efficiney is Reduced by 25% for up to 5 turns
\*Event032 Event: The miners on %Value1% have refused to work until their employers approve pay raises. Mining production has been reduced on that planet./p/p
Mining Efficiney is Reduced by 25% for up to 5 turns
\*Event033 Event: Pests from a visiting freighter escaped the biocontainment perimeter and began breeding out of control.  Agricultural output on %Value1% has been reduced./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiney is Reduced by 30% for up to 5 turns
\*Event034 Event: An infestation of pests has occurred on %Value1% and has reduced the agriculture output of the planet./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiney is Reduced by 30% for up to 5 turns
\*Event035 Event: Several creatures have escaped on %Value1%. They're eating the crops and will reduce the agricultural output of the planet until they've been contained./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiney is Reduced by 30% for up to 5 turns
\*Event036 Event: Citing extreme safety hazards, miners refused to return to work on %Value1%.  Mining production has fallen drastically./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event037 Event: The mining production has fallen drastically on %Value1% due to safety hazards./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event038 Event: Safety hazards have arisen on %Value1%. Mining production has been reduced until the cleanup is complete./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event039 Event: An infestation of pests has occurred on %Value1% and has reduced the agriculture output of the planet drastically./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event040 Event: Large locust type creatures have descended on %Value1% and are eating the crops. The agricultural output of the planet has been greatly reduced./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event041 Event: The harvest on %Value1% has been greatly reduced due to an infestation of pests not native the environment. Cleanup is underway./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event042 Event: Miners throughout on %Value1% left their jobs and began picketing their employers' headquarters.  Mining production has decreased./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 70% for up to 12 turns
\*Event043 Event: Mining production on %Value1% has been reduced due to worker strikes. Negotiations are underway./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 70% for up to 12 turns
\*Event044 Event: The production on %Value1% has been greatly disrupted due to a worker revolt./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 70% for up to 12 turns
\*Event045 Event: A plague of alien vermin devastated an entire continent's croplands on %Value1%. The problem has been contained but agricultural output has been drastically reduced./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns
\*Event046 Event: An infestation of pests has wiped out an entire continents agricultural output on %Value1% for the turn./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns
\*Event047 Event: The largest continent on %Value1% has had its agricultural output grind to a halt due to an infestation of insects./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns
\*Event048 Event: Miners on %Value1% quit their jobs today in a labor dispute. Mining production fell drastically on the planet./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 90% for up to 12 turns
\*Event049 Event: Due to a worker revolt the production on %Value1% has been drastically reduced./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 90% for up to 12 turns
\*Event050 Event: A failed labor dispute has brought worker production on %Value1% to a grinding halt. Negotiators are working on the problem./p/p
Mining Efficiency is Reduced by 90% for up to 12 turns
\*Event051 Event: Alien vermin escaped from a visiting freighter and has devastated the agricultural output of %Value1%. Starvation is almost guaranteed./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 95% for up to 12 turns
\*Event052 Event: A plague of insects have almost completely destroyed the agricultural output of %Value1%./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 95% for up to 12 turns
\*Event053 Event: The agricultural output on %Value1% has been destroyed due to ravenous insects that have descended onto the planet./p/p
Bioharvest Efficiency is Reduced by 95% for up to 12 turns
\*Event054 Event: Disruption of neural networks caused by playful AI's led to corrupted research data, which caused a minor, empire-wide slowdown in research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event055 Event: The artificial intelligence units being used to compile our research have failed and caused an empire wide slowdown in research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event056 Event: The processing units being used for our research have proven faulty. The correlation of data has been reduced causing a slowdown in our research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event057 Event: Several assumptions by our research staff have proven to be false. Research Empire wide has slowed down accordingly./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event058 Event: Our research has slowed down empire wide due to mistakes made by our research staff./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event059 Event: One of our newer scientists has come up with some bizarre conclusions. Research has slowed down while we disprove his theories./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 15% for up to 5 turns
\*Event060 Event: An undetected machine fault created a malicious AI.  The rogue caused a significant slowdown in research before it was isolated and eliminated./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event061 Event: A faulty AI unit has destroyed a research data. Our research has been slowed while the problem was resolved./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event062 Event: A mechanical glitch has resulted in lost research data. Our research production has been slowed while scientists sort through the mess./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event063 Event: The lead researcher for the %Value1% project has gone rogue and refused to contribute to the project any longer.  As a result, the project suffered a setback.
\*Event064 Event: The %Value1% project has suffered a major setback due to the lead researcher who has quit the project.
\*Event065 Event: The lead researcher for the %Value1% project has quit causing a setback in the project.
\*Event066 Event: Our research staff has become preoccupied by several important new theories. Empire research levels have slowed down accordingly./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 40% for up to 5 turns
\*Event067 Event: Several new theories made by research staff have turned out to be false. Research production has dropped while scientists disproved the claims./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 40% for up to 5 turns
\*Event068 Event: The scientific theories that some of our research was based on have been disproven. Research has slowed while our scientists update their calculations./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 40% for up to 5 turns
\*Event069 Event: Destructive AI's have gone on a rampage and destroyed months of work in our research facilities. Empire wide research has been drastically affected./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event070 Event: Some of our AI's collecting research data have proven to be faulty. The loss of data has had a devastating effect on our research progress./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event071 Event: A faulty AI in our research storage facility has caused a major setback in our research. An empire wide slowdown has been caused while researchers repair the damage./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event072 Event: Most of the team on the %Value1% project has taken ill causing a setback in the project.
\*Event073 Event: The %Value1% project has taken a setback due to most of the research staff becoming infected with an unknown virus.
\*Event074 Event: A virus has infected most of the staff working on the %Value1% project. The setbacks resulting are unavoidable.
\*Event075 Event: A well-respected researcher has disproven several of the theories our research was based on. A major reduction in research has resulted./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event076 Event: Our theories on Biochemical's have been proven false causing a drastic slowdown in our overall research./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event077 Event: Our main research data center has been destroyed due to a fire. Our collection of research has slowed down drastically as a result./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event078 Event: Destructive AI's have gone on a rampage and destroyed years of work in our research facilities. It'll take us years to repair the damage./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event079 Event: The AI at our research collection facility has destroyed all the data. The setback to our research facilities has been devastating./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event080 Event: An AI chip in our research storage facilities has caused wiped out years of data due to false commands. The effects are devastating./p/p
Research Efficiency is Decreased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event081 Event: Whispered rumors in %Value1% claimed that local pirates acquired an ancient Antaran Star Killer.  Panic ensued throughout the system./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event082 Event: Fear has been caused in the %Value1% system due to rumors of space pirates. Unrest has increased./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event083 Event: Panic has been caused in the %Value1% system by rumors of space pirates operating there. The rumors are causing unrest there./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event084 Event: Local starliners have been disappearing in the %Value1% system. It's rumored the space pirates are the cause and unrest has resulted./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event085 Event: Rumors of space pirates destroyed ships circulated in the %Value1% system causing unrest./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event086 Event: Local rumors point to pirates as the cause of the missing ships in the %Value1% system. Unrest has increased in that area./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event087 Event: Pirates in the %Value1% system have threatened to destroy the star. Our military is dealing with the situation but it's caused unrest./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event088 Event: Pirates have threatened several of the planets in the %Value1% system. Panic is sweeping the system./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event089 Event: The %Value1% system has been threatened by pirates, panicking the local citizens. Unrest has been increased./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event090 Event: Our diplomatic ability has improved as a result of educational reforms./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event091 Event: Some recent improvements made in our educational system have resulted in an improvement of our diplomatic abilities./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event092 Event: Our diplomatic abilities have been improved. The reported cause is a better understanding between races due to educational reforms./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event093 Event: A program of exchanging educators with alien societies has led to improvements in relations with other empires./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event094 Event: Our relations with other empires have improved due to a recent educator exchange reform./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event095 Event: Recent educational improvements have resulted in better relations with other races due to a better understanding of one another./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event096 Event: An increase in students studying at alien universities greatly increased awareness.  As a result, relations with alien races were vastly improved./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event097 Event: Students studying at alien universities have resulted in an empire wide appreciation of foreign languages and cultures. Relations with alien races have improved./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event098 Event: A new student exchange program with other races has improved our relations with other empires./p/p
Diplomacy Gains are Increased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event099 Event: In a targeted strike by terrorists against our command fortress, the leader %Value1% has been wounded. He's not expected to survive.
\*Event100 Event: Sir! There's been an accident. %Value1% has been wounded and is not expected to survive.
\*Event101 Event: One of your leaders in the high council has been wounded. %Value1% is hurt badly.
\*Event102 Event: In a successful targeted strike against his command vessel, the leader %Value1% of our forces has been killed.
\*Event103 Event: The leader %Value1% has suffered a horrible accident. He's not expected to survive.
\*Event104 Event: A terrorist spy has infiltrated our command post. %Value1% has been poisoned and isn't expected to survive the night.
\*Event105 Event: Buggy translation software has caused diplomatic problems when alien ambassadors became impatient with the device. Our relations have decreased./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 30% for up to 12 turns
\*Event106 Event: In the middle of our recent diplomatic talks the translator broke down. The dialog it issued insulted the other ambassador and lowered our relations./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 30% for up to 12 turns
\*Event107 Event: Our relations with several races have been lowered due to faulty translation equipment spewing out gibberish during an important talk./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 30% for up to 12 turns
\*Event108 Event: Alien ambassadors were upset when severe bugs in our translation software caused the machine to display a blue error screen every fifteen minutes./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event109 Event: Our relations with several ambassadors were lowered when our translation equipment broke down, wasting their trip./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event110 Event: Alien ambassadors have become dismayed when us when bugs in our translation equipment caused our recent talks to break down to insults./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event111 Event: A bug in our translation software caused a statement of goodwill to be incorrectly translated as an insult against the ambassador's mother. Diplomatic relations have fallen./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event112 Event: Diplomatic relations dropped drastically today when our software began insulting the alien ambassadors./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event113 Event: The alien ambassadors visiting left in disgust when the translation software translated a greeting into one of the oldest insults./p/p
Diplomacy Losses are Increased by 80% for up to 12 turns
\*Event114 Event: An accidental release of experimental nanobots has led to major damage on %Value1%.  
\*Event115 Event: Experimental Nanites have escaped from a facility on %Value1% destroying most of what was in their path.
\*Event116 Event: Major damage has been reported on %Value1% where experimental nanobots escaped into the cities.
\*Event117 Event: Wandering religious zealots were found to be speaking out against our way of life.  The problem was contained but has caused unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 15 for 1 turn
\*Event118 Event: Unrest has risen on %Value1% when terrorists speaking out against the government had a rally./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 15 for 1 turn
\*Event119 Event: The unrest on planet %Value1% has risen due to fanatics causing damage in the star base there./p/p
Unrest is Increased by 15 for 1 turn
\*Event120 Event: The sighting of a rare void crystal in the %Value1% system has caused a dramatic increase in tourism./p/p
Spaceport Efficiency is Increased by 3 for up to 6 turns
\*Event121 Event: Our space ports in %Value1% are reporting an increase in income due to a rare special event in the skies./p/p
Spaceport Efficiency is Increased by 3 for up to 6 turns
\*Event122 Event: The %Value1% system has had an increase in income due to a rare space crystal in the system./p/p
Spaceport Efficiency is Increased by 3 for up to 6 turns
\*Event123 Event: Facilities on %Value1% suffered slight damage due to limited geological disturbances.
\*Event124 Event: A small earthquake on %Value1% has caused some damage to the planet.
\*Event125 Event: A minor earthquake on %Value1% has destroyed some buildings there.
\*Event126 Event: Geologic activity has increased on %Value1% leading to several major earthquakes.  Damage to facilities appears to be significant.
\*Event127 Event: A major earthquake on %Value1% has destroyed a large portion of the buildings there.
\*Event128 Event: An earthquake has occurred on %Value1%. There appears to be quite a bit of damage caused.
\*Event129 Event: Recent deep core mining on %Value1% has led to the release of a dreaded Scath'lok hive.  We're currently repairing the damage caused.
\*Event130 Event: A Scath'lok hive was uncovered on %Value1%. The hive attacked the local populous and has destroyed several of the buildings there.
\*Event131 Event: The release of a Scath'lok hive on planet %Value1% has caused a significant amount of damage on the planet.
\*Event132 Event: Unexpected Volcanic activity on %Value1% has caused a series of major earthquakes.  Damage reports are expected to be extensive.  
\*Event133 Event: A huge earthquake on %Value1% has caused extensive damage to the planet.
\*Event134 Event: Reports indicate catastrophic damage on %Value1% where a major earthquake has occurred.
\*Event135 Event: Devastating tectonic movements have occurred on %Value1%.  Major earthquakes continue to rip through the major cities causing horrific damage.  
\*Event136 Event: A series of catastrophic earthquake has occurred on %Value1% causing major damage to the planet.
\*Event137 Event: A series of volcanic activity has occurred on %Value1% destroying a good portion of the planet.
\*Event138 Event: During exploration of a recent planet Orion technology was found. The discovery wasn't large but propelled the %Value1% technology further.
\*Event139 Event: The %Value1% research project has been completed due to a recent discovery.
\*Event140 Event: A recent breakthrough has propelled the %Value1% project to early completion.
\*Event141 Event: Reports indicate that several divisions of our troops have deserted due to the horrible attrition of a recent battle.
\*Event142 Event: A number of reports surfaced recently of unrest on a frontier world. Due to dangerous weapons testing several divisions of ground troops have deserted.
\*Event143 Event: A number of our troops have deserted recently. It will take time to replace them.
\*Event144 Event: Reports indicate several losses in our ground corps stationed on border worlds. Time will tell how long it will take to replace them.
\*Event145 Event: Several corps of our best troops deserted after a horrific battle.
\*Event146 Event: Due to reports of deadly enemy biological weapons several ground troop corps have deserted their posts.
\*Event147 Event: On our planet %Value1% a sizable group of marauders was formed. They create murder and arson, which unsettles the population. Military forces need to be show up and fight the gang.
\*Event148 Event: A large gang of outlaws threaten vast areas of %Value1%. Military efforts must be undertaken immediately.
\*Event149 Event: Armed gangs terrorize several provinces of %Value1%. The police forces are powerless and must be reinforced by military units.
\*Event150 Event: Organized crime rules on our planet %Value1%. We suspect that it extends into government circles. Our police forces there will be strengthened.
\*Event151 Event: Several crime syndicates have been able to establish themselves on %Value1%. Both the police and the administration are obviously corrupt. Immediate covert investigators must be deployed into the criminal network.
\*Event152 Event: Corruption and smuggling are rampant around %Value1%. It will take some time to clean up the local administration.
\*Event153 Event: Our clergymen on %Value1% report a dangerous sect that is spreading further and further. They are constantly recruiting new followers and turning the people against us. We should take care of it before the economy is completely paralyzed by the fanatics.
\*Event154 Event: A dangerous end-time sect is asking the population of the planet %Value1% for passive resistance. Our clergy and psychologists were asked to counteract this.
\*Event155 Event: A rogue psyker founded a new psychosect on %Value1%. His large following isolates themmselves from the values of our society. We have to do something so that the sect cannot spread any further.
\*Event156 Event: Sir, an attack! At %Value1%, an Space Crystal form plunged into the atmosphere from space and ravaged the planet. The security and military allies are engaged in a fierce defense battle with the creature. It will take some time before this monster is rendered harmless.
\*Event157 Event: An Energy Thread with absorption ability affects the planet %Value1% and has sucked gigantic amounts of energy out of the planetary supply networks, through which it has grown to enormous size. Now it is ravaging the cities. Our researchers and military strategists have to come up with a few ideas to save the planet.
\*Event158 Event: An insane scientist created a giant Amoeba on %Value1%, which he has now released against the population and facilities of the planet.
\*Event159 Event: Our genetic researchers at %Value1% have managed to breed a new way of life that will surely become a crowd pleaser. We recommend building an amusement park on this planet.
\*Event160 Event: Entertainment researchers developed a perfectly adapted fauna and flora on %Value1%. Flights to this planet are already fully booked.
\*Event161 Event: An engineering company set up a unique adventure park on the planet %Value1%, which simulates almost every conceivable experience with perfectly animated androids. The planet will be the number one travel destination for a long time.
\*Event162 Event: During mining excavations at %Value1%, the remains of a previously unknown prehistoric civilization were discovered. Some of our best archaeologists will analyze the finds. This will improve the planet's research for some time.
\*Event163 Event: In an inhospitable region of the planet %Value1%, researchers discovered strange artifact of an unknown life form that no doubt comes from a distant galaxy. Inscriptions of the artifact are currently being analyzed and fed into the planet's research network.
\*Event164 Event: During surveying of %Value1%, outlines of ruins became visible below the surface. The researchers came across millions of years old buildings of an unknown culture. Research efficiency will increase on this planet for some time.
\*Event165 Event: Extraneous bacterial pathogens were unearthed during mining operations at %Value1%. The entire planet is already infected. The population is being taken down, but our emergency quarantine service has already taken the first measures.
\*Event166 Event: In experiments with microscopic organisms on %Value1%, lethal pathogens were formed. The entire planet is already infected. The population is being carried away, but our emergency quarantine service is already on its way to the planet.
\*Event167 Event: A comet that struck at %Value1% was contaminated with unknown bacterial pathogens. The plague spread at lightning speed. The entire planet is already infected. The population is being carried away, but our emergency quarantine service has already been dispatched.
\*Event168 Event: An unknown, very old shipwreck drifted into orbit from %Value1%. Researchers and historians discovered remains of a mysterious culture on the wreck. In addition, the devices and finds of the wreck will be useful to our research on this planet.
\*Event169 Event: The sensors at %Value1% showed a foreign body when a asteroid was passing by, which was pulled along with the asteroid. Our salvage ships were able to recover the foreign body, which is currently being investigated by the researchers. Exceptionally interesting artifacts from an unknown culture were found on it.
\*Event170 Event: Recently a shipwreck hit %Value1%, luckily in uninhabited areas. Although not much of it remained, researchers set up a preliminary laboratory there. The ship probably dates from periods before our era.
\*Event171 Event: We should check the safety standards of our reactors. At %Value1% one of the largest kilns melted and triggered unprecedented radiation. Millions of dead and irreparable environmental damage are feared.
\*Event172 Event: A super meltdown occurred on %Value1%. Large agricultural areas have been contaminated and the number of deaths is in the millions.
\*Event173 Event: An unknown terrorist group captured a large reactor at %Value1% and blew it up. The result: contaminated environment and millions of deaths.
\*Event174 Event: A disaster. An event on %Value1% proved the existence of the long suspected gamma-ray bursts. Such a fan has now hit the planet and destroyed EVERYTHING. According to initial estimates, almost no one has survived.
\*Event175 Event: Nobody saw it coming. Nobody could avert it. A gamma-ray burst hit %Value1%. Everything is destroyed. According to initial estimates, almost no one has survived.
\*Event176 Event: %Value1% no longer reports. Our scientists believe that a gamma-ray burst hit this planet. The devastation must have been lethal - apparently no one has survived. An expedition team has already been dispatched.
\*Event177 Event: The magnetic field and the protective shields of the planet %Value1% can no longer withstand the current sun particle bombardment. The damage in production is not foreseeable.
\*Event178 Event: Our planet %Value1% is currently being hit by a violent ion storm. A number of energy supply facilities have failed. Production is stagnating.
\*Event179 Event: The short-term failure of the planetary magnetic field to %Value1% gives the planet a true sun particle bombardment. The energy supply is paralyzed, production stagnates.
\*Event180 Event: One of our scouts discovered a ship graveyard in a remote area of the galaxy. A real treasure trove for researchers across the empire - performance will increase everywhere.
\*Event181 Event: One of our fleets encountered a wreck of unknown origin on its way. Even though it must be millions of years old, scientists discovered important equipment on it that will be useful for general research.
\*Event182 Event: A research ship encountered a strange anomaly in a remote area of the galaxy. The ship's crew was able to feed the data into our research computers. This will benefit research across the empire.
\*Event183 Event: A high level link of a galactic gang of hackers contacted our secret service. Their information will lead to the destruction of many terrorist networks and syndicates.
\*Event184 Event: An unknown hacker sold our secret service important information about existing criminal syndicates. This enables us to break some gangs, which will contribute to the general fight against unrest.
\*Event185 Event: One of our undercover agents managed to sneak into a leadership position in a galactic syndicate. We can now stop the crime from within.
\*Event186 Event: The planet %Value1% experienced a pleasing short-term compensation of its inclination to the ecliptic, which, for an uncertain time, improves the climate considerably and the agricultural industry can produce much more food.
\*Event187 Event: The planet %Value1% experienced a pleasing short-term compensation of its inclination to the ecliptic, which, for an uncertain time, improves the climate considerably and the agricultural industry can produce much more food.
\*Event188 Event: The planet %Value1% experienced a pleasing short-term compensation of its inclination to the ecliptic, which, for an uncertain time, improves the climate considerably and the agricultural industry can produce much more food.
\*Event189 Event: According to eyewitness accounts, there have been several appearances of interstellarly revered religious luminaries on the planet %Value1%. Even though the authenticity of the reports is heavily questioned by our secret services, the news has spread like wildfire across the empire. The stream of pilgrims and onlookers, which has since flooded the planet, ensures an efficiency increase in recreation and trade. However, large amounts of food are also necessary for their supply, which is why there could be gaps in food production.
\*Event190 Event: The news of wholesome stones that were excavated at %Value1% during mining operations are circulating throughout the empire. Of course the news is esoteric nonsense, but the planet has seen a huge surge in tourism and entertainment since then. However, this euphoria slightly reduces the productivity of the planet.
\*Event191 Event: A so-called miracle healer founded a peaceful sect on %Value1%. With his prayers he is said to be able to cure even the most serious illnesses. Until this is exposed as charlatanism, however, the planet will certainly have increased tourism bookings. However, this euphoria slightly reduces the productivity of the planet.
\*Event192 Event: A very rare event takes place on the planet %Value1%. A small wormhole has collided with the planet and fused to the crust. Extra-dimensional matter gushes out of the wormhole, as well as strange radiation and chronotone particles that disrupt the flow of time. Although this will help research, the damage to production is enormous. Fortunately, this event is not of long duration.
\*Event193 Event: A research laboratory at %Value1% experimenting with space-time shift went off. An artificial wormhole formed, which melted into the crust. There were thousands of deaths, and alien radiation did great damage to the planet's production. Research will certainly learn from this. Fortunately, this event is not of long duration.
\*Event194 Event: A wormhole created by warpsmog merged with the earth's crust %Value1%. Extra-dimensional matter gushes out of the wormhole, as well as strange radiation and chronotone particles that disrupt the flow of time. Although this will help research, the damage to production is enormous. Fortunately, this event is not of great duration, since the wormhole will soon collapse.
\*Event195 Event: One of the legendary and lost relics of our religion has been rediscovered. Through contact with intelligent living beings, the artifact was activated immediately and fulfills everything with the presence of a mystical force. Every believer in our empire will tremble with the presence of the relic. Other empires will look at us with envy, which will increase our reputation.
\*Event196 Event: The new master of one of our numerous religious orders revealed to us that we had a relic that had long been thought lost. He makes them available to the public. Through contact with intelligent living beings, the artifact was activated immediately and fulfills everything with the presence of a mystical force. Every believer in our empire will tremble with the power of the relic. Other empires will look at us with envy, which will increase our reputation.
\*Event197 Event: From the estate of a deceased rich dealer and art collector, a relic of our religion believed to be lost has come to light again. It was donated to the Imperial Religious Museum. Through contact with intelligent living beings, the artifact was activated immediately and now fulfills everything with the presence of a mystical force. Every believer in our empire will tremble with the power of the relic. Other empires will look at us with envy, which will increase our reputation.
\*Event198 Event: Our sensors report a herd of rare space whales that roam our territory. We should send an expedition there immediately to explore these creatures.
\*Event299 Event: Our sensors report a rare gas constellation that has spontaneously formed in our territory. It is etheric life. We should investigate this anomaly before it resolves.
\*Event200 Event: Our sensors report the penetration of a huge, completely unknown life form into our territory. The being seems to be peaceful. We should strive to get in touch immediately to learn more about this way of life.
\*Event201 Event: A fleet group reports an attack by huge insectoids living in space. They came out of nowhere, no weapon could hurt them. They destroyed some of our ships and then moved on to unknown areas.
\*Event202 Event: One of our fleet groups was hit by unknown tick-like creatures. They settled on the outcrops of some ships and melted them. What is left of these ships @brig is ready for scrap. We commemorate the heroic crew members who resisted until the very last moment.
\*Event203 Event: One of our fleet groups got into a spontaneously occurring anomaly. Some ships were dragged into it. They could no longer be saved and disappeared.
\*Event204 Event: The sensors on %Value1% report a passing asteroid that is good for resource depletion. All mining ships on the planet are ready to go.
\*Event205 Event: On the planet %Value1% a considerable number of very comet-rich comets came down. This will significantly increase mining there for about a decade.
\*Event206 Event: Passing small asteroids close to %Value1% were mined with mining ships. For this decade, all raw material problems should be eliminated there.
\*Event207 Event: An unknown fleet group of brazen pirates attacked the rearguard of our fleet. They were able to board several ships before the main body came to the rescue.
\*Event208 Event: One of our fleet groups fought a fierce battle with pirates. Several of our ships have been destroyed.
\*Event209 Event: The rear guard of one of our fleet groups was boarded by pirates. They disappeared with the stolen ships before the main body could intervene.
\*Event210 Event: Huge colony of Moon Bats formed on one of %Value1% moons and performing raids on nearbly planets. Our military doing the best to contaminate infestation, meanwhile we keep losing our ships. System best scientific minds being concetrated on figuring out the way of negating this disaster.
\*Event211 Event: Sudden increased activity in %Value1% asteroid belt cause Mineral Collector to appear. He gobbles up our mining ships, so military pushing researchers to find a quick way of dealing with it.
\*Event212 Event: Radiation outburst of enormous proportions on a local sun formed Solar Bundle that proceeded to attack %Value1%. Our military doing our best to combat this creature, but we are losing a lot of our ships.
\*EvSysMod System Event
\*EvPltMod Planetary Event
\*EvEmpMod Empire Event

