\*LDRSTITL PERSONNEL

\*LDRSAPLD LEADERS
\*LDRSAPES ESPIONAGE

\*LDRSCOUN Leaders in your High Council: %value%
\*LDRSPHCO Your High Council is empty.

\*LDRSTRCO Cost

\*LDRSDISL DISMISS SELECTED LEADER
\*LDRSDISC CANCEL DISMISS ORDER

\*LDRSSELI SELECTED LEADER INFO

\*LDRSPHNM Name
\*LDRSPHLW Long-Winded Placeholder text.

\*LDRSESMC CURRENT ESPIONAGE MAINTENANCE COST:

\*LDRSESPR COMMISION COVERT OPS
\*LDRSESPT OPS CREATION
\*LDRSEPMC Primary Mission Circle:
\*LDRSERTS COMMISION THIS OPERATION
\*LDRSECTA Currently Commisioning:
\*LDRSETRC Primary Mission Circle
\*LDRSETRT Time Remaining
\*LDRSEDES DELETE SELECTED
\*LDRSEDCA RESUME CREATION

\*LDRSEAIF COMMITED OPERATIONS
\*LDRSELOS LIST OF OPERATIONS

\*LDRSEAGT Operation
\*LDRSEAST Status
\*LDRSEAMS Mission Circle
\*LDRSESAI OPS LEADER
\*LDRSEAGI COMMIT OPS
\*LDRSEACN Operation Code Name:
\*LDRSEACL Current Agenda:
\*LDRSEORD Orders:
\*LDRSEPRC Primary Circle:
\*LDRSECLO Cloak:
\*LDRSELUK Luck:
\*LDRSEDAG Dagger:
\*LDRSELOY Loyalty:
\*LDRSERET Decommision?

\*LDRSESNI Internal Security
\*LDRSESIN Commited, %value%
\*LDRSESIM Captured, %value%

\*LDRSEOIN Infiltrate, %value%
\*LDRSEORC Recall
\*LDRSEORT Decommision
\*LDRSEONC No Change

\*LDRSEEMP EMPIRE
\*LDRSENIA NUMBER OF INFILTRATED OPERATIONS

\*LDRSEIAS Commit an Operation into the selected empire?
\*LDRSEIAG INSERT OPERATION
\*LDRSEREC RECALL OPERATION
\*LDRSECRE CANCEL RECALL

\\Espionage Mission Circle Descriptions
\!EsMCi
\-ERROR!  This is NOT an option for espionage missions.
\-Military Covert Ops: Attempt to sabotage military infrastructure. Use "disinformation" and propaganda to try to confuse and erode support for enemy military goals and projects. The classic "peace movement" phenomenon is often a result of effective disinformation campaigns.
\-Political Covert Ops: Attempt to infiltrate political circles, create scandals, sabotage government and bureaucratic installations and remove "problematic" governors, heads of State and other high profile leaders.
\-Economic Covert Ops: Objectives include disrupting the economic activities of opposing empires by disrupting trade routes, encouraging illicit trade, and piracy and sabotaging economic infrastructure.
\-Social Covert Ops: Attempt to sow fear and unrest, through propaganda, subversion of the popular media, minor dissent from so called "useful idiots" (the disenfranchised and malcontents) and sabotage of recreational infrastructure.
\-Diplomatic Covert Ops: Attempt to disrupt the relations of others, cause unflattering documents to be "accidentally" leaked, "plant" lies and rumors; and manipulate "vulnerable" diplomatic personnel in addition to sabotage of government infrastructure.
\-Scientific Covert Ops: the classic "spies" of history steal theoretical research, prototypes or applied tech. They also disrupt projects, sabotage research infrastructure and neutralize opposing empires best minds, so that their work might be delayed or go unrealized.
\-Administrative [not in the game?] spies will do their part to make the administration of target empires a mess.  Although not nearly as effective as good old-fashioned government bureaucracy, you gotta hand it to them for trying.
\-Intelligence. [also not in the game] This spy will be a spy who spies on spies, who may also be, though won't necessarily, spying right back at them.
