\*LEADNA01 KaWyn Se
\*LEADNA02 Tul SaDum
\*LEADNA03 Kai Zagarin
\*LEADNA04 Tyr Enosorr
\*LEADNA05 Cursaanis
\*LEADNA06 Essivar
\*LEADNA07 Moghul Oolarol
\*LEADNA08 Aareel Biyaral
\*LEADNA09 Sinnn
\*LEADNA10 Shain Alegna
\*LEADNA11 Guy Geytz
\*LEADNA12 Neva Khe-Saharoh
\*LEADNA13 Ahhar Cha-Memnok
\*LEADNA14 Goreon Vendal
\*LEADNA15 Zale Sareen
\*LEADNA16 Liaeal
\*LEADNA17 Iarawen
\*LEADNA18 Azathkul
\*LEADNA19 Belethkul
\*LEADNA20 T'kt'tcha
\*LEADNA21 Kr'k'chull
\*LEADNA22 Unit A-4
\*LEADNA23 7ORT
\*LEADNA24 Alpha-T8C
\*LEADNA25 Matrix
\*LEADNA26 Minax Ch'Therion
\*LEADNA27 Loknar
\*LEADNA28 Karae Otohr
\*LEADNA29 Ree'hal Syn
\*LEADNA30 Maeghan Terron
\*LEADNA31 Arrlaan
\*LEADNA32 Cha Hode'
\*LEADNA33 Trilar
\*LEADNA34 Ithlis
\*LEADNA35 Zinm
\*LEADNA36 Ilitha
\*LEADNA37 Aren
\*LEADNA38 Ti'kri'ki
\*LEADNA39 Ik'irk'it


\*LEADDE01 Gritty and determined, %Value1% is directly descended from the leader of the Sakkra who initiated the first 'War of the Depths,' the historic war between the Sakkra and the Trilarians. As such he is viewed by the Sakkra (and many of the other Saurians) as royalty, and deserving of nothing but the utmost respect. Civilizations employing %Value1%'s services will benefit from increased loyalty from other empires, even in difficult times. Unfortunately, his arrogant ways can push other races to the breaking point, resulting in a reluctance to trade.

\*LEADDE02 %Value1% went from an officer's rank in the Sakkra Infantry Division into an enterprise building components for military equipment in the private sector. His military discipline made him a distinguished and hard-core leader in the company that he later founded. It also made him fanatically devoted to his personal power, a trait that makes him outcast even among his fellow Sakkra. %Value1% SaDum will greatly increase the output power of manufacturing facilities, but corruption and unrest tend to follow where he goes, and he also will try to pocket profits from whomever he is working for.

 \*LEADDE03 Many generations ago, the noble General, %Value1%, reluctantly committed the Grendarl clans to assisting the Sakkra in putting down the Raas uprising. Since that time over a millennium ago, the Clan Kai has put its strong military discipline into public service, building facilities for colonies and producing supplies for the people and the armies. %Value1%, current head of the clan, has insisted that the money normally made from such services be donated to the Raas as compensation for their suffering at Grendarl hands. 

 \*LEADDE04   The true warrior can do battle in any arena with any weapon.   This is the motto of %Value1%, Chief of Clans of the Grendarl. His arena is politics, and his weapons are words. He is not afraid to let his fearsome appearance intimidate those he negotiates with, but in place of battle rage is an icy hiss and stare that frequently dominates the Senate's chambers. %Value1% stood in the Senate on the day the New Orions declared their independence, and watches them warily, probing for weaknesses and information. He uses his imposing presence to pressure other empires into accepting treaties and trade offers, but his sense of honor will let him neither accept or offer surrender, and will never let another fight a battle for him. 

 \*LEADDE05 Descended from a family of heavy laborers, %Value1% has learned the ins and outs of productivity through several generations of family-taught behavior. No one can fault his work ethic; he is devoted to his tasks, and performs without hesitation or complaint. Years of skilled labor in the Antaran work camps did not go unnoticed, and the Antaran taskmasters eventually made him a camp leader, with orders to teach others in his camp to work like he did. Now free from Antaran domination, he continues to teach others to work harder for the good of the whole, although his lack of understanding of economics (he never worked for money) reduces the income that his productivity could bring in. 

 \*LEADDE06 The Raas, during their uprising against their Saurian brethren, learned that production and economics were as important in war as tactics and combat. By putting an early emphasis on production and manufacturing the Raas found that they could easily outproduce their adversaries and win battles with their sheer efficiency. 

 \*LEADDE07 The Nommo have made much profit by exporting surplus food, thanks to many new farming techniques pioneered by %Value1%. His use of experimental technology has brought greatly increased yields from the Nommo's oceanic farms. However, much of his research is considered radical and unconventional, and the techniques that he employs are often feared as untested and unsafe by the very people he is trying to feed. 

 \*LEADDE08 %Value1% spent the early years of his career working as a defense minister for despots and tyrants in the farthest reaches of the outer rim. His ambition exceeded such unsubstantial positions and his brilliance was soon discovered my several prominent empire in the core, where %Value1% quickly gained wealth and prestige. His old militaristic ways never escaped him, though, but they proved invaluable in times of war when loyalty and secretism was essential, even though his policies often severely restricted trade . 

 \*LEADDE09 %Value1%'s work for Silicoid Shipyards Inc. involved the acquisition of heavy minerals to assist in the growing of new vessels for the fleet. %Value1%'s mining operations were designed to be swift and precise, because Fleet Command wanted ships built quickly in case a defense had to be mounted against the New Orions' Great White Fleet. Several daring and risky techniques were developed by %Value1% to locate and extract minerals deep from the planetary core, but their success led to %Value1%'s promotion to the Chief of Mining Operations. Any civilization employing %Value1% will gain an impressive boost in menral production, but the techniques used by %Value1% often destroys valuable deposits, and the risk involved in his methods increase unrest. 

 \*LEADDE10 One of the canniest of the Human diplomats, Ambassador %Value1% was the obvious choice to lead the Human delegation at the fateful reconvention of the Orion Senate in 19097 GC. His speech opened the first session of the Senate, and his elegant discourse on the   beginning of a bright new age of peace for all Orions   was met with a thundering ovation. He is strong-willed and respected by diplomats from around the sector; civilizations employing him will find their relations with all other Senate members improved, including the New Orions, and encourage senate trade. His strong pacifistic views, however, will have a detrimental effect on a race's military efficiency. 

 \*LEADDE11 %Value1% has made his fortune within the Sol system by creating an impressive trade empire that links every corner of Terra. The reconvention of the Orion Senate under New Orion rule has opened up new territory, and he has already drawn up the plans needed to exploit that territory. Though the Human Government invited him to be their Interstellar Trade Adviser, he rejected that offer in favor of his own personal profit. He brings profit through trade and better economic policies to any civilization, but his capitalistic ways lead to an increase in corruption and inefficiency. 

 \*LEADDE12 %Value1% is known for his sudden flashes of insight into science and its applications. He is scorned by fellow researchers for following instinct rather than experimentation, but no one can deny his talents. He directed the research projects that helped reverse-engineer the Antaran monitors that orbited the Evon homeworld. Civilizations which employ him will see increases in research, but other empires will be less eager to share their research. 

 \*LEADDE13 %Value1% was an Evon spy-turned-diplomat; years of work in intelligence-gathering missions earned him a promotion to the directorship of espionage and embassy operations. He has participated in several meetings of the Orion Senate, always observing and gathering data. His cool and unsmiling demeanor conceals great wisdom, and he has mastered the fine art of negotiation and mediation. His presence reduces the negative penalties for diplomatic actions as he smooths over the situations with calming words and assurances. 

 \*LEADDE14 Sights of Antaran ships landing and launching and tales of the old times when the Psilons were an interstellar empire were the driving factors behind %Value1%'s desire to become an engineer. He worked to learn everything there was to know about science, and at an early age mastered several academic disciplines. Because of his vast knowledge, he was tapped to be part of a top-secret Psilon project to decipher and reverse-engineer some stolen pieces of Antaran technology; his success there kept him involved in other espionage-related projects. He has learned and applied techniques that improve test tube output for all research fields for whichever civilization he is working with. 

 \*LEADDE15 The former director of Psilon Military Research and Development is always looking for ways to use advanced technology to improve military production and performance. Her ceaseless drive to upgrade military hardware borders on ruthlessness, and some of her methods are not popular with the civilian populations (although quite popular with the armed forces). She will provide a civilization with a bonus to research production, but she is known for security breaches in her projects, and local unrest will also be increased as a result.  

 \*LEADDE16 Though the Antarans relocated all species to their homeworlds and purged them of their technologies, the Imsaeis never forgot the lessons learned from their past: the secrets of gas giant terraforming meant death to all Ethereans. %Value1% held one of the most important jobs of all- watching other races for indications of the development of such technologies. As a result, %Value1% commands an impressive spy network heavy with assassins and saboteurs, and he will not hesitate to use any means necessary to protect his species from annihilation. He will work for any civilization (mostly to gather data from them), improving their spying skills. 

 \*LEADDE17 The Etherean War of 18026 GC ended as a loss for the Ethereans, primarily as a result of their slower manufacturing methods in place at the time. Since then, they have learned that success comes from a simple mantra: build more, faster. %Value1% has led the herds for almost a century now, and she has driven them during that time to rebuild their cities and their armies, for now they are on equal footing with the other Orion races. %Value1% is an excellent motivator, driving the manufacturers with a sense of urgency and need, and thus increasing production rates across the board. 

 \*LEADDE18 %Value1% is one of the oldest surviving Ithkul around, and still retains some traces of memory from his first victim: an Antaran soldier. These distant memories of Antaran military procedures have made %Value1% into a deadly tactician for the Ithkul, and he has directed the Harvester infiltration of the Orion Sector with brutal proficiency. Those few races willing to tolerate a Harvester leader will see the effects on their armed forces via new tactics, improved skills and reduced fleet maintenance costs.  

 \*LEADDE19 %Value1% oversees the Harvester's host body manufacturing program, making sure that all Harvesters can be provided with a body to feed on when the Need is upon them. Her projects focus heavily on bioharvesting technologies, which often include mass cloning, cryogenic storage, steroidal enhancement, and radical genetic modifications. These projects are feared and reviled by most organic races; nonetheless, the improvements that she brings makes her valuable to those daring enough to stomach her presence. 

 \*LEADDE20 The Hive Tcha'Tchen has always been the Builders' Hive, providing the Empire with laborers for raising cities and building ships for millennia. Most famous of the Hive was the legendary Taskmaster %Value1%, who helped build the fleet that was victorious at the Battle of Antares in 18012 GC. Now, a thousand cycles later, %Value1% has inherited the memories of his ancestor, and faces the same challenge: help build up a power that can smite the New Orions. %Value1% is tireless in his work, and frequently directs his crews for days at a time without rest. His employment brings an increase in Industry output for the empire that hires him. 

 \*LEADDE21 %Value1% serves as the Hive Taskmaster for the Klackon Empire. This, one of the highest posts in the Klackon Hives, gives him complete control over the development of the empire, from construction to conquest. He has used his post to drive the Klackon armies to supreme efficiency, building their strength by using them to build new Hives and expand existing ones. His techniques are costly, taxing the Empire's economy, but governmental influence and colonial manufacturing output will increase as well. 

 \*LEADDE22 %Value1% is one of the original Cybernetiks who made the Crossing from cyborg to pure machine. Only eleven others of its entire generation remain functional and uncorrupted. %Value1% directed most of the original research that led to   the crossing,   and has since then increased its knowledge and research databanks to impressive levels, to the exclusion of almost everything else. The civilization that employ %Value1%'s services will immediately see the result in their research and development programs. %Value1% fanatical Meklar-centric opinions, however, tend to sour relations with all other races. 

 \*LEADDE23 %Value1% is a relatively young Meklar, but has gained notoriety through its ultra-conservative militaristic views on Meklar society. Leading a radical party of   Neo-Cybernetiks   on Meklon, %Value1% speaks out against the original Meklars, saying they are still flawed because of their previous status as flesh-beasts. %Value1% believes that it and others of its generation have finally achieved the state of being   the perfect machine,   and thus should rule the Meklars. %Value1% has amassed a sizeable military following, and has used numerous manufacturing techniques to build more equipment and units to support its cause. Its great failing, however, is that it believes that it completely eschews science in favor of pure manufacturing power, believing that it will be able to sieze whatever technology it needs through brute strength alone. 

 \*LEADDE24 Everyone in the galaxy knows about the efficiency of the Cynoids and %Value1% is no exception. While it has done nothing to increase its own personal reputation it spends all of its time working on increasing efficiency through trade and manufacturing. As a result the civilization will notice improved trade and manufacturing income, but his careless employment practices are be an open door to spies. 

 \*LEADDE25 No one alive knows the true designation of the Cyborg known as %Value1%. Its age, however, is estimated at over 2000 cycles- even in the late days of the Pax Humanica and the Great War, records point to %Value1% assisting the Orion races. The Dark Ages provided %Value1% with enough time to study and ponder the complex issues of social interaction between species and races, and the mechanisms by which peaceful non-military coexistence could best be attained. Now the mysterious Cyborg has returned to the Orion sector, hoping to unite the races as one and reject the hostile power of the New Orions. 

 \*LEADDE26 A second-generation descendant of the legendary Admiral Therion V'Raak, who led the Antarans to victory over the Orion sector races over a thousand cycles ago, %Value1% now feels like the true Antaran destiny has been betrayed by the so-called   New Orions.   She wants a return to the glory days of Antares, but in true Antaran fashion also wants to crush the insolent New Orions for their defiance of Antaran tradition. %Value1% knows that she must use the lesser species of Orion to achieve her goals, and thus will offer them assistance in research and development. Having an Antaran on hand, however, will be looked on with great disfavor by the civilization and its diplomatic contacts. 

 \*LEADDE27 The mysterious figure known as %Value1% helped the fledgling Orion races after they defeated the first Guardian of Orion; his understanding of Orion technology and Antaran military strategies helped guide them to victory against the Antaran fleet amassed at Kathar. And then he vanished, never to be seen again, until now. His goals remain a mystery, but his assistance still proves to be invaluable: any civilization fortunate enough to find him will benefit from his vast scientific knowledge. His presence tends to make other empires jealous, however, and they will stop at nothing to steal some of his technology for themselves. 

 \*LEADDE28 As part of the deep space defenses for the Varakesh, %Value1% and his ship the Star Reaver were caught in the pull of an unstable wormhole while in the midst of a pivotal battle. Now, his ship destroyed in the heart of the Orion sector, %Value1% and his troops act as merciless and efficient mercenaries for the highest bidder in an effort to gain enough funds and resources to return to their home system. 

 \*LEADDE29 One of the leader members of the Darlok secret force council, %Value1% was pivotal in engineering many of the sabotages and insurgencies that occurred in the Orion sector. The DSF was an almost illuminati-type organization, rumored to have agents and moles in every office of every civilization, manipulating and controlling the course of the Sector. After the destruction of the Darlok civilization by the New Orion Fleet, %Value1% gathered his closest staff members and stole away in a small starcraft to seek sanctuary and regroup in an effort to eventually bring the DSF to power again. Any civilization who gives him safe harbor will gain enormous benefits in the areas of spying, but government enforcment and tax profits will decrease as Darloks harbor a traditional suspicion of authority. 

 \*LEADDE30 %Value1% is the last of the Elerian telepaths. She has suffered countless horrors- the terror of the Antaran work camps, the psychic death-screams of her sisters, the strain of becoming increasingly more alone with every moment. With the destruction of her race by the Great White Fleet, she has given in to her anger, and has vowed to use her mental skills to fight for revenge against the New Orions. Her chances of psychically acquiring information are high, but most will fear the civilization that employs such an amoral telepath. 

 \*LEADDE31 %Value1% is the last surviving relative of Ambassador-in-exile Rrlenn, who perished in the destruction of Fieras by the Great White Fleet. In death she became the symbol of Mrrshan defiance, inspiring armies to rise up against their oppressors and take what is rightfully theirs. Her sibling %Value1%, who fled the holocaust with a handful of others, swore revenge on the New Orions and all their allies for his sister's death. The New Orions and their supporters will not look kindly on the civilization that employs %Value1%, but that does not matter to him. He will improve the skills and strengths of the militaries that work with him, training them with the intention of using their power to avenge his sister and his race. 

 \*LEADDE32 One of the few survivors of a rumored genetic experiment of the lost tribes, he is constantly haggling, always working in the gray or black areas of the market. %Value1% will find a deal where none is to be had, and is the type that could sell water to a Trilarian or a heater to the devil. His ethics are non-existent, and while any civilization that employs him will find their market and income increase, they will also suffer unrest through the effects of corruption, vice, and upset citizens who feel like they've been bilked out of their goods and belongings. After a particularly bad deal, he is entirely likely to disappear in the middle of the night, looking for the next sucker. 

 \*LEADDE33 The Master Crafter of %Value1% is renowned both as an architect and an artisan. She has directed the construction of many of %Value1%'s public service buildings, and those structures are seen as works of art and wonders of the architectural world. She was also called upon to build up the first Trilarian war fleet before the New Orion's War of Example, and her artistic skills influenced the ship designs, causing them to be aesthetically pleasing. Her presence generates an increase in tourism and recreation, but her works are expensive to maintain. 

 \*LEADDE34 The scientist %Value1% is famous throughout the galaxy for wild studies and bizarre methods. Despite his habits his very presence encourages people to flock to the study of science. Any civilization hosting him will notice an increase in research, but %Value1% tends to question everything, 

 \*LEADDE35 The manufacturing prowess of %Value1% is legendary through the Silicoid Empire. Most of his adult years were spent in the mining federation where he learned his trade and constantly improved the mining output of each station he was assigned. After his contract was expired he was offered permanent positions among the senior members but declined in order to pursue his own mining company and to provide work to the highest bidder. Civilizations employing %Value1% will find an increase in their mining ability but at a significant cost, as his facilities are expensive to maintain and his diplomacy lacks tact. 

 \*LEADDE36 The Imsaeis have always been a bit on edge about the massive slaughtering of their race during the terraforming of gas giants. %Value1% is no exception. Though always a diplomat in public, most of those who know of her are well aware of her many snide comments towards various races and technologies. As a result, her presence tends to create an increase in diplomacy but occasionally gives conflicting results. 

\*LEADDE37 Since the defeat of the Ethereans in the War of 18026 GC they've had to repair a broken economy. The repair effort has been a strenuous one but one that %Value1% has taken one effortlessly. When most around him were complaining about not having enough to go around he concentrated on what was there and found creative solutions. The results have spoken for themselves and any civilization employing him can expect similar financial gains. Unfortunately while he finds creative solutions he also knows how to make money disappear and rumors indicate that he's been known to dip into the till.

\*LEADDE38 %Value1% served as medical liaison to the Human home world for years where he learned many of their mannerisms and eventually recovered from their unorthodox individuality. During his time there his hive was destroyed through natural causes and since then he's been traveling the galaxy looking for a new hive and continuing his services through medical research. Any civilization employing him will find mortality rates greatly decreased because of his services.

 \*LEADDE39 With the growing demand for efficiency %Value1% has spent most of his life working to organize the research production of the Tachidi research facilities. His concentration is undaunted in whatever task sits before him and any civilization that hires him will find his usefulness in organizing and appropriating data immediate, especially since it makes it much harder for enemy agents to get their hands on it. Unfortunately, his methods can make it hard for his own scientist to get their hands on it as well. 

 \*LEADDE40 %Value1%, the Director of Human Research and Technology, is a firm believer in the phrase   knowledge is power.   Decades at universities working for the Antarans gave her an appreciation for their strength and their use of power and knowledge to dominate the sector. She plans to use that same knowledge to launch technology forward in the technological cold war she believes is about to envelop the Orion Sector. She often pursues the more esoteric fields of research, believing that the other Orion races will discover the   simple   applications for her. As a result, her research is more effective and tends to jump forward with positive overruns but also tends to be more expensive for the empire as a whole. 

 \*LEADDE41 %Value1% is a die-hard believer in a return to the   good old days,   when Humanity ruled the sector under the benevolent Pax Humanica. However, even he knows that Humanity as it stands is not yet ready to challenge the might of the New Orions. Not yet. Therefore he willingly works with other Orion races, hoping to assemble an armada capable of finally throwing off the New Orion's stranglehold over the sector. His training techniques improve a civilization's fleet and combat skills, but his fanatic methods and philosophies tend to generate unrest among most people. 

 \*LEADDE42 The former commander of the Evon planetary defense grid, %Value1% now advises the Evon government on interplanetary relations. He has studied the developing armies of their Orion neighbors and, based on their recent actions in the Senate, has proposed a plan of action detailing the relative strengths and weaknesses of each race and predicting the potential military and political directions they might soon follow. This detailed plan increases the chance of positive diplomatic settlements and negotiations. His plan has made many enemies, however, and his projects are often the target of enemy covert operations. 

 \*LEADDE43 This former Trade Minister of the Evon was famous for negotiating the Orion Trade Bill, one of few legislations proposed by the Orion Sector races that the New Orions actually approved. However, %Value1% was later dismissed from his post in a bribery scandal and vanished from the high profile of Evon political society. He has since worked for pirates and mercenaries, enemies and allies, always offering his political and economic wisdom for brief periods and then disappearing again. Trade profits and corruption go hand-in-hand wherever %Value1% is. 

 \*LEADDE44 Admiral %Value1% comes from a long line of Psilon military leaders- he is logical and precise, having studied military history and tactics from scores of conflicts. He has helped prepare numerous strategies should the New Orions turn their Great White Fleet against the growing Psilon Empire. Lack of technology during the Dark Ages taught him to   do more with less,   and he is confident of the abilities of his fleets, with or without technological superiority. Research is slightly reduced when he is in command, but all he always manages to make the most of any situation. 

 \*LEADDE45 One of few Psilon scientists to go into politics, %Value1% understands the true value of technology. Long ago, it propelled the Psilon Empire to the highest levels of power, and she knows it can do so again. Now she is sent to negotiate with technologically inferior races, using science as a bargaining chip to achieve her goals. She promotes research and development within any civilization that hires her, and has a good chance of negotiating positive and profitable treaties; nonetheless, to achieve those treaties she tends to offer a lot of technology she deems   expendable  . This makes many scientists uncomfortable and unwilling to share their research, so less overruns will be reported. 

 \*LEADDE46 The Ethereans lost their war against the local Orion races because of the slower nature of their construction and development methods. Much of that has changed for the Imsaeis in the past millennium, most recently due to the efforts of %Value1% who has pushed his people to rebuild from the Dark Age and learn from their past. %Value1%'s efforts succeeded in bringing up Imsaeis manufacturing efforts and research and development, but his methods are very expensive for any civilization to implement.  

 \*LEADDE47 A tremendous boost in production speed was the key factor in allowing the Imsaeis to remain competitive with their fellow Orions. %Value1% provided that boost with a strict, nearly militant regimentation of Imsaeis production facilities. Drawing on additional talent from all sectors, he brought production rates up planet-wide, but the cost came in food, for he drew on many skilled food production workers to boost the rest of the planet's capabilities. Nonetheless, most Imsaeis believe that it was worth it. 

 \*LEADDE48 The Eoladi have always been an ethical and honorable race, fighting only when their very homes were threatened. Now, with the Orion Sector open once again, they have sent out their representatives to deal peacefully with their neighbors. %Value1% is one of many Eoladi who have volunteered to meet their neighbors in the Orion Senate and try to solve the sector's problems in peaceful unity. Though idealistic, %Value1% is still an intelligent negotiator, and is skilled at easing political tensions between warring races. 

 \*LEADDE49 The Darloks and the Eoladi have many ancient standing agreements that provide for each other. %Value1% is the Keeper of Secrets for the Eoladi, and still retains control of a tiny faction of Darloks who have fled Nazin's destruction. Those Darloks, bound by the centuries-old treaties, now assist %Value1% in gathering intelligence for the Eoladi. As a result, he wields an impressive spy network that now stretches through the Orion Sector. 

 \*LEADDE50 Even the inorganic Silicoids were not spared from the Antarans' experiments in genetics. %Value1% was part of a program to increase the combative skills of the crystalline beings, using data the Antarans had on the Space Crystals, titanic entities that roamed space freely and devoured entire planets. %Value1% now functions like a crystalline analytical computer, and is solely devoted to the mechanics of warfare. Though this modification generates tremendous bonuses for a civilization's forces, %Value1% knows only warfare, and thus generates political unrest due to its hostile nature. 

 \*LEADDE51 In the mad scramble by the Orion races to rise up and claim independence from the Antaran overlords and rejoin the Orion Senate, many aspects of government and organization were seen anew, and the once oppressed races had a rough time reconstructing their bureaucracies. %Value1% took the disjointed Silicoid research programs and united them in one single   planetary university   that still works and keeps the Silicoids in the tech race. %Value1% strives to create a unified scientific and technological civilization where all citizens are encouraged to contribute and are even alowed access to advanced technologies. Although idealic, %value1%s system does increase the scientific output of the civilization that he works for. Unfortunately %value1% carries traditional Silicoid values and will preach them to the masses, so population growth will be moderately reduced. 

 \*LEADDE52 Although the Antarans made the Orion Sector into a nightmarish genetics laboratory during the Dark Age, it did not leave the Meklars totally unscathed. %Value1% was one of many Meklars who were taken for study and enhancement by the Antaran robotics technologists. The Antarans modified %Value1% to better interface with and control production machinery, increasing its capacity for detail and multitasking while reducing the less relevant personality programming traits. As a result, %Value1% brings an impressive boost to production efficiency, but has become inhumane even by Meklar standards and thus generates substantial unrest. %Value1% is also known to disregard all forms of life to achieve further efficiency, and is widely hated for it. 

 \*LEADDE53 %Value1% was the Meklar who, several hundred cycles ago, developed the interface that enhanced the Meklars' ability to   plug in   to their ships, vehicles, and buildings and thus establish even more direct links with their tools and surroundings. %Value1% has continued to develop this user interface, simplifying it and accelerating it, and giving lightning-fast reflexes when it comes to using such machines. The results have been faster more efficient use of military fleets, but the advanced systems can not be integrated into larger ships. 

 \*LEADDE54 %Value1% believes in the exchange of information for a price. This Cynoid is often called a pirate even by its own people. It promotes free trade between races, offering goods and services to all in need. The price of these goods is often higher than expected; %Value1% will often try to   acquire   information from its trade partners by whatever means necessary. This theft of data usually goes undetected; %Value1% is skilled at the game. But %Value1%'s reputation precedes it, and therefore, though it will bring bonuses to trade and espionage, other civilizations will be uneased its presence and unwilling to do business. 

 \*LEADDE55 %Value1% volunteered to leave the Cynoid homeworld and travel throughout the sector when the New Orions took control; it wanted to see the sights and wonders of the galaxy. In its travels it has made many observations and discoveries, learning the sciences and technologies of the Orion races, both living and dead. %Value1% is itself a scientific encyclopedia, and its observations and knowledge are of great help to scientific expeditions. His all-encompassing travels have led to a great hatred of the Antarans and their ways, which puts many empires on edge and makes them less likely to bargain with the empire that employs %Value1%. 

 \*LEADDE56 The Trilarians see the Orion Senate as a tool for accomplishing several objectives quickly and easily. %Value1% will go to all lengths to procure political and diplomatic assistance, and often pushes for the other races to join in condemning galactic   criminals.   He will often help a race get what it wants or needs out of Senate legislation, be it recognition, condemnation of another, or any other vote.  His methods are usually unsavory, and sometimes he doesn't succeed in hiding them from other empires. 

 \*LEADDE57 %Value1% is famed throughout Trilarian society as a child genius, born with an incredible ability to solve complex mathematical problems and calculate detailed formula in her head. Her assistance on numerous research projects has led to many surprising breakthroughs and discoveries that have propelled the Trilarians forward in returning their empire to the stars. But %Value1% is erratic, offering her aid to anyone who asks, and her   research   is hard to quantify. 

 \*LEADDE58 Ever concerned with regaining control of their true homeworld from the Trilarians, %Value1% is the voice that speaks out most fervently for the Nommo. %Value1% has pleaded for aid, from the halls of the Senate to the embassies of every race in the sector, bargaining and negotiating for any advantage he can get for his people. Few ambassadors are as well-known among the diplomatic elite of the Senate; %Value1% knows everyone who walks its fabled halls. He will work for any civilization, usually as a result of a bargain made to benefit the Nommo. He has gained notoriety for his uncanny ability to turn even the most negative of conversations around and deftfully avoid its negative elements. 

 \*LEADDE59 %Value1% worked for many cycles producing military equipment for the Nommo planetary defense forces. His philosophy was   function over form  ; there is no beauty in his constructs, no aesthetics in his buildings, nothing but pure and simple application. He believes that art is a waste of time and energy, and that spending time making an object   look good   is time that could be spent making the object work better. %Value1% has designed and built some of the ugliest structures on the planet, in popular opinion, but no one can question the perfect utilitarianism of his designs. %Value1% will improve production speed for a civilization, but that civilization's citizens' unrest levels will increase as more and more of %Value1%'s work pervades the region. 

 \*LEADDE60 The Harvester research coordinator has overcome the memory-based limitations of his species and transformed research and development into a supreme art of interview and interrogation. By questioning those Harvesters who have bonded with scientists and researchers, %Value1% has gleaned thousands of scientific and technological secrets and he now uses that knowledge to attempt to infer other potential discoveries. In this manner he has drawn on the scientific knowledge of almost every Orion race, and has even initiated some research projects of his own design. 

 \*LEADDE61 One of the biggest challenges facing the Harvesters was production and manufacturing. Owing to their own fragility, they had to come up with methods of production that were still efficient but less damaging and dangerous to their bodies. %Value1% designed several efficient remote-output processing plants for resource acquisition and component manufacture, and these systems gave the Harvesters the edge they needed to stay in the sector. %Value1% will bring these same systems to any race; they are expensive and create a lot of pollution, but production output is significantly increased. 

 \*LEADDE62 Through the unity of the Klackon Hive mind, %Value1% has managed to concentrate all thought on science and technology into one single mental stream and use that to overcome the Klackon bent towards non-creativity. It is an extremely challenging and strenuous process, and has caused him physical pain and suffering over the years. Once he learned that this technique could be applied to the other races with less efficiency but substantially less discomfort, %Value1% offered himself to the neighboring Orion races as a research coordinator. %Value1%'s ability increases research output and his Klackon contacts can provide intelligence valuable to any covert operation although the cost of research is increased due to his non-creative inclinations. 

 \*LEADDE63 %Value1% controls a team of Klackon infiltrators who enjoy the challenge of spying on other races and stealing their secrets. Using several unidentifiable pieces of technology (which many suspect were stolen from the Antarans), %Value1% can sneak his team in among any race, often burrowing into the ground or hiding in subterranean tunnels and listening in on the happenings on the surface. His team is highly unethical and public with their bragging, and thus the civilization that hires %Value1% will gain data through espionage, but will cause uneasiness in the general population, making them quite touchy about their freedoms. 

 \*LEADDE64 The inherent curiosity of the Tachidi is most evident in %Value1%, who is fixated on understanding their galactic neighbors in utmost detail. %Value1% has studied the technologies of the other races, and even of the Antarans via the monitors left behind around their homeworld. He has sought out refugee Darloks to learn their secrets of data acquisition. He has even interrogated and dissected individuals of the other races to understand them better. %Value1%'s approach to learning (frequently considered   unethical   by others) will nonetheless improve a civilization's research output and espionage skills, but the unrest for hiring him will be vast and widespread. 

 \*LEADDE65 The Antaran geneticists targeted the extremely productive Tachidi with experiments designed to make them even more capable at mining. %Value1% is one of the results of those vile experiments- his innards are techno-organically enhanced for greater endurance, resilience, and strength. %Value1% is now fixated on work: he must always be active, either working or digging, or his body will burn itself out. This non-stop activity motivates others around him, increasing overall mining output, although being costly in money and resources. 

 \*LEADDE66 When the proud Sakkra were laid low by the might of the Antaran Black Fleet, they learned a hard lesson: their vast numbers could not stand up to Antaran technology. Since then, even with their world turned into a work camp, they devoted part of their military to the constant acquisition of more and more technology, at any cost. %Value1% has directed the Sakkra engineers to new heights of military research, and, with the sudden rebirth of the Orion sector races, has also prepared infiltration teams for the more forceful acquisition of technology. 

 \*LEADDE67 The instinctive Sakkra drive to expand and reproduce has always put a strain on their food production. The fertile farmlands of Sssla were enough to nourish the Sakkra, but the Antarans took the bulk of the food and left the scraps to the starving Sakkra. %Value1% set up a system to increase food output while hiding the results from the Antarans, thus helping the Sakkra survive the end of the Dark Age. With their new potential to expand again into the Orion sector, he has been called upon to provide food for the masses, and his techniques are being applied to all new colonies to improve overall bioharvesting output. %Value1% has always been secretive, and his unwillingness to share his methods to any but the highest bidder enrages other civilizations. 

 \*LEADDE68 The Raas have always been ready to fight an underground guerilla war against an oppressing force, and one of their best tools was the food-for-profit plan of action developed a thousand cycles ago to fund their revolution against their fellow Saurians. Now %Value1% has updated that plan and is ready to assist any civilization in readying itself for a protracted engagement against superior forces- his techniques cut heavily into manufacturing rates, but the bonuses to bioharvest output and profit are often worth it. 

 \*LEADDE69 The humble Raas have always been great orators, from the days when they spoke out against the Sakkra oppression of their people to the present, when %Value1% stood in the Well of the Orion Senate and pleaded the case for his people's membership in the   august   body. %Value1% is a brilliant negotiator and moderator, soft-spoken and calm, yet known for his stirring and energetic use of language and rhetoric to bring others to his viewpoints. He is frequently invited to mediate disputes between civilizations, and his presence in a civilization's council reduces tensions that civilization might have with other races, although he has been known to cut other empires more than fair shares of trade deals. 

 \*LEADDE70 The marketplace is his battlefield, and he is clearly one of its generals. Having masterminded several hostile takeovers within the early years of interstellar trade, and having predicted and profited from several other key financial events (including the destruction of the Gnolam empire and with it, the collapsing of their financial system), %Value1% is both respected and feared by traders and businessmen throughout the sector. Even the Gnolams held him in high esteem before their demise. Now he seeks power and wealth for the benefit of his employers, though he is still bound by the code of honor that all Grendarl swear to. His presence brings profit through trade and trade agreements, although many are wary of bargaining with him. 

 \*LEADDE71 One of the strongest of the Grendarl chose to use his might and skills not for warfare above the ground, but rather in battle with the ground itself. %Value1% is rumored to be so strong that he can crush raw ore in his bare hands. He is fearless and confident, and pushes his mining crews and equipment to their limits to get the results he needs. His honor demands that no one is lost to the mines, and so far, despite several mining accidents, he has kept his crews alive and well. With him directing the day-to-day mining operations, an empire will see a definite rise in mineral production; %Value1%'s honor demands nothing less. 

 \*LEADDE72 %Value1%, a previous Intelligence Officer, shares many of the Evon's environmental views, but tends to interpret them to his own liking. He cares little for the natural environmental state of a planet if it is ill-suited for the Evons, and will work feverishly to terraform it to his liking regardless of cost or loss of life. The methods of %Value1% have proven efficient again and again, yet his haste in terraforming often leads to increased environmental instability and soil damage. 

 \*LEADDE73 %Value1% is well known for his scientific craftiness, as he is able to accomplish many technological feats thought impossible with the current level of technology.  He specializes in environmental fields, and finds creative ways to terraform a planet, though often at great cost to his employer. 

 \*LEADDE74 Saurians have traditionally formed harsh, militant societies, whose hostile methods have often been met with misunderstanding from other races in the orion sector. Some would take a diplomatic route, but %Value1% believes in peace through strength and military superiority. He specializes in oppression and brutal efficiency to achieve his ends, but it does have its downsides. Such brutal oppression increases mortality rates, and those that survive attemp to leave at all costs. 

 \*LEADDE75 Born from a collaboration of highly efficient Meklar units, %Value1% was to be destined for greatness. However, a failure in the logic circuitry during its   birthing   transmission process left 2 of the parent units corrupted and the others dead, leaving %Value1% as the only survivor of the affair. As a result, the unfortunate unit became an unusual, outcast member of Meklar society, yet was innately talented. %Value1% finally found his place in the service of the military, where the unit found that it could discern the presence of enemy craft in even the most distorted of sensor readings. Although %Value1% proved his worth again and again he remained an outcast, so it spends its time traveling the galaxy seeking a civilization where it will fit in. 

 \*LEADDE76 A born artist, %Value1% has always believed in form over function. Despite his mantra, his work has always had both, and his medium is not strictly canvas. The lavish architecture of %Value1% has often brought cities back from financial downfall due to the sheer amount of tourism he attracts, but he has just as often bankrupted his employers when his methods proved too costly. Any empire employing %Value1% will see an increase in planetary infrastructure and population at a large financial cost. 

 \*LEADDE77 %Value1% has always believed that outside contact would bring about the downfall of the Etherean race, but it is an unfortunate necessity in current times. %Value1% believes in a secure society untouched by other races, and will stop at nothing to keep such undesirables out. He does, however, believe in trade, as it is a very indirect method of association. 






\*LEADIC01 +10% Diplomacy Gains
\*LEADIC02 +20% Diplomacy Gains
\*LEADIC03 +30% Diplomacy Gains
\*LEADICAA - 20% Diplomacy Gains
\*LEADICAB - 30% Diplomacy Gains
\*LEADICAC - 10% Diplomacy Gains

\*LEADIC04 +10% Fleet Maint
\*LEADIC05 +20% Fleet Maint
\*LEADIC06 +30% Fleet Maint
\*LEADICAD - 10% Fleet Maint
\*LEADICAE - 20% Fleet Maint
\*LEADICAF - 30% Fleet Maint

\*LEADIC07 +10% Diplomacy Losses
\*LEADIC08 +20% Diplomacy Losses
\*LEADIC09 +30% Diplomacy Losses
\*LEADIC10 - 10% Diplomacy Losses
\*LEADIC11 - 20% Diplomacy Losses 
\*LEADIC12 - 30% Diplomacy Losses

\*LEADIC13 +15% Senate Trade
\*LEADIC14 +30% Senate Trade
\*LEADIC15 +50% Senate Trade 
\*LEADICAG - 15% Senate Trade
\*LEADICAH - 30% Senate Trade
\*LEADICAI - 50% Senate Trade

\*LEADIC16 +1 Spaceport Efficiency
\*LEADIC17 +2 Spaceport Efficiency
\*LEADIC18 +3 Spaceport Efficiency
\*LEADIC19 - 1 Spaceport Efficiency
\*LEADIC20 - 2 Spaceport Efficiency
\*LEADIC21 - 3 Spaceport Efficiency

\*LEADIC22 +10% Trade AUs
\*LEADIC23 +20% Trade AUs
\*LEADIC24 +30% Trade AUs
\*LEADIC25 - 10% Trade AUs
\*LEADIC26 - 20% Trade AUs
\*LEADIC27 - 30% Trade AUs

\*LEADIC28 +5% HFoG
\*LEADIC29 +10% HFoG 
\*LEADIC30 +15% HFoG
\*LEADIC31 - 5% HFoG
\*LEADIC32 - 10% HFoG
\*LEADIC33 - 15% HFoG

\*LEADIC34 +10% Research Efficiency
\*LEADIC35 +20% Research Efficiency
\*LEADIC36 +30% Research Efficiency
\*LEADIC37 - 10% Research Efficiency 
\*LEADIC38 - 20% Research Efficiency
\*LEADIC39 - 30% Research Efficiency

\*LEADIC40 +10% Gov Efficiency
\*LEADIC41 +20% Gov Efficiency
\*LEADIC42 +30% Gov Efficiency
\*LEADIC43 - 10% Gov Efficiency
\*LEADIC44 - 20% Gov Efficiency
\*LEADIC45 - 30% Gov Efficiency

\*LEADIC46 +10% Rare Mineral Value
\*LEADIC47 +20% Rare Mineral Value 
\*LEADIC48 +30% Rare Mineral Value 
\*LEADIC49 - 10% Rare Mineral Value 
\*LEADIC50 - 20% Rare Mineral Value
\*LEADIC51 - 30% Rare Mineral Value
 
\*LEADIC52 +10% Rare Bioharvest Value
\*LEADIC53 +20% Rare Bioharvest Value
\*LEADIC54 +30% Rare Bioharvest Value
\*LEADIC55 - 10% Rare Bioharvest Value
\*LEADIC56 - 20% Rare Bioharvest Value
\*LEADIC57 - 30% Rare Bioharvest Value

\*LEADIC58 +15% Terraform Cost
\*LEADIC59 +30% Terraform Cost
\*LEADIC60 +50% Terraform Cost
\*LEADIC61 - 15% Terraform Cost
\*LEADIC62 - 30% Terraform Cost
\*LEADIC63 - 50% Terraform Cost

\*LEADIC64 +5 Spy Offense
\*LEADIC65 +10 Spy Offense
\*LEADIC66 +15 Spy Offense
\*LEADIC67 - 5 Spy Offense
\*LEADIC68 - 10 Spy Offense
\*LEADIC69 - 15 Spy Offense

\*LEADIC70 +5 Spy Defense
\*LEADIC71 +10 Spy Defense
\*LEADIC72 +15 Spy Defense
\*LEADIC73 - 5 Spy Defense
\*LEADIC74 - 10 Spy Defense
\*LEADIC75 - 15 Spy Defense

\*LEADIC76 +10% Population Research
\*LEADIC77 +20% Population Research
\*LEADIC78 +30% Population Research
\*LEADIC79 - 10% Population Research
\*LEADIC80 - 20% Population Research
\*LEADIC81 - 30% Population Research

\*LEADIC82 +5% Unrest
\*LEADIC83 +10% Unrest
\*LEADIC84 +15% Unrest
\*LEADIC85 - 5% Unrest
\*LEADIC86 - 10% Unrest
\*LEADIC87 - 15% Unrest

\*LEADIC88 +10% Military Efficiency
\*LEADIC89 +20% Military Efficiency
\*LEADIC90 +30% Military Efficiency
\*LEADIC91 - 10% Military Efficiency
\*LEADIC92 - 20% Military Efficiency
\*LEADIC93 - 30% Military Efficiency

\*LEADIC94 +10% Industry Value
\*LEADIC95 +20% Industry Value
\*LEADIC96 +30% Industry Value
\*LEADIC97 - 10% Industry Value
\*LEADIC98 - 20% Industry Value
\*LEADIC99 - 30% Industry Value

\*LEADICAJ +10% Population Industry
\*LEADICAK +20% Population Industry
\*LEADICAL +30% Population Industry
\*LEADICAM - 10% Population Industry
\*LEADICAN - 20% Population Industry
\*LEADICAO - 30% Population Industry

\*LEADICAP +10% Pollution
\*LEADICAQ +20% Pollution
\*LEADICAR +30% Pollution
\*LEADICAS - 10% Pollution
\*LEADICAT - 20% Pollution
\*LEADICAU - 30% Pollution

\*LEADICAV +5% Population Growth
\*LEADICAW +8% Population Growth
\*LEADICAX +10% Population Growth
\*LEADICAY - 5% Population Growth
\*LEADICAZ - 8% Population Growth
\*LEADICBA - 10% Population Growth
\*LEADICZZ +15% Population Growth

\*LEADICBB +10% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICBC +20% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICBD +30% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICBE - 10% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICBF - 20% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICBG - 30% Antaran Expedition Success
\*LEADICEA +40% Antaran Expedition Success

\*LEADICBH +5% Infra-  structure
\*LEADICBI +10% Infra-  structure
\*LEADICBJ +15% Infra-  structure
\*LEADICBK - 5% Infra-  structure
\*LEADICBL - 10% Infra-  structure
\*LEADICBM - 15% Infra-  structure

\*LEADICBN +10% Bioharvest Surplus Value
\*LEADICBO +20% Bioharvest Surplus Value
\*LEADICBP +30% Bioharvest Surplus Value
\*LEADICBQ - 10% Bioharvest Surplus Value
\*LEADICBR - 20% Bioharvest Surplus Value
\*LEADICBS - 30% Bioharvest Surplus Value

\*LEADICBT +10% Mineral Surplus Value
\*LEADICBU +20% Mineral Surplus Value
\*LEADICBV +30% Mineral Surplus Value
\*LEADICBW - 10% Mineral Surplus Value
\*LEADICBX - 20% Mineral Surplus Value
\*LEADICBY - 30% Mineral Surplus Value

\*LEADICBZ +10% Casus Belli Gains
\*LEADICCA +20% Casus Belli Gains
\*LEADICCB +30% Casus Belli Gains
\*LEADICCC - 10% Casus Belli Gains
\*LEADICCD - 20% Casus Belli Gains
\*LEADICCE - 30% Casus Belli Gains

\*LEADICCF +10% Bioharvest Efficiency
\*LEADICCG +20% Bioharvest Efficiency
\*LEADICCH +30% Bioharvest Efficiency
\*LEADICCI - 10% Bioharvest Efficiency
\*LEADICCJ - 20% Bioharvest Efficiency
\*LEADICCK - 30% Bioharvest Efficiency

\*LEADICCL +10% Building Costs
\*LEADICCM +20% Building Costs
\*LEADICCN +30% Building Costs
\*LEADICCO - 10% Building Costs
\*LEADICCP - 20% Building Costs
\*LEADICCQ - 30% Building Costs

\*LEADICBR +10% Maint Cost
\*LEADICCS +20% Maint Cost
\*LEADICCT +30% Maint Cost
\*LEADICCU - 10% Maint Cost
\*LEADICCV - 20% Maint Cost
\*LEADICCW - 30% Maint Cost

\*LEADICBX - 1 Disband Delay
\*LEADICCY - 3 Disband Delay
\*LEADICCZ - 5 Disband Delay
\*LEADICDA +1 Disband Delay
\*LEADICDB +3 Disband Delay
\*LEADICDC +5 Disband Delay

\*LEADICDD - 10% Pollution Absorbtion
\*LEADICDE - 20% Pollution Absorbtion
\*LEADICDF - 30% Pollution Absorbtion
\*LEADICDG +10% Pollution Absorbtion
\*LEADICDH +20% Pollution Absorbtion
\*LEADICDI +30% Pollution Absorbtion

\*LEADICDJ - 10% Industry Efficiency
\*LEADICDK - 20% Industry Efficiency
\*LEADICDL - 30% Industry Efficiency
\*LEADICDM +10% Industry Efficiency
\*LEADICDN +20% Industry Efficiency
\*LEADICDO +30% Industry Efficiency

\*LEADICDP - 10% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDQ - 20% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDR - 30% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDS +10% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDT +20% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDU +30% Mining Efficiency
\*LEADICDV +30% Mining Efficiency

\*LEADICDW - 1 Shipyard Capacity

\*LEADICEB - 1 Recreation Efficiency
\*LEADICEC - 2 Recreation Efficiency
\*LEADICED - 3 Recreation Efficiency
\*LEADICEE +1 Recreation Efficiency
\*LEADICEF +2 Recreation Efficiency
\*LEADICEF +3 Recreation Efficiency

\*LEADICEG - 5% Taxes Collected
\*LEADICEH - 10% Taxes Collected
\*LEADICEI - 15% Taxes Collected
\*LEADICEJ +5% Taxes Collected
\*LEADICEK +10% Taxes Collected
\*LEADICEL +15% Taxes Collected

\*LEADICEM - 10% Maximum Population
\*LEADICEN - 20% Maximum Population
\*LEADICEO - 30% Maximum Population
\*LEADICEP +10% Maximum Population
\*LEADICEQ +20% Maximum Population
\*LEADICER +30% Maximum Population

\*LEADICES - 10% Population Pollution
\*LEADICET - 20% Population Pollution
\*LEADICEU - 30% Population Pollution
\*LEADICEV +10% Population Pollution
\*LEADICEW +20% Population Pollution
\*LEADICEX +30% Population Pollution

\*LEADICEY +1 Spy Dagger
\*LEADICEZ +2 Spy Cloak
\*LEADICFA +10 Spy Luck
\*LEADICFB +1 Shipyard Capacity


\*LEADER Leader Effect
