\*Bioharve Bioharvesting
\*BioHRare Agricultural Businesses
\*BioPrPop Agricultural Intensity
\*RBioOut Regional Bioharvest
\*Harvest Cultivated Areas
\*LWNutz Cultivation Methods
\*LWMethod Special Cultivation Policy
\*Mining Mining
\*MinRare Mining Businesses
\*MinPP Mining Intensity
\*MinConv Mineral Conversion Rate
\*Mineral Usable Resources
\*BBMethod Special Mining Policy
\*BBBetrieb Mining Organization
\*BBNutz Mining Method
\*Manufact Manufacturing
\*ManuPP Worker Rights
\*RBioManu Organic Industry
\*RCraftsm Craftsmanship
\*Produktart Product Type
\*Produkt Production Focus
\*PBetrieb Production Factories
\*PVerschm Factory Pollution Factor
\*PLobby Production Lobbies
\*Research Scientific Agenda
\*RTestTub Research Afinity
\*ForArt Scientific Community
\*BildLobb Educational Financing
\*RRecrea Social Agenda
\*RMilita Military Agenda
\*Trade Fantastic Traders
\*CRTrade Mercantile
\*RPorts Natural Navigators
\*TradeLevel Wealth
\*RExchan Barter
\*Handelgut Free Market Regulations
\*Environm Environmental
\*RGovEff Government Agenda
\*RHFoG Heavy Foot of Government
\*Economic Economics
\*Wirtschaft Economic Organisation
\*Accuracy Accuracy
\*Aptitude Aptitude
\*Reflexes Reflexes
\*Toughnes Toughness
\*Doktrin War Doctrine
\*CRPeaceT Spirituality
\*CRTreaty Respect
\*MeansWar Fatalism
\*OSMayILB Senate Relations
\*PositivCB Casus Beli
\*PositivDP Diplomatic Ability
\*RceDiplo Culture Agenda
\*RBaseRel Empathic
\*GravPen Gravity Tolerance
\*Governme Government Type
\*SenateMe Starting Member of Orion Senate
\*Agenda Agenda
\*Citizens Citizenship
\*Medien Media Freedom
\*PlanMine Homeworld Mineral Richness
\*PlanBioD Homeworld Biodiversity
\*RBioHRin Independent Farmers
\*Cunning Cunning
\*RCloak Cunning
\*RDagger Dangerous
\*RLuck Lucky
\*RSpyTime Quick
\*RSpyOff Sharp
\*RSpyDef Aware
\*SpionSchule Spying School
\*DiploSchulen Diplomatic School
\*ROppres Social Tolerance
\*TechDisc Lab Luck
\*TechKnow Creativity
\*TechOver Anti-Reactionism
\*TechPosO Genius
\*RPopGrow Population Growth
\*RCloning Cloning
\*RMaxPop Survival Agenda
\*RTerrafo Natural Agenda
\*UmweltTk Environmental Engineering
\*RTerCost Terraforming Cost
\*RAntaraX Antaran Background
\*RLesserA Lesser Specials
\*RGreatA Greater Specials
\*RCheat CHEAT SCREEN
\*Fatalism Fatalism
\*Respect Respect
\*Spiritua Spirituality
\*SocialTo Social Tolerance
\*Special1 Special Attributes
\*Excellent Excellent
\*Superior Superior
\*Good Good
\*Average Average
\*Poor Poor
\*Awful Awful
\*Abysmal Abysmal
\*Investor Investors
\*Monetari Monetarists
\*Specie Specie
\*Barter Barter
\*Unique Unique
\*RandomCh Random
\*Tribalis Tribalistic
\*Absoluti Absolutist
\*Transiti Feudal
\*Represen Representative
\*Collecti Collectivist
\*Survival Survival
\*Military Military
\*Scientif Scientific
\*Wealth Wealth
\*SelfFulf Self-fulfillment
\*CommonGo Common Good
\*Utopia Utopia
\*Expansio Expansionism Agenda
\*Green Green Agenda
\*Loyalty Loyalty
\*Duty Duty
\*Associat Association
\*Liberty Liberty
\*Dangerou Dangerous
\*Quick Quick
\*Sharp Sharp
\*Slow Slow
\*Original Original
\*Adaptive Adaptive
\*Normal Normal
\*Imitativ Imitative
\*Pervasiv Pervasive
\*Strong Strong
\*Natural Natural
\*Resisted Resisted
\*Devout Devout
\*Accepted Accepted
\*Embracin Embracing
\*Acceptin Accepting
\*Understa Understanding
\*Intolera Intolerant
\*RPNaturE Natural Engineers
\*RPNaturR Insatiably Curious
\*RPIthChm Ithkul Charm
\*RPAntIth Orion Redemption
\*RLStubbo Stubborn
\*RLSpaPor Low-Orbit Moons
\*RLFarmer Independent Farmers
\*RLParadi Paradise
\*RLBarrac Barracks Living
\*RLMilita Militant
\*RLCharis Charismatic
\*RPFantaT Fantastic Traders
\*RPTolera Tolerant
\*RPMilitT Military Traditions
\*RPEmpath Empathic
\*RPNatuaN Natural Navigators
\*RPLucky Lucky
\*RPAntarB Antaran Background
\*Temp Insert Description Here
\*SMRandom Random
\*SMNo No
\*SMYes Yes
\*SocOrder Ethos Social Order
\*Utopian Utopian
\*Tradilst Traditionalist
\*Militrst Militarist
\*Tribal Tribal
\*EthGoals Ethos Goals
\*EtSocial Ethos Society
\*EthDivin Ethos Divinity
\*Power Ethos Power Structure
\*Law Ethos Accepted Laws
\*Buerger Ethos Privileged Circles
\*Kult Ethos Dominant Cult
\*DKult Ethos Religios Order
\*Toleranz Ethos Religious Tolerance
\*Traditio Ethos Traditions
\*Talent Ethos Talents
\*Laster Ethos Negative Quirks
\*PursKnow Pursuit of knowledge
\*Honour Honour
\*Material Materialism
\*Equality Equality
\*Individu Individualist
\*Clan Clan
\*National Nationalist
\*Universl Universalism
\*Monothst Monotheist
\*Polythst Polytheist
\*Atheist Atheist
\*EmperGod Emperor-God
\*URich Ultra Rich
\*VRich Very Rich
\*Rich Rich
\*Abundant Abundant
\*Diverse Diverse
\*Heteroge Heterogeneous
\*Similar Similar
\*Reverent Reverent
\*Deferent Deferential
\*Individu Individualistic
\*Insubord Insubordinate
\*Sensitiv Sensitive
\*Knowledg Knowledgeable
\*Aware Aware
\*Insensit Insensitive
\*EventCar Event Cards
\*Genetic Genetic
\*Organic Organic
\*Composi Composite
\*Industr Industrial
\*Inherent Human Player Balancing
\*Risilic Silicoid Pack
\*Rigasba Gasbag Pack
\*Ricyber Cybernetik Pack
\*Riithku Ithkul Pack
\*RiHith Other
\*GravNorm Normal
\*GravMed Medium
\*GravHigh High
\*PolAbs Tolerant
\*PolprPop Ecological Consciousness
\*Subterra Underground
\*Maritim Maritime
\*Oberflch Surface
\*LWIRaub Overexploitation
\*LWISele Selective Cultivation
\*LWIAusge Balance
\*Duenger Intensive/p
Fertilization/p
\*Nebenpro By-Products
\*LWLimit Limited Quantity
\*LWQualit Strict Quality
\*Monokult Monoculture
\*Organ Organic/Biomass
\*Stein Rock/Minerals
\*Erze Ores
\*Bquali Quality Control
\*Staatlim State Regulation
\*Landnahm Landgrab
\*Bkonzern Large Corporation
\*Bprivat Private Claim
\*Bausgew Balanced
\*Braub Overexploitation
\*Bselek Selective Mining
\*Bnausgew Balance
\*Quali Qualitative
\*Quanti Quantitative
\*Paausgew Balanced
\*Werkzeug Tools/Mechanics
\*Waffen Weapons/War/p
machines/p
\*Konsum Consumer
\*Chemie Chemical Industry
\*Elektro Electronics Industry
\*Prkonzrn Large Companies
\*Prgilde Craft Guilds
\*Prmisch Mixed Companies
\*Pvextrem Extreme
\*Pvhoch High
\*Pvnorm Normal
\*Pvnied Low
\*Aristokt Trade
\*Militaer Military
\*Religio Religion
\*Volk Science
\*Kollektiv Collective/p
Consciousness/p
\*Unilaw Universal Law
\*Regiolaw Regional Law
\*Anarchie Anarchy Self-justice
\*Bfanatik Fanatic
\*Boekos Eco
\*Barbeit Workers/Farmers
\*Binterl Intellectuals
\*RKOrden Religious-military/p
order/p
\*RKFanati Zealotry
\*RKWussts Expansion of Mind
\*RKGotthe Naturalism
\*RKGigant Hedonism
\*Dkkasten Caste System
\*Dkopfer Sacrificial Cult
\*Dkinquis Inquisition
\*Dkpsycho Psychodelic Cult
\*Totolera Tolerant
\*Toausgew Balanced
\*Tointole Intolerant
\*Krieger Warriors
\*Spirit Spiritual
\*Haendler Traders
\*Bauern Peasants
\*Handwerk Craftsmen
\*Tolerant Adaptable to/p
Ecosystem/p
\*Technik Technicians
\*Navigat Navigators
\*Emphart Sixth Sense
\*Antaria Antarian Historians
\*Faul Indolencent
\*Individ Exceptionists
\*PESSIMIS Pessimists
\*Parzifis Pacifists
\*Pervers Perverts
\*Plmilit Military
\*Plhandel Trade
\*Plwiss Science
\*Fakoop Cooperative
\*Fanorm Normal
\*Faegoz Egocentric
\*BlMilit Military
\*BlReli Religion
\*BlIndus Industry
\*Hgwaffen Weapons
\*Hgdrogen Drugs
\*Hgsklav Slaves
\*Hgmuell Radioactive Waste
\*Hghehler Stolen Goods
\*Utwieder Recycling
\*Utland Landscaping
\*Utemisso Utilization-/p
conversion/p
\*Utverord Ecology Regulations
\*Offense Offense
\*Defense Defense
\*Kdausgew Balanced
\*Dsmilit Military
\*Dsreli Religion
\*Dshandel Trade
\*Dswissen Science
\*Mdomini Dominant
\*Mfrei Free Speech
\*Mausgew Balanced
\*Mzens Cencored
\*Wiplan Planned Economy
\*Wimarkt Market Economy
\*Ssmilit Military
\*Ssindwis Industry/Science
\*Ssterror Terror
\*Ssgilde Guilds

\\Humanoid descriptions

 \*RACE0D00 The Humans are the master manipulators of the Orion Sector, and have ruled or actively attempted to do so for thousands of Galactic Cycles.  Sly and greedy, they take by force only what they cannot take through negotiation or trade.  Recent Humans claim to be descendants of the Ancient Orions. Although most empires of the Orion Sector scoff at the arrogance of such a presumption, there is enough uncertainty in Humanity's origins to lend credibility to this "ancient legitimacy"...
 \*RACE0D01 The Evon have confounded their Orion Sector neighbors with their extreme secrecy.  Their people are easily recognized by their iridescent blue-black skin and shimmering gown-like clothing, and their cities and structures are elaborate and ornate, revealing an intricacy in design that seems to parallel everything that they do.  They are both mystical and mysterious, a society rich in ceremony and ritual, evoking questions that they will not readily answer...  
 \*RACE0D02 The Psilons have always been devoted to the pursuit of knowledge, a devotion that borders on fanaticism.  During the Dark Age, in exchange for favor from the Antaran overlords, the Psilons willingly allowed the Antaran geneticists to experiment on and manipulate their bodies to increase their capacity for learning and research.  The Psilons of today are the result of centuries of horrific genetic reconstruction: mentally powerful, but with their bodies weakened to the point where they must use hover chairs to move and mechanical waldoes to physically manipulate items in their world. 

\\Etherian descriptions

 \*RACE1D00 The Imsaeis are the most keenly observant of the Etherean races, which plays well with their ingratiating manner.  Their ability to gain acceptance through good listening and humility has made them valuable participants in diplomatic negotiations, and has provided them with vast amounts of information and intelligence.  The Imsaeis always know more than they say, and while on the outside they seem to be agreeable and engaging, secretly they are constantly striving to be in control of events around them.
 \*RACE1D01 The Eoladi give almost everyone a slight pause when they are first encountered, as each individual possesses his own personal code of ethics. Once understood and accepted, however, the Eoladi are valued society builders and competent leaders.  These skills came from the aftermath of the Etherean War, when all Etherean societies were shattered and needed to be rebuilt from scratch.  The Eoladi still believe that they have much to teach to the other Orion Sector races in the ways of personal and social improvement.

\\Geodic descriptions

 \*RACE2D00 Curiously unique, the Silicoids represent a true divergence from other life and its origins in the Orion Sector. They are believed to have come about from the shards of a giant sentient crystal that was destroyed above their home planet. Each Silicoid begins as an asexually created shard, incubated in a nutrient bath, and eventually grows into an individual with all of the prior knowledge of its "parent." This efficiency comes at a cost of speed, however, so forethought and careful planning are key to any successful Silicoid society.

\\Cybernetic descriptions

 \*RACE3D00 Calling themselves the "Pure Ones" to signify their complete separation from the corruption of biological matter, the Meklar are masters of mathematical and computer sciences, and their mechanical efficiency makes them both supreme industrialists and formidable foes in combat. Contemptuous of organic life forms (the "flesh beasts" of the Orion Sector), they also eschew their technologies, including economics and ecological science.  They despise the Cynoid, their Cybernetic brothers who have not yet rejected their biological origins.
 \*RACE3D01 The Cynoid have not completely turned their back on their biological origins, and are cyborgs, unlike the completely artificial Meklar.  The Cynoid are ruthless and brilliant when it comes to economic calculations and financial matters.  They understand the value of money, how to work it, how to use it, and how to exploit it in every way possible.  Outstanding barterers, they are often interested in improving the lot of their citizens to make them more productive and, hence, more taxable.

\\Ichthytosian descriptions

 \*RACE4D00 The Trilarians are one of the oldest races in the Orion Sector, and are known for being extreme traditionalists.  They are a peaceful race, and their society places great emphasis on art, architecture, and philosophy. They have changed very little since the War of the Depths and the Second Exile, trying desperately to regain the glories of their past while preparing for the new future that awaits them in the Orion Sector...
 \*RACE4D01 The Nommo are a cephalopodic species that once coexisted with the Trilarians.  They left after the War of the Depths to found their own empire, based on their more radical and militaristic beliefs.  They believe they are descended directly from the "Old One," the god of the first Ichthytosians who brought them wisdom (and who, ironically, was an Antaran scientist who began the first steps of genetic modification to the Ichthytosians).  This delusion that they are "children of god" has occasionally led to holy wars against those who might deny them their birthright, most notably the Trilarians who still lay claim to what the Nommo consider "their" homeworld...

\\Harvester descriptions

 \*RACE5D00 The Harvester Project was the result of the Antarans' quest for a biological agent that would ravenously infect most life forms and either kill them or render them mentally docile and obedient. It was a major endeavor, with dozens of research labs working on various facets of the project. And, in the end, the Antarans succeeded in breeding a parasite that did exactly what they wanted it to do. Other races fear and despise the Ithkul, and not without cause, for the many terrifying tales of their destructive power are unfortunately quite accurate.

\\Insectoid descriptions

 \*RACE6D00 The Klackon Hive Mind is the ultimate picture of a harmonious society working for the greater good of all.  The Klackons revere this purity of social form, not even noticing the cost in creative or original thought. This unity of purpose makes the Klackons brutally industrious and organized, with leaders born for their tasks and directing the masses without question.
 \*RACE6D01 The Tachidi are among the largest races in the Orion Sector.  Like the Klackons, they are extremely industrious and productive, but they have overcome the limitations of the Hive Mind and now view the universe with insatiable curiosity.  This curiosity is their biggest challenge, however, as it is the curiosity of a child, one that does not know that you can hurt the puppy if you pet it too hard...

\\ Saurian descriptions

 \*RACE7D00 The Sakkra are closest genetically to the original Saurians that forced their own evolution and left the Ichthytosian homeworld in exile thousands of cycles ago.  They are highly aggressive, easily angered, and carry a bitter scaly patch on their shoulders.  Their age-old hatred of the Ichthytosian species flavors every aspect of their society, and their drive to build and expand is often a pretext for finding and eliminating every trace of their ancient enemies.
 \*RACE7D01 The Raas were bred by their fellow Saurians as highly productive slave laborers, and were sold and used throughout the Orion Sector until the end of the Great War.  They orchestrated a vast and bloody revolution that ultimately earned them their freedom.  They left to found a new society, with their own governments and religion.  Their industrious natures are still there, and now they finally have a chance to work for themselves and take their place in the history of the Orion Sector.
 \*RACE7D02 Grendarl society relies on two core ideals: loyalty and indifference to physical hardship.  Their clan-based social structure emphasizes placing the group before the individual, with supreme honor resting on the concept of death before failing the Clan.  They are warriors, deriving just as much honor and glory from battle with their foes as from supporting the Clans.

 \*RACE8D00 The Harvester Project was the result of the Antarans' quest for a biological agent that would infect most life forms and either kill them outright or render them mentally docile and obedient.  It was a major endeavor, with dozens of research labs working on various facets of the project.  And, in the end, the Antarans succeeded in breeding a parasite that did exactly what they wanted it to do.  Now that parasite has been unleashed, and the Orion Sector races are right to be afraid of a species dedicated to wiping them out to the last.



\*RBIOHARS Adds +2 to bioharvest DEA efficiency.
\*RBIOHARG Adds +1 to bioharvest DEA efficiency.
\*RBIOHARA Default bioharvest DEA calculations.  Base efficiency is 5.  
\*RBIOHARP Deducts -1 from bioharvest DEA efficiency.

\*RBIOHSUP Doubles money from rare bioharvest products.
\*RBIOHGOO +50% money from rare bioharvest products.
 \*RBIOHAVE Normal money from rare bioharvest products.  Technology does not directly increase these revenues, but it does bring terraforming technology that opens new regions for growing food.  Bioharvesting efficiency also influences the amount of money you make from rare bioharvest products. 
\*RBIOHPOO -50% money from rare bioharvest products.

 \*RBIOPPSU +1 bio produced per pop.  Your race does not need to eat food.  Bio produced this way does not generate rare bioharvest products, and therefore not much money.  This ability does, however, transfer to your magnates and conquered populations. 
\*RBIOPPGO +.5 bio produced per pop.  Your race only needs to grow half as much food.
\*RBIOPPAV Normal bioharvesting by population.  
\*RBIOPPPO +1 additional bio required per pop.  Your race eats twice as much.  

 \*RBIOOUTE Your race reliably propogates subsistence farmers that generate +1 bioharvest per region.  In other words, for every region you inhabit, you will automatically feed 1 unit of pop.  It's like having a free Subterranean Farm in every region.  This is a handy ability to feed brand-new colonies, or to maintain a minimal population under seige.  On more populated planets, however, the effect will be inconsequential. 
 \*RBIOOUTS Your race reliably propogates subsistence farmers that generate +.5 bioharvest per region.  In other words, for every 2 regions you inhabit, you will automatically feed 1 unit of pop.  It's like having a free Hydroponics Farm in every region.    This is a handy ability to feed brand-new colonies, or to maintain a minimal population under seige.  On more populated planets, however, the effect will be inconsequential. 
 \*RBIOOUTG Your race generates +.25 bioharvest per region.  In other words, for every 4 regions you inhabit, you automatically feed 1 unit of population. 
 \*RBIOOUTA Your race is only average at subsistence farming, and generates no extra bioharvest per region.   
\*RBIOOUTP Your race is terrible at subsistence farming and requires more food than normal as you expand.  You require .5 more bioharvest per region.

\*RMININGS Adds +4 to mining DEA efficiency.
\*RMINING Adds +2 to mining DEA efficiency.
\*RMININGA Default mining DEA calculations.  Base efficiency is 5.
\*RMININGP Deducts -1 from mining DEA efficiency.

\*RMINRARS Doubles money from rare minerals.
\*RMINRARG +50% money from rare minerals.
 \*RMINRARA Normal money from rare minerals.  This is the best early source of money, but technology does not directly improve these revenues.  Mining efficiency also influences how much money you make from rare minerals. 
\*RMINRARP -50% money from rare minerals.

 \*RMINPPE Produce +2 units of minerals per pop.  Minerals produced this way do not generate rare minerals, and therefore not much money.  This ability does, however, transfer to your magnates and conquered populations. 
\*RMINPPS Produce +1 units of minerals per pop.
\*RMINPPG Produce +.5 units of minerals per pop.  
\*RMINPPA Normal minerals by population.
 \*RMINPPP Population consumes 1 unit of minerals.  WARNING:  if minerals drop into the negative, and you found a new colony, you will get a DirectX crash.  NOT RECOMMENDED FOR USE. 

\*RMANUFAS Adds +16 to manufacturing DEA efficiency.
\*RMANUFAG Adds +8 to manufacturing DEA efficiency.
\*RMANUFAA Default manufacturing calculations.  Base efficiency is 20.  
\*RMANUFAP Deducts -4 to manufacturing DEA efficiency.

 \*RMANUPPS +5 production per unit of population.  This production does not require a DEA, does not use minerals, is not affected by gravity, and   transfers   to your magnates.  It generates no cash.   
\*RMANUPPG +2.5 production per unit of pop.
\*RMANUPPA Normal production per unit of pop.  Base production per pop is 3.
\*RMANUPPP -1.5 production per unit of pop.  Your race will have a hard time getting new colonies on their feet.

\*RCRAFTS +10 to money produced by industry.
\*RCRAFTG +5 to money produced by industry.
 \*RCRAFTA Normal money produced by industry.  Base is 10.  Unlike bioharvest and mineral revenues, craftsmanship increases with technology.  Manufacturing efficiency has no direct affect on how much money you make from craftsmanship. 
\*RCRAFTP -5 to money produced by industry.

 \*RGENETIC Your industry runs on 100% bioharvest products.  As you research new technology, your industry will gradually begin requiring minerals.   
 \*RORGANIC Your industry runs on 50% bioharvest, 50% minerals.   
 \*RCOMPOSI Your industry runs on 25% bioharvest, 75% minerals 
\*RINDUSTR Your industry runs on 100% minerals

\*RRESEARS Adds +12 to research DEA efficiency.
\*RRESEARG Adds +6 to research DEA efficiency.
\*RRESEARA Default research DEA calculations.  Base efficiency is 10.
\*RRESEARP Deducts -3 from research DEA efficiency.

 \*RTESTE +4 test tubes produced per pop.  This research does not require a DEA, is not affected by gravity, and your magnates and conqured populations will have the same ability. 
\*RTESTS +2 test tubes produced per pop.
\*RTESTG +1 test tubes produced per pop.
\*RTESTA Normal test tubes produced per pop.  Base is 1.  

\*RRECREAS Your Recreation DEAs operate at +6 efficiency.  
\*RRECREAG Your Recreation DEAs operate at +2 efficiency.
\*RRECREAA Normal Recreation DEA effeciency.  Default is 3.  Recreation DEAs reduce unrest and generate money.  Your choice of government influences how effective recreation DEAs are.
\*RRECREAP Your Recreation DEAs are one-tenth as effective.

\*RMILITAS Your Military DEAs operate at +6 efficiency.
\*RMILITAG Your Military DEAs operate at +1 efficiency.
\*RMILITAA Normal Military DEA efficiency.  Default is 1.  Military DEAs greatly reduce unrest.  Your choice of government influences how effective military DEAs are.
\*RMILITAP Your Military DEAs are one-tenth as effective.

\*RTRADES Doubles the money made from trade agreements
\*RTRADEG Adds +50% to the money made from trade agreements
\*RTRADEA Uses the default trade calculations.
\*RTRADEP Halves the money made from trade agreements

\*RCRTRADS Increases likelihood of Trade Agreements by +50.
\*RCRTRADG Increases likelihood of Trade Agreements by +25.
\*RCRTRADA Uses the default trade calculations.
\*RCRTRADP Decreases likelihood of Trade Agreements by -25.

\*RPORTSS Increases the trade level by +4.
\*RPORTSG Increases the trade level by +2.
 \*RPORTSA Default space port efficiency.  Base space port efficiency is 3.  Spaceports are more effective with a low Oppressometer.  When the Oppressometer is at 0, space ports operate at +20%; when it is at 10, at -30%.  They are also more effective with peaceful military-political policies.  At   Peace and Prosperity  , spaceports operate at +15%; at   Holy War  , at -30%.   
\*RPORTSP Decreases space port efficiency by 2.

\*RTRADELS Increases the trade level by +4.
\*RTRADELG Increases the trade level by +2.
\*RTRADELA Default trade level.
\*RTRADELP Decreases the trade level by 2.

\*REXCHANS Your race is excellent at bartering.  Adds +100 to the chance to make an exchange agreement.
\*REXCHANG Your race is good at bartering.  Adds +50 to the chance to make an exchange agreement.
\*REXCHANA Default chance to make an exchange agreement. 
\*REXCHANP Your race is terrible at bartering.  Subtracts 50 from the chance to make an exchange agreement.

\*RENVIROS Reduces pollution by 90%.
\*RENVIROG Reduces pollution by 50%.
\*RENVIROA Uses the default environmental calculations.
\*RENVIROP Increases pollution by 50%.

\*RPOLABSS Doubles the amount of pollution absorbed (PolluAbs+=2)
\*RPOLABSG Increases the amount of pollution absorbed by 50% (PolluAbs+=1.5)
\*RPOLABSA Uses standard pollution absorbtion calculations
\*RPOLABSP Decrease the amount of pollution absorbed by 100% (PolluAbs+=-1)

\*RPPPAVG Normal Pollution per Person calculations used
\*RPPPP Pollution per person increased by 50% (Polperpop+=.5)
\*RPPPAWF Pollution per person increased by 100% (Polperpop+=1)
\*RPPPABY Pollution per person increased by 150% (Polperpop+=1.5)

 \*RGOVEFFS Increases Government Efficiency by +3.  Government DEAs give across-the-board increases in DEA efficiency and minor decreases in Unrest.  Superior Efficiency gives you roughly an 18% bonus to all DEAs in range of a Government DEA, a 31% bonus at a System Seat, and a 44% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  The Unrest is about -6 per region, but -12 at a System Seat, and -21 at an Imperial Seat.  Mining bonuses are much greater than for other DEAs, being roughly squared, so you normally get a 39% bonus, but a 71% bonus at a System Seat, and a 107% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  These numbers will fluctuate depending on regional population, technology, and the overlapping influence of other government DEAs.   
 \*RGOVEFFG Increases Government Efficiency by +1.5.  You get roughly 11% bonuses to all DEAs in range of a Government DEA, a 19% bonus at a System Seat, and a 28% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  The Unrest is about -3 per region, but -7 at a System Seat, and -11 at an Imperial Seat.  Mining bonuses are much greater than for other DEAs, being roughly squared, so you normally get a 23% bonus, but a 41% bonus at a System Seat, and a 64% bonus at an Imperial Seat. 
 \*RGOVEFFA Default Government Efficiency.  Base efficiency is 1, which gives roughly 4% bonuses to all DEAs in range of a Government DEA, an 8% bonus at a System Seat, and an 11% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  The Unrest is about -1 per region, but -2 at a System Seat, and -4 at an Imperial Seat.  Mining bonuses are much greater than for other DEAs, being roughly squared, so you normally get an 8% bonus, but a 16% bonus at a System Seat, and a 23% bonus at an Imperial Seat. 
 \*RGOVEFFP Decreases Government Efficiency by .5.  You get roughly 2% bonuses to all DEAs in range of a Government DEA, a 4% bonus at a System Seat, and a 6% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  The Unrest is about -1 per region, still -1 at a System Seat, and -2 at an Imperial Seat.  Mining bonuses are much greater than for other DEAs, being roughly squared, so you normally get a 4% bonus, but an 8% bonus at a System Seat, and a 12% bonus at an Imperial Seat.  WARNING:  with a Poor government, any mineral deficits you run will be approximately double what you expect because of slipshod practices.  Careful mineral management is therefore crucial! 

\*RHFOGS Your beaurocracy grows at half the normal rate.
\*RHFOGG Your beaurocracy grows at 75% of the normal rate.
 \*RHFOGA Your beaurocracy grows at a normal rate, gradually increasing the costs for everything you build in your empire. 
\*RHFOGP Your beaurocracy grows at 125% of the normal rate.

 \*RECONOMS Increases interest earned by 5%, decreases debt interest by 2% and decreases the heavy foot of government by 25%. 
 \*RECONOMG Increases interest earned by 2%, decreases debt interest by 1% and decreases the heavy foot of government by 10%. 
\*RECONOMA Uses the default economic calculations.
 \*RECONOMP Decreases interest earned by 1%, increases debt interest by 1% and increases the heavy foot of government by 5%. 

\*RACCURAS Increases Ground Combat ability by +2 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Reflexes and Toughness.
\*RACCURAG Increases Ground Combat ability by +1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Reflexes and Toughness.
\*RACCURAA Gives no bonus to Ground Combat.
\*RACCURAP Decreases Ground Combat ability by -1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Reflexes and Toughness.

\*RAPTITUS Increases the amount of experience gained by troops 200% and decreases the amount of experience lost by 95%.
\*RAPTITUG Increases the amount of experience gained by troops 124% and decreases the amount of experience lost by 85%.
\*RAPTITUA Uses the default experience calculations.
\*RAPTITUP Decreases the amount of experience gained by troops 15% and increases the amount of experience lost by 34%.

\*RREFLEXS Increases Ground Combat ability by +2 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Toughness.
\*RREFLEXG Increases Ground Combat ability by +1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Toughness.
\*RREFLEXA Gives no bonus to Ground Combat.
\*RREFLEXP Decreases Ground Combat ability by -1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Toughness.

\*RTOUGHNS Increases Ground Combat ability by +2 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Reflexes.
\*RTOUGHNG Increases Ground Combat ability by +1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Reflexes.
\*RTOUGHNA Gives no bonus to Ground Combat.
\*RTOUGHNP Decreases Ground Combat ability by -1 on a scale of 0 to 10.  This stacks with Accuracy and Reflexes.


\*RCRPEACS Increases your chance to make peacetreaties (CRPeaceT) by +50
\*RCRPEACG Increases your chance to make peacetreaties (CRPeaceT) by +25
\*RCRPEACA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RCRPEACP Decreases your chance to make peacetreaties (CRPeaceT) by -25

\*RCRTREAS Increases your chance to make treaties (CRTreaty) by +50
\*RCRTREAG Increases your chance to make treaties (CRTreaty) by +25
\*RCRTREAA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RCRTREAP Decreases your chance to make treaties (CRTreaty) by -25

\*RMEANSWS MeansWar counter increases by +2. (Less chance of war)
\*RMEANSWG MeansWar counter increases by +1. (Less chance of war)
\*RMEANSWA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RMEANSWP MeansWar counter decreases by -1. (More chance of war)

\*ROSMAYIS Increases Senate relations (OSMayILB) by 50%
\*ROSMAYIG Increases Senate relations (OSMayILB) by 25%
\*ROSMAYIA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*ROSMAYIP Decreases Senate relations (OSMayILB) by 20%

\*RPOSITIG Increases causus beli (PositivCB) by +10%
\*RPOSITIS Increases causus beli(PositivCB) by +20%
\*RPOSITIA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RPOSITIP Decreases casus beli (PositivCB) by -8%

\*RPOSITDS Increases diplomatic relations (PositivDP) by 80%
\*RPOSITDG Increases diplomatic relations (PositivDP) by 40%
\*RPOSITDA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RPOSITDS Decreases diplomatic relations (PositivDP) by 33%

\*RRCEDIPS Sets RaceDiplomacy level to 3 (AI less likely to attack higher numbers)
\*RRCEDIPG Sets RaceDiplomacy level to 2 (AI less likely to attack higher numbers)
\*RRCEDIPA Uses the default settings for reactions.
\*RRCEDIPP Sets RaceDiplomacy level to 0 (AI less likely to attack higher numbers)

 \*RBASECOS +50 to the base reaction modifier from other races.  Note:  very high reaction modifiers over +200 may   roll-over   the current relations slider so that it appears relations are deeply negative, but this is an appearance only, and in reality relations are still amazing.  
\*RBASECOG +25 to the base reaction modifier from other races.
\*RBASECOA Normal base reaction modifier.
 \*RBASECOP -25 to the base reaction modifier from other races.  If you want to be really hateful, take the Greater Special   Ithkul Charm  . 

\*RGRAVPEN Race has normal gravity tolerance (default)
\*RGRAVPEM Race has -1 bonus to grav penalty (Gravpen)
\*RGRAVPEH Race has -2 bonus to grav penalty (Gravpen)

"\*RGOVERNA Sets your initial government types to one of the Absolutionist Series. This Series includes Despotism, Monarchy, Oligarchy, and Constitutional Monarchy. Absolutist governments demand that one's primary loyalty be to the State. The Leader may be seen as merely a symbol of the State, as its servant, as its guiding force, or even as the State personified. In any case, Absolutist governments give their Leaders a relatively free hand to guide their governments as they see fit."	
"\*RGOVERNL Sets your initial government type to Feudal. An emperor keeps the throne of a feudal government by balancing and subtly encouraging the rivalries between the more powerful members of this class. There is little loyalty to the central government, and local barons are always on the lookout for personal gain. Citizens can't enjoy basic freedoms, propaganda outlets constantly spreading disinformation and military keeps a tight grip over any real opposition. Government uses slaves to power mines and agriculture, while native population works in factories. Research and development suffers greatly due to broken institutions, corruption and inexistent educational system. Peoples are very tried and willing to transform into any other government any minute. (Check encyclopedia Collectivist Details on the bottom)"
"\*RGOVERNR Sets your initial government types to one of the Representative Series. This Series includes Democracy, Parliamentary, Republicanism and Corporate.  The overarching purpose of Representative governments is to promote the good of individual citizens. When the good of individuals conflicts with the good of society as a whole, Representative governments generally side with individuals. For this reason, ordinary members of society are much more likely to be enfranchised under Representative governments than most other regimes."	
"\*RGOVERNC Sets your initial government types to one of the Collective Series. This Series includes Hive and Unification. Collectivist series governments demand that one's primary loyalty be to society as a whole. While virtually all government types claim to promote the general welfare of the society they rule, non-Collectivist regimes are all based on the assumption that people will resist government actions to some extent, whether because of self-interest, honest disagreements about the direction society should go, or sheer perversity. Thus, most governments are designed with the goal of minimizing public resistance to government policies in mind; some try to achieve this by using force to keep the population in line (e.g. Despotism), while others attempt to ensure that the government will only pursue policies a majority of the citizens already support (e.g. Representative series governments). By way of contrast, Collectivist series governments are premised on there being a fundamental harmony between the government and the governed, such that citizens will happily do whatever the government demands of them. When this condition is met, Collectivist governments can be extremely effective. However, many populations are simply unable to achieve the kind of social consensus necessary to make Collectivist government workable"	
"\*RGOVERNT Sets your initial government to a Random choice from 1 of the 4 main Series Representative, Absolutist, Collectivist, and Feudal."	

\*RSENATER There's a random chance of your race starting out as a member of the Orion Senate.
\*RSENATEN Guarantees that your race will not begin as a member of the Orion Senate.
\*RSENATEY Sets your race as a member of the Orion Senate when the game begins.

\*RCITIZES Deducts -30 per region from the unrest factors on your planets.
\*RCITIZEG Deducts -15 per region from the unrest factors on your planets.
\*RCITIZEA Uses the default unrest calculations.
\*RCITIZEP Adds +10 per region to the unrest factors on your planets.

 \*RPLANEUR Sets your initial starting planet as Mineral Ultra Rich.  The mountainous and broken regions both generate as many bulk minerals as the mountains on Very Rich planets, but many more rare minerals. 
\*RPLANEVR Sets your initial starting planet as Mineral Very Rich.
\*RPLANEMR Sets your initial starting planet as Mineral Rich.
\*RPLANEMA Sets your initial starting planet as Mineral Abundant.
\*RPLANEMP Sets your initial starting planet as Mineral Poor.

\*RPLANEBD Your home planet has one Alluvial plain and one Fertile plain.
\*RPLANEBH Your home planet has one Alluvial plain and one Arable plain.
\*RPLANEBS Your home planet has one Alluvial plain and one Hard Scrabble plain.

\*RBIOHG Your race can grow food on worlds from Red1 to Paradise.
\*RBIOHA Your race can grow food on worlds from Yellow1 to Paradise.
\*RBIOHP Your race can grow food on worlds from Green1 to Paradise.  

\*RCLOAKS Adds +2 to your spy cloaking.
\*RCLOAKG Adds +1 to your spy cloaking.
\*RCLOAKA Default spy cloaking.  Cloaking caps at 10.  This is your spies' ability to avoid being caught behind enemy lines.
\*RCLOAKP Subtracts 1 from your spy cloaking.

\*RDAGGERS Adds +2 to your spy dagger ability.
\*RDAGGERG Adds +1 to your spy dagger ability.
\*RDAGGERA Default spy dagger ability.  Dagger ability caps at 10.  This is your spies' ability to accomplish missions behind enemy lines.
\*RDAGGERP Subtracts 1 from your spy dagger ability.

\*RLUCKS Adds +40 to your spies' luck.
\*RLUCKG Adds +10 to your spies' luck.
 \*RLUCKA Default spy luck.  Average luck is usually between 25 and 40, and caps at 100.  Your spy lives one turn for every point of luck. 
\*RLUCKP Subtracts 10 from your spies' luck.

\*RSPTIMES Subtracts 2 from spy training time.
\*RSPTIMEG Subtracts 1 from spy training time.
 \*RSPTIMEA Default spy training time.  Scientific spies take 6 turns, Military and Social 5 turns, Political, Diplomatic, and Economic spies 4 turns to train. 
\*RSPTIMEP Adds 1 to spy training time.  

 \*RSPOFFS Adds 20 to spy insertion, 20 to spy offense, and 20 to spy loyalty. 
 \*RSPOFFG Adds 10 to spy insertion, 10 to spy offense, and 10 to spy loyalty. 
\*RSPOFFA Normal spy offensive abilities.  
 \*RSPOFFP Subtracts 10 from spy insertion, 10 from spy offense, and 10 from spy loyalty.   

\*RSPDEFS Adds 20 to spy defense and 20 to spy repel.
\*RSPDEFG Adds 10 to spy defense and 10 to spy repel.
\*RSPDEFA Normal spy defensive abilities.
\*RSPDEFP Subtracts 10 from spy defense and 10 from spy repel.

 \*ROPPRESS Increases your Optimum Oppressometer by +2, making you much more difficult to spy on. 
\*ROPPRESG Increases your Optimum Oppressometer by +1.
\*ROPPRESA Default Optimum Oppressometer.
 \*ROPPRESP Decreases your Optimum Oppressometer by 1, making you easier to spy on.   

\*RTECHDIS Increases the chance of having a technology overrun by 10%
\*RTECHDIG Increases the chance of having a technology overrun by 5%
\*RTECHDIA  Uses the default technology calculations.
\*RTECHDIP Decreases the chance of having a technology overrun by 5%

\*RTECHKNS You will know 98% of potential technologies. 
\*RTECHKNG You will know 86% of potential technologies. 
\*RTECHKNA You will know 74% of potential technologies. 
\*RTECHKNP You will know 62% of potential technologies. 

\*RTECHOVS Decrease the chance of a technology overrun will be negative by 10%
\*RTECHOVG Decrease the chance of a technology overrun will be negative by 5%
\*RTECHOVA  Uses the default technology calculations.
\*RTECHOVP Increases the chance of a technology overrun will be negative by 5%

\*RTECHPOS Increases the chance of a technology overrun will be positive by 10%
\*RTECHPOG Increases the chance of a technology overrun will be positive by 5%
\*RTECHPOA  Uses the default technology calculations.
\*RTECHPOP Decreases the chance of a technology overrun will be positive by 5%

\*RPOPGROS Your race grows 40% faster than normal.
\*RPOPGROG Your race grows 20% faster than normal.
\*RPOPGROA Your race has normal growth.
\*RPOPGROP Your race grows 10% slower than normal.

 \*RCLONINE Your race starts with cloning technology equivalent to the Biology 25 technology   Cloning Centers  .  This gives your race a fixed pop growth increase, +.025, that greatly increases growth on sparely settled colonies, but is scarcely noticeable on large colonies.  For instance, a normal Human race will grow at 3.5% on their Alluvial Plains on turn 1, but a Human race with this technology will grow at 5.5%.  However, this growth advantage diminishes by about a tenth of a percentage point every other turn as the region fills and the cloning increase becomes relatively smaller.   
 \*RCLONINS Your race starts with cloning technology that gives a fixed pop growth of +.016, or about 2/3rds that of   Cloning Centers.   
 \*RCLONIGO Your race starts with cloning technology that gives a fixed pop growth of +.008, or about 1/3rd that of   Cloning Centers.   
\*RCLONINA Your race starts with no cloning technology.  

\*RMAXPS Your race fits 30% more people on a planet and grows about 15% faster.
\*RMAXPG Your race fits 15% more people on a planet and grows about 7.5% faster.
\*RMAXPA Your race has normal population maximums.
\*RMAXPP Your race fits 10% fewer people on a planet and grows about 5% slower.

\*RTERRAE Your race begins with 3 rings of terraforming technology.
\*RTERRAS Your race begins with 2 rings of terraforming technology.
\*RTERRAG Your race begins with 1 ring of terraforming technology.
\*RTERRAA Your race begins without terraforming technology.

\*RTERCSTS Your race terraforms at 1/10th normal cost.
\*RTERCSTG Your race terraforms at 1/2 normal cost.
\*RTERCSTA Your race pays normal costs for terraforming.  These costs increase for each ring a planet is terraformed.
\*RTERCSTP Your race pays 3 times normal costs for terraforming.

\*RANTARXS You have twice the chance to find Antaran artifacts.
\*RANTARXG You have +20% chance to find Antaran artifacts.
\*RANTARXA You have the default chance to find Antaran artifacts.
\*RANTARXP You have 1/10th the chance to find Antaran artifacts.

\*RSOUTOPN Utopian societies focus their attentions on the perfection of the individual, and the strive for harmony with one another and their environment.  Positions of power in these societies are generally held by those individuals best suited to the particular role, whether through natural ability or temperament, while the rest of the populace pursue their own concerns./p/pProvides a 50% bonus to the efficiency of Recreation DEAs, a 20% bonus to Maximum Population and Population Growth, +1 to Industry and Test Tubes per Population point, and allows one level of terraforming beyond what is normally allowed by technology (up to Sweet Spot).
\*RSOTRDST Traditionalist societies are concerned with the rule of law, and are ruled by customs even stronger than law.  They promote order and balance, and generally concentrate power in institutions of long-established lineage.  Every being knows its place in such a society, and the process of government is made much more efficient thereby./p/pProvides a 25% bonus to the efficiency of Government DEAs and reduces the Heavy Foot of Government by 25%.
\*RSOMLTST Militarist societies concern themselves primarily with conquest, and rule by force of arms.  Positions of power are almost always held by military officers, and order is maintained by strong para-military police forces./p/pProvides a 25% bonus to the efficiency of Military DEAs, a 50% bonus to the number of Militia units generated to defend a planet, and subtracts 20% from Fleet Maintenance costs.
\*RSOTRIBL Tribal societies generally organize themselves along family lines, and the heads of the most important families tend to dominate.  This is the most simplistic form of social order, and is usually replaced with a more complex system as a society matures./p/pProvides no bonuses or penalties.

\*REGKNOWL This ethos' highest value is to advance the scientific knowledge of the race.  Its members will place their pursuit of the sciences before all else, including personal gain, national concerns, even, in the case of the fanatical Psilons, before their own physical well-being.  More moderate races, however, will simply encourage their members to pursuit a higher education and a career in research, while more spiritual races will often have monks who devote their lives to research in laboratories-monasteries.  Such a devotion to knowledge is its own failing, as less intellectual vocations, such as bioharvesting, mining and manufacturing, are considered menial, secondary, failing morally, and are often shun by polite society.
\*REGHONOR This ethos' highest value is honour.  Its members will always try to do what's right.  They never lie, and always stand by their word, no matter the price.  Failing to do the honourable thing is the highest moral crime.  The penalty varies from society to society, but it is always quite severe: the Grendarls challenge dishonourable members to duels to the death, while Sakkras expulse them from their clan.  Honourable societies benefit from reduced unrest in the population.  However, its people have a lot of trouble playing the dishonourable games of cloak and dagger.
\*REGMATER This ethos holds that one's first priority in life is to improve one's own physical condition.  Such an ethos might preach that the physical world is the only one that matters, or that one's standing in the spiritual world is a reflection of the physical world.  The Gnolams are the most famous race to have followed such an ethos, and they often spent their lives scouting the galaxy, looking for rare and luxurious artefacts that would bring them instantaneous fortune.  Obviously, a people that subscribes to such an ethos will have mastered the arts of trade, in order to make deals that will be as profitable as possible.  However, very few of those people will be tempted to take on a career as a researcher, as the rewards can be very sparse.
\*REGEQUAL This ethos preaches complete social equality.  Everyone is equal, every job is of equal importance, and therefore every citizen is equally deserving of the rewards earned by society as a whole.  Trillian society, in the centuries of peace and prosperity between the War of the Depths and the Dark Ages, developed such an equalitarian philosophy.  The feeling of social membership inherent to this ethos encourages workers to be as productive as they can.  However, the sight of any social inequality will disturb people who believe in this ethos, and as such inequalities are inevitable in the Universe this can become a constant source of social unrest.

\*RESINDIV This ethos preaches the "every man for himself" philosophy.  This is not necessarily an egocentric ethos: the Eoladi for instance believe that only you know what is best for yourself, and that attempting to involve yourself in someone else's affairs can often cause more harm than good.  Therefore, followers of this ethos attempt to improve their own lives in the way they think is best.  This gives the population a sense of empowerment, of control over their destiny, which goes a long way towards reducing social unrest.  However, diplomatic negotiations with such a people can be quite arduous, as the negotiator will place his own needs and wants first.
\*RESCLAN Societies following this ethos organize themselves in a "clan" structure.  These clans are often based around blood-relatives, as is the case in Sakkra society, the most famous clan-based society in the sector.  Other forms of clan associations can exist however, like social casts, sexual subgroups, or even the worker unions of the Raas.  Members of a clan look after each other and help each other in any way possible, without expecting personal rewards, to advance the social standing of the clan.  On the other hand, a person that commits actions that hurt his clan's standing or reputation can be expelled or ever executed by his clan-mates, and fights between clans, even over trivial matters, can often last for generations.  Each clan has to insure its security, and therefore has to organize a clan military force.  When the entire society is threatened, several clans will combine their forces and raise quite a powerful interstellar army.  However, because each individual considers the needs of his clan first, the central government's power and efficiency is weakened.
\*RESNTION This ethos encourages people to place the needs of the State before all else.  All work, all social development and achievements, must be focused on pushing the empire forward.  It is this mentality that drives empires such as the Klakons and the Nommo to aggressively expand into the galaxy.  There are obvious differences between these two races: the Klakons are biologically bound to obey the Hive Mind, while the Nommo freely chose to devote their existence to their race.  However, members of both these races will loyally, even blindly, obey edicts from their government and work towards the objective of advancing their race's standing in the Sector.  They will let nothing, be it an enemy nation or environmental concerns, stand in their way.
\*RESUNIVR Members of this ethos are thought to look beyond the divisions of cast, race, or empire, and to embrace all life forms as equals, partners in Creation.  This ethos teaches that matters of the individual or of the state are trivial, what matters is the Universe as a whole.  One's true purpose in life should be to help advance all races, all people, in a quest for universal understanding and unity.  The Imsaeis follow such an ethos, and travel the galaxy to observe, understand and advise the other races, in the hope of guiding them towards a greater common good.  The teachings of universal understanding and unity that this ethos is based on make its followers superb diplomats, however it does greatly discourage them from using military forces.

\*REDMONST This ethos is based around the belief that there is a single all-powerful being that created the Universe and guides the races (his Children).  Often, the doctrine of such an ethos will be based around the testimonies of prophets who have had visions from or contact with the Supreme Being.  These testimonies will allow the creation of a set of rules, which the Supreme Being wants his children to follow.  These rules can however be impractically rigid, and when a government's edict bends or breaks one of these rules, the people are forced to decide between their ethos and their government.  Usually, the dictates of the ethos will dominate, and the government's standing will be weakened.  Human society is based on such a monotheist ethos, and before the Dark Ages Human missionaries traveled the Sector in search of non-believers (which they called the Lost Children), to tell them of their prophets' stories.  Through extensive contact with aliens, the missionaries brought back knowledge of foreign culture and beliefs, which is a great help to Human diplomats.
\*REDPOLST This ethos is based around the belief that there are several powerful beings that exist in a Realm beyond our comprehension.  These beings have social relations like us: they make deals with each other, they can betray each other, they can have children and they can even kill one another.  Each of these beings also has control over an aspect of our physical realm.  They can interact with us directly through prophets or indirectly through nature, and the greatest heroes of our world can even cross over to theirs to help them in their struggles.  Members of this ethos are neutral towards alien ethos, and simply accept alien gods as more deities in the other Realm.  Polytheist societies have a great respect for nature, as it is often through nature that their gods speak to them.  However, they also build luxurious temples, organize elaborate ceremonies and offer expensive gifts to their gods, in hope of gaining their favours.  These rich and intricate traditions are most remarkable in Evon society, and have captivated all those who have been in contact with the blue-skinned aliens.  However, those luxurious traditions can put a strain on their society's economy.
\*REDATHST This ethos is based around the belief that there is no mystical super-powerful being and no spiritual realm.  All that exist is the Universe, and there is nothing beyond or outside it.  The laws of nature are sufficient to explain it entirely, and anything that appears to be mystical or spiritual is simply the result of an insufficient or incorrect understanding of these laws.  Members of an atheist ethos will seek to understand the laws of nature because of a need to explain their environment and their existence, and to disprove claims of the supernatural.  The Psilons are an example of an atheist society where that quest for knowledge has turned to fanaticism.  Their inability to fully understand the Universe in mathematical terms, however, is often a source of social unrest.  The reaction of an atheist society towards another ethos can vary greatly, and can range from respectful acceptance to pity to downright intolerance for their simple-mindedness.
\*REDEMPGD This is a very special ethos.  It can be based on either monotheist or polytheist beliefs.  There can be one Supreme Being, or several of them in another Realm.  But this being or these beings have cast their power into a mortal form, the Emperor who leads the society.  The Emperor might have been blessed with his powers at his birth, or he might have been blessed while still in the womb, or he could even be the child of one of the gods and a mortal.  In any case, the Emperor has received supernatural strength and abilities, higher intelligence and wisdom, even knowledge of the future.  He can never be wrong, and must be obeyed at all times.  The Meklar people follow such an ethos: they obey an emperor-unit who received a divine algorithm from the gods, which gives it unique abilities.  A society following an Emperor-God benefits from reduced social unrest: it can be quite comforting to be able to see your god and to talk to him in person.  However, such societies are also intolerant of other races, the Infidels who dare to look upon the Emperor and refuse to recognise his divine nature.  This intolerance can spill over to the negotiating table, and put a strain on diplomatic relations.

 \*RRLSTUBB +2% chance to know potential techs.  Combined with Superior Creativity, this gives you a 100% chance to know potential technologies. 
\*RRLSPAPO Your race begins with the capability of building Space Ports.  Ordinarily Space Ports are researched at Physics level 7.  A region must have a minimum population of 2 to build a Space Port.
 \*RRLFARME Your race reliably propogates subsistence farmers that generate +.25 bioharvest per region.  This is a handy ability to feed brand-new colonies, or to maintain a minimal population under seige. 
\*RRLBARRA You only pay 1/10th cost for fleet maintenance.  
 \*RRLMILIT Your Military Capacity is +1.  This means your military DEAs start the game influencing an entire planet.  The default is to begin influencing only a single region.  WARNING:  If you research   Z Storage and Basing Facilities   at Economy 42, AND you steal Trans Dimensional Battlements from the New Orions, AND you have all the other Military Capacity technologies, then your Military Capacity will   roll over   and your Military DEAs will become useless. 
 \*RRLCHARI You attract amazing leaders.  Your leaders have +20 to ability, luck, persuasion, and loyalty, and -10 to clout, ambition, and corruption.  (Those are all good things.)  Do these variables work?  Who knows?  Buyer beware!   

 \*RRLPARAD You have the ability to terraform worlds to paradise, provided you have the requisite terraforming ring technology to get that far! 
 \*RSPECIA1 For those of you who just can't get enough Manufacturing Efficiency, here's another +16. 
 \*RSPECIA2 For those of you who just can't get enough Research Efficiency, here's another +12. 
 \*RSPECIA3 Check this box in combination with the   Poor   Reaction Modifiers to be just as popular as the Ithkul!  In fact you'll be worse, since the Antarans will hate you, too.  -125 to Reaction Modifiers. 
 \*RSPECIA4 For those Ithkul who have always wanted to be loved, check this box and have normal diplomacy!  Also, the Antarans will adore you.  +150 to Reaction Modifiers.   

\*RCHEATA You are not cheating in any way.  Base pollution per pop is .75.
 \*RCHEATP Your race gets 100 free points, except that out of guilt they produce an additional 1/10th of a point of pollution per pop.  You're a cheater. 
 \*RCHEATAW Your race gets 200 free points, except that out of guilt they produce an addtional 2/10ths of a point of pollution per pop.  You're an awful cheater. 
 \*RCHEATAB Your race gets 300 free points, except that out of guilt they produce an additional 3/10ths of a point of pollution per pop.  You're an abysmal cheater.   

\*SILIPACK Select this ONLY if you are playing as Silicoid. (Computer Silicoids gets more bonuses)
\*GASBPACK Select this ONLY if you are playing as Gasbags. (Computer Gasbags gets more bonuses)
\*CYBEPACK Select this ONLY if you are playing as Cybernetik race. (Computer Cybers gets more bonuses)
\*ITHKPACK Select this ONLY if you are playing as Ithkul. (Computer Ithkul gets more bonuses)
\*HUITPACK Other

\*RHASUBTR Underground cultivation methods. +0.5 bioharvest capacity.
\*RHAMARIT Maritime farming methods. +0.5 bioharvest capacity.
\*RHAOBERF Surface cultivation methods. +0.5 bioharvest capacity.

\*LWINRAUB Reckless agricultural cultivation. Increases agricultural DEA efficiency by 2 and agricultural production per population point by 0.5. Increases pollution by 20%.
\*LWINSELE Gentle agricultural cultivation. Reduces pollution by 20% and terraforming costs by 10% - but also the efficiency of agricultural DEA by 1.
\*LWINAUSG Normal setting./p 

\*RLWMDUEN /p
Many agricultural businesses use too much fertilization for optimal yield. Increases pollution by 10% and by contaminated food -5 pollution absorption. Increases the efficiency of the agricultural DEA by 1.
\*RLWMNEBE Since agricultural production alone is not profitable in many agricultural companies, these companies often specialize in resource extraction. Therefore increases resource extraction per population point by 1, but reduces the efficiency of the agricultural DEA by 1 and its capacity by 1.
\*RLWMMONO For increased yields, many companies prefer to concentrate exclusively on one product. As a result, the price of food products often drops to the bottom. Reduces the efficiency of the space by 1. Reduces the rare raw materials per food unit by 20%. Increases the efficiency of the agricultural DEA by 1.
\*RLWMLIMI To achieve better prices on the market, a quantity limit was introduced. Therefore reduces the agricultural surplus by 2 and the agricultural production per population point by 0.5. Increases the efficiency of the rooms by 1.
\*RLWMQUAL Due to strict quality controls, most agricultural businesses have long since switched to the best quality. Reduces the efficiency of the agricultural DEA by 1 and the agricultural surplus by 1. Increases the rare raw materials generated by agricultural production by 20%.

\*RMINORGA Organic material or biomass. Increases mine capacity by 0.5.
\*RMINSTEN Rock or minerals. Increases mine capacity by 0.5.
\*RMINERZE Ores, metals. Increases mine capacity by 0.5.

\*RBBMQUAL In order to produce high quality products, high quality resources are required. Inferior material remains in the earth. Reduces mining DEA efficiency by 1, as well as mining surplus. Increases rare raw materials from mining by 20%.
\*RBBMSTAA The price for resources remains reasonably stable, the state or trade organizations limit the mining. Reduces mining surplus by 2 and resources per population point by 0.5. Increases the efficiency of the rooms by 1.
\*RBBMLAND Expropriation of private property at resource prospecting. Increases churn rate by 10% and agitation factor by 2. Increases mining efficiency by 1.

\*RBBBKONZ Only large corporations take over the mining. Increases mining DEA efficiency by 1 and increases capacity by 1. Decreases resource production per population point by 0.5.
\*RBBBPRIV Predominantly small companies or interest groups are mining the resources. Increases resource production per population point by 1. Decreases mining DEA efficiency by 1.
\*RBBBAUSG Normal setting./p

\*RBBNRAUB Reckless depletion of resources. Increases mining DEA efficiency by 2 and resources per population point by 0.5. Increases the cost of terraforming by 10%.
\*RBBNSELE Selective, careful depletion of resources. Reduces terraforming costs by 20% and pollution by 5%. Reduces mining DEA efficiency by 1.
\*RBBNAUSG Normal setting./p

\*RPRAQUAL Increases production AU by 10% and resource utilization rate by 1. Decreases Industry efficiency by 1.
\*RPRAQUAN Increases Industry efficiency by 1 and Industry capacity by 1. Decreases AU from production by 10%.
\*RPRAAUSG Normal setting./p

\*RPSPWERK Specializing in toolmaking and precision engineering. Production per population point increases by 0.5.
\*RPSPKONS Specializing in consumer goods such as clothing, jewelry and other luxury items. Increases recreation DEA efficiency by 10%.
\*RPSPCHEM Specializing in the manufacture of chemical substances and plastics. Increases production and research efficiency by 1. Worsens pollution by 10%.
\*RPSPELEK Specializing in the manufacture of electronic devices. Increases test tubes by 0.5 per population point.
\*RPSPWAFF /p
Specialization in weapon production and manufacture of ground war equipment. Increases ground combat ability by 1.

\*RPRBKONZ Production is mainly managed by large corporations. Increases the efficiency of Industry DEAs by 1 and their capacity by 1. Decreases production per population point by 0.5.
\*RPRBGILD Traditional craft guilds run the production. The production per population point increases by 1 and the AE generated by the production by 10%. Reduces the efficiency of Industry DEAs by 1.
\*RPRBMISB Normal setting./p

\*RPRVEXTR Pollution increases by 30%, while terraforming costs increase by 10%. Increases the Industry DEA efficiency by 1 and its capacity by 0.25.
\*RPRVHOCH Increases pollution by 10%. Increases the efficiency of the Industry DEA by 1.
\*RPRVNORM Normal setting./p
\*RPRVNIED Reduces pollution by 10% and the efficiency of Industry DEAs by 1.

\*RPOWERAR Allows the aristocracy and rich traders to share the power. Increases spaceport effect by 5%, the efficiency of the Industry DEA by 1, and the agitation factor by 1.
\*RPOWERMI The military has a considerable claim to power in this society. Increases the efficiency of the military DEA by 2 and the generation of militia units by 20%, reduces the unrest factor by 3. Increases both the costs of suppression and the maintenance of the fleets by 10%.
\*RPOWERRE Religious representatives and fanatics shape power here. Increases the Recreation DEA efficiency by 2, reduces suppression costs by 10% and the agitation factor by 2. Decreases the efficiency of the research DEA by 1.
\*RPOWERVO Scientists and scholars form a majority in the government. Increases the efficiency of the research DEA by 2, decreases the likelihood of a technological overrun by 5, and increases the likelihood that an overdraft will occur will be increased by 5. Also increases the likelihood of a tech block is reported by 5. Decreases the efficiency of the government DEA by 1 and increases the unrest factor by 1.

\*RLAWKOLL /p
No law is needed. The collective consciousness excludes practically every crime - in most cases at least. Reduces unrest factor by 5. Increases government DEA efficiency by 2.
\*RLAWUNIL A universal law for all classes and classes. Reduces the unrest factor by 2, increases the efficiency of the government DEA by 1.
\*RLAWREGL Special rights for higher classes, special obligations for lower classes. Increases the agitation factor by 1.
\*RLAWANAR No real constitution. Vigilante justice that differs from planet to planet. Good armament. Increases militia generation by 50% but increases unrest factor by 3. Decreases government DEA efficiency by 2.

\*RBRSFANA Religious-philosophical fanatics enjoy a special status and make governing difficult. Increases the unrest factor by 2, reduces the efficiency of government DEAs by 1. Increases the number of militia units generated by 10%, reduces the suppression costs by 5%.
\*RBGSOEKO Ecologically oriented associations enjoy a special status and make governing difficult. Increases the agitation factor by 1 and the suppression costs by 5%. Reduces government DEA efficiency by 1. Reduces environmental impact by 10%.
\*RBGSARBT Trade unions and agricultural associations enjoy a special status and make governing difficult. Increases the agitation factor by 5 and the suppression costs by 10%. Reduces the efficiency of government DEAs by 1. Increase by 0.5 agriculture, resource depletion and production per population point.
\*RBGSINTE Intellectual associations and faculties are particularly important and thus make governing more difficult. Increases the agitation factor by 2, reduces the efficiency of government DEAs by 1. Increases the test tubes per population point by 0.5.

\*RRGKULT1 /p
Military orders that go to war to spread the "true" faith. Increases ground combat ability by 1 and spies' ability by 1. Because of increased aggressive behavior, the diplomatic attitude of other races towards you is reduced by 10%./p
\*RRGKULT2 Fanatic supporters of this cult guarantee excellent civil defense: + 20% militia generation. Strict dogmas and controls to keep these commandments reduce suppression costs by 10%. However, the people do not have much to laugh about, the efficiency of the Recreation DEAs is reduced by 2.
\*RRGKULT3 /p
Mental training and meditations strengthen the inner values of the population. Research increases by 0.5 test tubes per population point. Significant appreciation of spy luck. However, a uniform worldview is always questioned, the unrest factor increases by 2. Meditation centers increase the efficiency of the recreational DEA by 1.
\*RRGKULT4 The adoration of nature itself causes above all a good use of it and its resources. The efficiency of government DEAs increases by 2. In addition, the nature worship significantly reduces the agitation factor by 3, which also results in a 20% reduction in suppression costs. The efficiency of the recreational DEA increases through ceremonial staging by 1. The population is somewhat disturbed in their free creativity by the omnipotence of the nature powers, which reduces the test tubes per population point by 0.5. 
\*RRGKULT5 Hedonistic events in huge temples increase the efficiency of the recreational DEA by 3 and the impressive design of other races increases the basic attitude towards you by 10%. The disadvantage is the constant riots and riots that arise from the events. This increases the agitation factor by 2.

\*RDRKKAST A caste system that differentiates between high and low quality peoples. Leads to impoverishment of the lower castes and therefore reduces the growth rate of the population by 5%. The military training is prohibited in the lower caste, which is why 20% fewer militia units can be raised. Finally lowers the suppression costs by 10%.
\*RDRKOPFR Mass sacrifices to appease the gods have been the custom here for ages. Reduces the growth rate of the population by a 10%. Since the cult of sacrifice is unintelligible for the most other races, the basic attitude of other races deteriorates towards you by 25%. The belief in well-tuned gods awakens a feeling of security among many and lowers the unrest factor by 1.
\*RDRKINQU Merciless torture and humiliation for the good of religion lead to a 5% decrease in population growth rate, and the spread of anxiety reduces test tubes by 0.5 per population point. Lastly, reduces suppression costs by 10%.
\*RDRKPSYO /p
Legal ingestion of psychedelic drugs for ceremonial purposes often causes mental illness in the population. Reduces the efficiency of the Industry DEA, the mining DEA and the agricultural DEA by 1 each. In addition, the suppression costs are increased by 5%. However, increases the entertainment value in the population: +1 to the Recreation DEA efficiency.

\*RRTOTOLE Increases the growth rate of the population by 5% and improves the basic attitude of other races towards you by 20%. Increases the agitation factor by 2 and reduces the chance of unmasking an enemy spy by 1.
\*RRTOAUSG Normal setting./p
\*RRTOINTO Increases the probability of unmasking an enemy spy by 2. Decreases the unrest factor by 1. Decreases the basic attitude of other races towards you by 10% and the growth rate of the population by 5%.

\*RTRADITK This specie has a long tradition of war. Increases ground combat ability by 1.
\*RTRADITS Promotes the ingenuity of the population. Increases by 0.5 test tube per population point.
\*RTRADITH It has been the custom here to do business for ages. The efficiency of the rooms increases by 2.
\*RTRADITB This specie has always been skilled in making land fertily. Increases agriculture by 0.5 per population point.
\*RTRADITW The craft has always been a tradition here. The AU generated by production increases by 10%.

\*RTALENTA /p
Adaptable species receive a 30% bonus on pollution tolerance and 20% on pollution absorption.
\*RTALENTT Technically gifted species increase research capacity by 10% and get + 10% on robot technology.
\*RTALENTN Navigators travel 10% faster with warp drives.
\*RTALENTE The sixth sense brings about a 20% improvement to ship detection radius. Spies receive a +2 bonus on homeland security. In addition, the positive diplomatic bonus improves by 20%.
\*RTALENTX 20% higher chance to discover Antaran technology.

\*RLASTERV The reputation of being sexually deviant, enjoying the suffering of others, and performing strange experiments trail this specie. Increases diplomacy by 20% and population growth decreases by 5%, immoral experiments reduce the likelihood of a technological overrun by 5.
\*RLASTERZ The people despise the use of violence and war in general. Fleet maintenance therefore increases by 20%, the efficiency of the military DEA decreases by 2 and the generated militia units by 20%. In addition, ground combat capability is reduced by 1. The likelihood of achieving a non-aggression pact or a peace agreement increases slightly.
\*RLASTERP Continuous clairvoyance and distrust reduce the basic relationships with other breeds by 20%. Also causes the people to be more difficult to control. The agitation factor increases by 2 and the suppression costs by 10%. The probability of unmasking an enemy spy increases by 1.
\*RLASTERI One thinks of oneself rather than the community of the people. The disagreement causes unrest and crime. The unrest factor consequently increases by 3, the suppression costs by 20%. The test tubes per population point increase by 0.5.
\*RLASTERF This specie generally spends more time enjoying than working. The efficiency of the Industry, mining and agricultural DEA is reduced by 1. The efficiency of the Recreation DEA is increased by 2.

\*RPRLMILI Reduces fleet maintenance by 10%. Reduces Idndustry conversion rate by 1 and manufacturing AU by 10%.
\*RPRLHAND Increases the efficiency of the spaceport by 1. Decreases the conversion rate of Industry by 1 and the capacity of the Industry DEA by 0.5.
\*RPRLWISS Increases the test tubes per population production by 0.25. Reduces resource conversion rate by 1 and Industry DEA capacity by 0.5.

\*RFRAKOOP Consistent collaboration between scientists. Increases the efficiency of research DEAs by 2 and their capacity by 1.
\*RFRANORM Normal setting./p
\*RFRAEGOZ Fierce competition in research and strict project secrecy lead to a reduction in the efficiency of all research DEAs by 1 and their capacity by 0.5. Reduces the likelihood of a technological overrun by 5.

\*RBDLMILI Many military academies and sports influenced by military increase the efficiency of military DEAs by 10%. Reduces the efficiency of the research DEAs by 1 and the test tubes per population point by 0.25 through one-sided education.
\*RBDLRELI Religious schools and religion reduce the likelihood of an insurrection by 2. Unilateral education reduces the efficiency of the research DEAs by 1 and the test tubes per population point by 0.5.
\*RBDLINDU The industry invests considerable sums in education, as a result the AU generated by production increases by 1, while due to the one-sided education the efficiency of the research DEAs decreases by 1 and their industrial and educational institutions reduce their efficiency Capacity by 0.25.

\*RHDGWAFF Legal arms trade. Increases the efficiency of the space port by 1 and the profit from trade agreements by 20%. Increases the unrest factor by 3 and slightly worsens the chance of a trade agreement.
\*RHDGDROG Legal drug trafficking. Increases the efficiency of the space ports by 1 and the profit from trade agreements by 20%. Increases suppression costs by 20% and worsens the chances of a trade agreement.
\*RHDGSKLA Legal slave market. Increases the efficiency of the spaces by 1 and the profit from trade agreements by 20%. Increases the unrest factor by 2, reduces the basic attitude of other races to you by 20%. Worsens the chances of a trade agreement significantly.
\*RHDGMULL Allowed trade in garbage and hazardous waste products. Increasing the efficiency of the spaceports by 1 and the profit from trade agreements by 10% improves the chances of a trade agreement a little. Increases pollution by 20% and reduces the amount of environmental cleanup per AU by 20%.
\*RHDGHEHL Black market trading in stolen valuable goods from across the galaxy. Increases the efficiency of the space ports by 1 and the profit from trade agreements by 10%. Lowers the basic attitudes of other races by 10% and slightly worsens the chances of a trade agreement.

\*RUMTWIED Best recycling of waste to resources ratio. Reduces pollution by 10%. Increases the resources gained per population point by 0.5. As this makes mining somewhat less profitable, the capacity of the mining DEAs is reduced by 0.5.
\*RUMTLAND Inclusion of natural landscape areas as an integral part of the development of the country. Pollution is reduced by 10% and terraforming costs are reduced by 20%. As a result, many actually accessible agricultural areas are not built on, which is why the capacity of the agricultural DEAs is reduced by 0.5.
\*RUMTEMSS /p
Industrial and traffic utilization are efficiently used to filtered out pollution and send it to atmosphere. Reduces pollution by 20%. However, it also reduces the efficiency of industrial DEAs by 1.
\*RUMTVERO /p
Strict environmental regulations and severe penalties for eco-offenses reduce the environmental impact by 10%. But increases the unrest factor by 1, because the population perceives this as an incision in their personal freedom.

\*RKRDOFFN Increasing ground combat ability by 1 increases experience gained by 50%.
\*RKRDDEFE Increases the efficiency of the military DEA by 1 and the number of militia units generated by 10%, as well as the attachment factor by 1.
\*RKRDAUSG Normal setting./p

\*RDPSMILI Military officials set the tone in diplomatic negotiations. This improves negotiations with other races in the area of non-aggression pact and alliance deals.
\*RDPSRELI Religious representatives set the tone in diplomatic negotiations. This improves negotiations with other races in the area of peace making. Also improves general diplomatic negotiating ability a little.
\*RDPSHAND Trade representatives set the tone in diplomatic negotiations. This improves negotiations with other races in the area of trade agreements and the profit from trade agreements.
\*RDPSWISS Scientific representatives set the tone in diplomatic negotiations. This improves the chances of scientific collaboration with other races.

\*RMEDDOMI The media dominate a large part of social life. Increases the efficiency of the Recreation DEA by 4. This also increases the creativity of the population: 0.5 additional test tubes per population point. Entertainment becomes a box office hit, which increases the efficiency of the Spaceports by 1. Through unsparing clarification, the agitation factor worsens by 3 and the suppression costs increase by 15%.
\*RMEDFREI The media are free from any censorship. Increases the efficiency of the recreational DEA by 2. Entertainment becomes a box office hit, which increases the efficiency of the Spaceports by 1. Decisions by the government and other established institutions can be questioned. Therefore, the agitation factor increases by 1 and the suppression costs by 5%.
\*RMEDAUSG Normal setting./p
\*RMEDZENS Anti-legislative or manipulative media are censored and sometimes banned. Reduces the efficiency of the recovery DEAs by 2 and the efficiency of the rooms by 1. It also lowers the suppression costs by 5%.

\*RWISPLAN Increases the efficiency of the production DEA by 2 and the efficiency of the mining and agricultural DEA by 1. Decreases the efficiency of the spaceport by 1.
\*RWISMARK Increases the conversion of resources by 1 and the AU generated by production by 10%. Production increases by 0.25 per population point. And increases the efficiency of the spaceports by 1.

\*RSPSMILI A military special unit regularly provides spies. Excellent defense service, increases the likelihood of exposing an enemy spy by 1. Hard drills increase the combat ability of the spies by 2.
\*RSPSINWI Spies specifically trained by industry and research increase the likelihood of successfully inserting the spy by 1 and the likelihood of successfully completing a mission by 2.
\*RSPSTERR An extremely fanatical training in espionage, which above all gives the spy increased combat ability by 2 and also increases the probability of not being detected on enemy territory.
\*RSPSGILD These are classic thief guilds and martial arts schools. The spy is endowed with many unusual skills. Its camouflage increases by 2, the likelihood of being smuggled in successfully by 1, the combat skills increase by 1 and the likelihood of successfully completing a mission by 1.
