\\System Specials
\*spSolWn Strong Stellar Winds
\*spSolWnD Strong Stellar Winds produce a large amount of radiation and elecromagnetic "pollution" in this system.  Items built here are commensurately more expensive.
\*spBtlSt Ancient Battle Site
\*spBtlStD This is an ancient battle field. Ancient and decrepit husks of blasted ships are in orbit around the sun.
\*spBtlLs Battle Lust
\*spBtlLsD An odd chemical reaction produces feelings of euphoria here, especially in stress filled situations such as combat. Units are less likely to retreat from battle in this system.
\*spAntarX Antaran X
\*spAntrXD An Antaran X may be recovered here. 
\\Ancient Battle Sites
\*spBat01 S1
\*spBat01D S1
\*spBat02 S2
\*spBat02D S2
\*spBat03 S3
\*spBat03D S3
\*spBat04 S4
\*spBat04D S4
\*spBat05 S5
\*spBat05D S5
\*spBat06 S6
\*spBat06D S6
\*spBat07 S7
\*spBat07D S7
\*spBat08 S8
\*spBat08D S8
\*spBat09 S9
\*spBat09D S9
\*spBat10 S10
\*spBat10D S10

\\Horror Table
\*spHor01 Giant Reptiles
\*spHor01D There are giant reptiles in this region./p Reduces population growth by -10% /p and damages the infrastructure, /p Production and mining each -5%. /p However, is well suited as a tourist attraction: + 10% recreation. /p Is eliminated by 2,000 to 5,000 AU investment in the military.
\*spHor02 Aggressive reptiles
\*spHor02D This region has particularly aggressive poisonous reptiles./p Reduces population growth by 20% /p and reduces mining and agricultural efficiency by 5%. /p Reduces recovery by 10%. /p Will be eliminated through 1,500 to 3,500 AU Terraforming investments.
\*spHor03 Huge Insectoids
\*spHor03D There are huge insects in this region./p Reduces population growth by 15% /p and damages infrastructure /p and mining -5%. /p Destroys agricultural land, /p Agricultural economy -5%. /p However, increases research by 5%. /p Eliminated by 2,000 to 5,500 AU investment in the military.
\*spHor04 Aggressive Insectoids
\*spHor04D There are particularly aggressive poisonous insects in this region./p Reduces population growth by 30% /p and agriculture by 50%, /p Mining by 10%, /p Recovery by -50%. /p However, research increases 5%. /p Can be used for military purposes./p Military-DEA +5%. /p Is eliminated by 2,500 to 6,000 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor05 Huge Aquanoids
\*spHor05D There are huge aquanoid life forms in this region./p Reduces population growth by 5% /p and mining and agriculture each 10%. /p However, it provides a 10% higher recovery effect./p Will be eliminated by 1,500 to 2,500 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor06 Aggressive Aquanoids
\*spHor06D There are particularly aggressive and toxic aquatic life forms in this region./p Reduces population growth by 10% /p and mining effect by 20%, /p Research by 30% /p and recovery 10%. /p Will be eliminated by 2,000 to 3,500 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor07 Huge Predators
\*spHor07D There are huge predators in this region./p Reduces population growth by 5%. /p Damages infrastructure./p Industry -10% /p Mining -5%. /p Increases the recreational effect as a tourist attraction by 10%. /p Will be eliminated by 1,500 to 4,000 AU investment in the military.
\*spHor08 Aggressive Predators
\*spHor08D There are particularly aggressive predators in this region./p Reduces population growth by 10%, /p Mining, research by 10%. /p Recovery -5%. /p Eliminated by 2,000 to 4,000 AU investment in the military.
\*spHor09 Harmful Pests
\*spHor09D There are special pests in this region. /p Reduces agriculture by 75%, /p Mining by 10%, research and recreation by -10%. Eliminated by 2,500 to 5,000 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor10 Harmful Microbes
\*spHor10D This region has particularly aggressive and tissue-eating microbes./p Reduces population growth by 25%, /p Mining and industry by 30%, /p Recovery -80%. /p Due to the rare chemical substances in the microbes research increased by +10 %. /p Eliminated by investing 5,000 to 1,0000 AU in research.
\*spHor11 Neural Viruses
\*spHor11D In this region there are viruses that damage the nervous system of the population./p Reduces government effect by 50%, /p Research 30% /p and recovery 75%, /p and military DEA -20% ./p Eliminated by 4,000 to 7,500 AU investment in research.
\*spHor12 Harmful Parasites
\*spHor12D There are harmful parasites in this region./p Reduces population growth by 25%./p Reduces agriculture by 10%. /p Recovery -50%. /p Eliminated by 3,000 to 5,500 AU investment in research.
\*spHor13 Neural Leeches
\*spHor13D In this region there are leeches that damage the nervous system of the population./p government effect -25%, /p recovery -50%, /p research -20% /p and military effect -25%. /p Eliminated by 4,000 to 7,000 AE investment in research.
\*spHor14 Radiated Mminerals
\*spHor14D There are aggressive radiated minerals in this region./p Reduces mining by 30%, /p Industry by 10%, /p Research by 10%. /p Cannot be eliminated.
\*spHor15 Huge Floral Life Form
\*spHor15D There are huge plants in this region that damage the country's infrastructure./p Reduces agriculture by 30%, /p Industry and mining by 10%. /p Counts as a tourist attraction, + 20% recreation./p Eliminated by 1,500 up to 3,000 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor16 Aggressive Flora
\*spHor16D There are particularly poisonous aggressive plants in this region./p Reduces population growth by -5%. /p Reduces recovery by -25%. /p Eliminated by 1,500 to 3,000 AU investment in terraforming.
\*spHor17 Harmful Fungal
\*spHor17D In this region there is harmful and toxic fungal grow./p Reduces population growth by 10%. /p Agriculture -25%, /p Recovery -50%. /p However, research increases by 5%. /p Eliminated by 2,000 to 3,000 AU investment in terraforming.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          
\*spHor18 Neural Drugs
\*spHor18D A strong drug is being obtained in this region./p Reduces research and government by 25%, /p Agriculture, industry and mining decreased by 5%, /p Military effect by -20%. /p However, enormously increases the recreational value by 25% /p and spaceport trade by 50%. /p Cannot be eliminated.
\*spHor19 Harmful Transcendent Life Forms
\*spHor19D There is a transcendent way of life in this region, which causes great damage to the population and the infrastructure./p Reduces agriculture, /p mining and industry by 50%. /p Reduces research, /p Government and recreation by 75%, /p and the military by 25%. /p Can not be eliminated.
\*spHor20 Harmful Underground Life Forms
\*spHor20D In this region there are harmful and toxic underground organisms./p Massively reduces the agriculture by 75%. /p Mining -50%. /p Eliminated by 4,000 to 7,500 AE investments in terraforming.


\\Monster Type Table

\\Guardian Force Table

\\Regional Specials
\*spAbCol Abandoned Colony
\*spAbColD At one time, this was the site of a colony that belonged to your race.  It is still habitable, though there is no sign of what happened to the previous colonists./p/p

Decreases Building Costs by 10-15%/p
Chance of Finding a Small Colony is 50/p
Chance of Finding a Medium Colony is 35/p
Chance of Finding a Large Colony is 15/p
Increases AUs in the Treasury by 200 to 500 for Medium Colony/p
Increases AUs in the Treasury by 400 to 1000 for Large Colony

\*spVolc Active Volcanoes
\*spVolcD An unusual amount of volcanic activity exists on this planet. This increases the cost of terraforming the planet considerably./p/p

Increases Planetary Terraforming Cost by 50%/p
Decreases Maximum Amount Planet can be Terraformed by 25%

\*spCache Cache
\*spCacheD A cache; see cache table.
\*spHorr Horror
\*spHorrD Horror
\*spOracl Mysteries
\*spOraclD Mysteries
\*spRes Resources
\*spResD Resources
\*spCave Cavernous
\*spCaveD This planet has a series of large, inhabitable caves underground.  This allows for more colonists to live on the planet, as well as providing some additional defense in combat./p/p

Increases Maximum Regional Population by 1 /p
Increases Ground Combat Fortification Value by 2

\*spContr Smugglers' Haven
\*spContrD This planet has long been used as a base for smugglers and other outlaws.  Efforts at tax collection and law enforcement will meet with considerable resistance, and valuable materials tend to 'vanish' on a regular basis./p/p

Decreases Government DEA Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Rare Bioharvest Value by 20%/p
Decreases Rare Mineral Value by 20%/p
Decreases Craftmanship Value by 20%

\*spElcAc Electrical Activity
\*spElcAcD The high amount of electrical activity on this planet interferes with electronics and communications.  As a result, DEAs relying on sensitive electronics and mass-communication are less efficient here./p/p

Decreases Research DEA Capacity by 1 /p
Decreases Manufacturing DEA Efficinecy by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 10%/p
Decreases Spaceport DEA Efficiency by 1

\*spMicrb Hostile Microbes
\*spMicrbD This region is infested with hostile microbes.  These microbes are immune to all known anti-bacterial agents, and severely limit population growth.  Nearly all areas of the economy are hampered to some degree, although study of the organisms can benefit research in the areas of medical science and bio-warfare./p/p

Decreases Population Industry by 2/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 50%/p
Increases Population Pollution by 4/p
Increases Research DEA Efficiency by 125%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 95%


\*spInsct Hostile Insect Life
\*spInsctD This region is infested with hostile insects.  These insects interfere with most types of production.  Safety precautions and filters make all regional buildings more expensive to build and maintain./p/p

Increases Construction and Maintenance Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Mine DEA Efficiency by 75%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 75%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spAniml Hostile Animal Life
\*spAnimlD Small hostile animals infest this region.  These animals are mostly pests, getting into food stores and warehouses, but they can also be dangerous in some circumstances, lowering population growth by a small amount./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 40%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spLAnim Large Hostile Animals
\*spLAnimD This region is the preferred hunting ground for packs of large predatory animals.  These animals will snatch livestock and even citizens, reducing both bioharvesting and population growth somewhat.  Some foolish tourists may actually come to this region specifically to hunt these animals./p/p

Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 75%

\*spHAnim Huge Hostile Animals
\*spHAnimD Massive predators roam this region at will.  These dangerous creatures can cause quite a bit of trouble for populations and livestock, but they provide a great training opportunity for shock troops, and in some cases can even be trained for military purposes themselves./p/p

Increases Military DEA Efficiency by 30%/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 35%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 30%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 60%

\*spFlora Hostile Flora
\*spFloraD A region of this planet is covered with hostile plant life.  These plants grow wildly and are deleterious to all known life forms.  They will choke and kill most regular food crops, and make for a generally unpleasant atmosphere, even reducing population growth by a small amount./p/p

Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Ecosystem Quality by 1/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 15%/p
Decreases Infrastructure by 15%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 80%

\*spHosMn Radioactive Minerals
\*spHosMnD The minerals in this region are contaminated by dangerous radioactive isotopes.  The additional processing and safeguards necessary to work with these minerals will greatly reduce the effectiveness of mining and industry in the region, and the background radiation inhibits population growth./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Mining Capacity by 1/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spWells Natural Wells
\*spWellsD Natural springs of exceptionally pure water exist in abundance in this region, encouraging population growth and tourism.  In addition, the efficiency of industry is boosted slightly by the ready availability of fresh water./p/p

Increases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spThriv Thriving Ecosystem
\*spThrivD The abundance of flora and fauna on this planet has resulted in a veritable cornucopia effect.  Bioharvesting planet-wide is vastly improved./p/p

Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Ecosystem Quality by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%
\*spPoll Fragile Ecosystem
\*spPollD The ecological balance on this planet is precarious at best.  The effects of pollution will be felt much more strongly here than is usually the case, and bioharvesting must be kept reasonably contained.  Also, great care must be taken when terraforming the planet, lest the balance be upset too much./p/p

Increases Pollution by 50%/p
Increases Terraform Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%
  
\*spRAnim Menagerie
\*spRAnimD A wide array of rare and unusual animals can be found in this region, increasing the income from bioharvesting and trade, as well as being popular with tourists and biological researchers./p/p

Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Increases Spaceport Capacity by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Rare Bioharvest Value by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 60%

\*spRFuel Natural Fuels
\*spRFuelD Rare natural fuel types can be found in this region, which provide modest increases to manufacturing and trade while producing considerably less pollution than synthetic fuels./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Pollution by 50%/p
Decreases Population Pollution by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spRGems Rare Gems
\*spRGemsD Several rare and very pure crystals and gemstones can be found in this region, greatly increasing the value of mineral products and manufactured goods, as well as boosting trade revenue and research./p/p

Increases Research Efficiency by 30%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Increases Craftmanship Value by 50%/p
Doubles Rare Mineral Value

\*spRMetl Rare Metals
\*spRMetlD Several sources of extremely rare metals can be found in this region, which increase the quality and value of mining products and manufactured goods.  The metals can also be traded and used in research./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Mining Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Craftmanship Value by 30%/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spRPtro Rare Petrochemicals
\*spRPtroD Rare chemical fuel types can be found in this region, which increase the effectiveness of manufacturing, research and trade efforts, but reliance on these fuels carries a penalty in increased pollution./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 50%/p
Doubles Pollution

\*spRPlnt Rare Plants
\*spRPlntD This region contains a wide variety of unusual plants.  They may be valued for their nutritious, aesthetic or scientific properties, or they may simply be valuable to others who will pay well for them in trade./p/p

Increases Bioharvest Capacity by 1/p
Increases Population Bioharvesting by 1/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 4/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 70%

\*spRRdio Rare Radioactives
\*spRRdioD Rare radioactive materials can be found in this region, which are useful for research and manufacturing, and of course can be traded away for quick profits.  The down-side is that background radiation has a deleterious effect on population growth./p/p
 
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 30%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 4/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 35%/p
Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 35%

\*spFLUs Primitive Species
\*spFLUsD A barely sentient species inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p

Generates Forced Labor Units/p
Doubles Unrest

\*spStElm Strategic Elements
\*spStElmD 
\*spEvent Event
\*spEventD
\*spWonder Natural Wonders
\*spWondD A series of awe-inspiring natural formations exist in this region.  People will flock to this region from all corners of the empire to view these wonders, and centers of government located here will also benefit from the added prestige./p/p

Increases Government DEA Efficiency by 4/p
Doubles Recreation DEA Efficiency/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spRandRs Random Research
\*spRanRsD A cache of stored research data has been found here. Twenty-five research points will be added at this planet for a short duration.
\*spRnTech Derelict Ship
\*spRnTecD The remains of a crashed vessel are uncovered on this planet.  Some of the technology on-board is apparently recoverable./p/p
\*spResLdr Rescued Leader
\*spResLdD A famous leader has been marooned on this planet for years, and is willing join your civilization in return for being rescued./p/p
\*spAnFund System anomaly
\*spAnFunD An anomaly in this solar system provides information about a new technology.

\\Cache Table
\*spCach1 Antaran Technology Cache
\*spCach1D An Antaran Technology Cache is located here. The first civ to discover this location gains a random Antaran Technology.
\*spCach2 Horror
\*spCach2D Planet keep producing hallucinations affecting population.
\*spCach3 Repairable Structures
\*spCach3D A series of repairable structures are located here, reducing the cost of building by 25%.
\*spCach4 Pirate Treasure
\*spCach4D A cache of gold, jewels and other valuables have been found here. These have been converted to AUs and the funds added to your treasury.  Once word gets out, treasure hunters from across your empire will flock to this planet, hoping to pick up anything your survey teams might have missed./p/p

Provides 50-500 AUs upon discovery/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 1
\*spCach5 Rare Aphrodisiac
\*spCach5D A rare Aphrodisiac exists here and will increase the planets population growth rate for a short time.
\*spCach6 Data Cache
\*spCach6D A cache of stored research data has been found here.  As much as can be recovered is sent out as soon as possible to all research installations, where it may help with some current projects.
\*spCach7 Antaran Technology Cache 
\*spCach7D An Antaran Technology Cache is located here. The first civ to discover this location gains a random Antaran Technology.

\\Mystic Table
\*spMyst1 Cooperative Reptiles
\*spMyst1D There are special reptilian indigenous people in this region./p Particularly useful in mining +20%. /p Industry +10%. /p Outstanding trappers Military DEA + 10%.
\*spMyst2 Cooperative Insectoids
\*spMyst2D There are special insectoid indigenous people in this region./p Particularly efficient in pollution and pest control, agriculture +50%. /p research +10%. /p Excellent senses: military DEA +10 %.
\*spMyst3 Cooperative Aquanoids
\*spMyst3D There are special aquatic indigenous people in this region./p Help with the depletion of maritime resources, mining +20%. /p Also useful with the exploration of deep maritime regions, research +20%. /p Suitable for training./p Recreational DEA + 20% / p and military DEA + 10%.
\*spMyst4 Trainable Animals
\*spMyst4D There are special animals in this region. Particularly useful for transport in inaccessible regions./p Improves mining +10%, /p Industry +20%, /p Agriculture + 20%. Suitable for training: recovery DEA + 30%.
\*spMyst5 Useful Microbes
\*spMyst5D There are useful microbes in this region. Their decomposing properties are particularly helpful in mining: +50%. /p Help with pest control: Agriculture +20%. /p Giving science new material: Research + 50%.
\*spMyst6 Symbionts
\*spMyst6D There are symbiotes in this region who can be used for the health and well-being of the population. /p Increases population growth by 25%. /p Increases the recovery by + 150% /p and research + 25%.
\*spMyst7 Useful Flora
\*spMyst7D In this region there are particularly useful plants that are suitable as building material./p Reduces construction costs by 50%. /p Industry + 20%.
\*spMyst8 Useful Pharmaceuticals
\*spMyst8D Health-promoting and awareness-enhancing medicines are obtained in this region./p Increases population growth by 20%. /p Improves recovery by 300%. /p Increases spaceport revenues by 200%.
\*spMyst9 Cooperative Transcendent Form of Life
\*spMyst9D In this region there is a transcendent form of life that promotes the mental strength of the population. /p Research +50%, /p Recreation +50%, /p Government DEA +20%. /p Excellent for the confusion of enemy invaders./p Therefore: Military-DEA + 20%.
\*spMyst10 Useful Underground Life Forms
\*spMyst11 There are particularly useful underground life forms in this region./p Increase cultivation efficiently /p Agricultural areas: Agriculture + 100%.

\\Resources Table
\*spRes2 Rare Radioactive Elements
\*spRes2D There are rare radioactive substances in this region./p Research +200%, /p Production +50%, /p Spaceport Effect +300%, /p Agriculture -20%.
\*spRes3 Rare Chemical Gases
\*spRes3D Rare gases have been discovered in this region./p Research +50%, /p Industry + 50% /p and mining +75%. /p spaceport effect + 100%.
\*spRes4 Rare Gemstones
\*spRes4D Particularly rare and beautiful gemstones are mined in this region. /p Research +200%, /p Spaceport effect + 300%.
\*spRes5 Rare Minerals
\*spRes5D There are rare minerals in this region./p Research +100%, /p Agriculture +100%. /p Spaceport Effect + 50%.
\*spres6 Rare Metals
\*spRes6D In this region there are special valuable metals./p Research +50%, /p Industry +100%. /p Spaceport effect + 200%.
\*spRes7 Rare Crops
\*spRes7D Valuable crops thrive in this region./p agriculture +300%, /p spaceport effect + 100%.
\*spRes8 Rare Animals
\*spRes8D A large number of rare and particularly sought-after animals live in this region./p Recovery effect +100%, /p Research +25%, /p Spaceport effect + 100%.
\*spRes9 Rare Rocks
\*spRes9D Rare rock is found in this region./p production +25%, /p spaceport effect + 50%.
\*spRes10 Rare Fossil Fuels
\*spres10D Extremely rare fuel can be produced in this region./p production +300%, /p spaceport effect +300%. /p pollution + 25%.

\\Refugee Table
\*spRefu2 S28
\*spRefu2D S28
\*spRefu3 S29
\*spRefu3D S29
\*spRefu4 S30
\*spRefu4D S30
\*spRefu5 S31
\*spRefu5D S31
\*spRefu6 S32
\*spRefu6D S32
\*spRefu7 S33
\*spRefu7D S33
\*spRefu8 S34
\*spRefu8D S34

\\Ruins Table
\*spRuin1 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin1D In this region there are ruins of a long-gone civilization, the population can take advantage of the well-preserved infrastructure./p Industry efficiency + 50%.

\*spRuin2 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin2D There are a lot of crumbling ruins in this region; the researchers discover tons of artifacts and technologies in it./p Spaceport effect +200%. / p Mining effect +25%. / p Is used up after 50 to 200 rounds.

\*spRuin3 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin3D In this region there are a number of well-preserved ruins which the population can use for living and expanding./p Maximum population +1.

\*spRuin4 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin4D In this region there are ruins of a long forgotten civilization, the researchers discover old records in data banks./p + 200% research./p Is used up after 50 to 200 rounds.

\*spRuin5 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin5D Quirky and curious ruins have been discovered in this region, which are ideal as a tourist attraction./p Recreation efficiency + 300%

\*spRuin6 Archaeological ruins
\*spRuin6D In this region there are crumbled ruins, there are a lot of valuable relics and artifacts to be discovered./p research +50%, / p spaceport effect +400%. / p is used up after 25 to 150 rounds.

\\Slave Races Table
\*spHumn Human Labor
\*spHumnD A lost colony of Humans inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spEvon Evon Labor
\*spEvonD A lost colony of Evons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spPsi Psilon Labor
\*spPsiD A lost colony of Psilons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spMek Meklar Labor
\*spMekD A lost colony of Meklar inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spCyn Cynoid Labor
\*spCynD A lost colony of Cynoids inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spSak Sakkra Labor
\*spSakD A lost colony of Sakkra inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spRaas Raas Labor
\*spRaasD A lost colony of Raas inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spGren Grendarl Labor
\*spGrenD A lost colony of Grendarl inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spTri Trilarian Labor
\*spTriD A lost colony of Trilarians inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spNommo Nommo Labor
\*spNommoD A lost colony of Nommo inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spIms Imsaeis Labor
\*spImsD A lost colony of Imsaes inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spEolad Eoladi Labor
\*spEoladD A lost colony of Eoladi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spSilic Silicoid Labor
\*spSilicD A lost colony of Silicoids inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spKlack Klackon Labor
\*spKlackD A lost colony of Klackons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spTachi  Tachidi Labor
\*spTachiD A lost colony of Tachidi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spIthk Ithkul Labor
\*spIthkD A lost colony of Ithkul inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spMeta Darlok Labor
\*spMetaD A lost colony of Darlocks inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spNonCo Noncorporeal Labor
\*spNonCoD A lost colony of Noncorporeals inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spProto Protoplasmic Labor
\*spProtoD A lost colony of Protoplasmics inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spPlant Plant Labor
\*spPlantD A lost colony of Plants inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spFungl Phaigour Labor
\*spFunglD A lost colony of Phaigor inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spAvian Alkari Labor
\*spAvianD A lost colony of Alkari inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spGarga Rhea Labor
\*spGargaD A lost colony of Rhea inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spBulra Bulrathi Labor
\*spBulraD A lost colony of Bulrathi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spMrrsh Mrrshan Labor
\*spMrrshD A lost colony of Mrrshan inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spEler Elerian Labor
\*spElerD A lost colony of Elerrians inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spGnol Gnolam Labor
\*spGnolD A lost colony of Gnolams inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spElder Elder Labor
\*spElderD A lost colony of Antarans inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.
\*spComBt Combot Labor
\*spComBtD A lost colony of ComBots inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Provides passive race benefits of these race to the planet and generates extra FLU's.

\\Planetary Specials
\*spBtlDm Ancient Battle Damage
\*spBtlDmD This planet was heavily damaged during some ancient battle. Battle damage is cheaper to repair than standard terraforming, allowing this planet to be terraformed for less than is normal.
\*spArtPl Artificial Planet
\*spArtPlD
\*spTrap Ancient Defense System
\*spTrapD
\*spEcOrb Eccentric Orbit
\*spEcOrbD This planet has an extremely elliptical orbit, resulting in an exceptionally large seasonal disparity.  It will cost considerably more to terraform the planet and bioharvesting is highly problematic./p/p

Increases Terraform Cost by 80%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%

\*spEntEc Entrapping Ecosystem
\*spEntEcD Visitors to this planet must take extreme precautions against the environment, not because it is toxic, but due to retro-virii that force the body to become dependant on substances only found on this planet.  This greatly reduces tourism and trade, and makes it very difficult to get soldiers or government officials to serve here./p/p

Decreases Government Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 40%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 3/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spHbMon Hibernating Monster
\*spHbMonD
\*spErWth Erratic Weather
\*spErWthD The highly erratic weather patterns on this planet make bioharvesting particularly difficult, and interfere with tourism and trade./p/p

Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 1/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spMetSh Meteor Showers
\*spMetShD 
\*spMgFld Strong Geomagnetic Fields
\*spMgFldD This planet has very strong magnetic fields. These fields interfere with the delicate instruments required for research and manufacturing, and also affect atmospheric and orbital craft, restricting military and trade operations./p/p

Increases Gravity Penalty by 1/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 15%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Research Efficiency by 40%/p
Increases Ground Combat Fortification by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 95%

\*spHStrm Global Storms
\*spHStrmD Huge, powerful storms rage across this planet constantly. Costs for building and maintaining structures here are greatly increased while bioharvesting is greatly reduced.  Military and civilian aircraft are somewhat hampered as well./p/p

Increases Construction Cost by 80%/p
Increases Maintenance Cost by 90%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 40%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 10%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spHTect Tectonic Instability
\*spHTectD 
\*spStRng Stratosphere Rings
\*spStRngD This planet has large rings around its equator.  The rings are an excellent tourist attraction and offer some research benefits, but they also provide a convenient hiding place for pirates and other less savory visitors./p/p

Increases Recreation Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 50%

\*spHGas Hostile Gases
\*spHGasD The atmosphere of this planet has significant amounts of toxins.  This reduces the efficiency of almost all aspects of life here./p/p

Increases Research Capacity by 3/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 250%/p
Increases Building Cost by 50%/p
Decreases Growth Rate by 75%

\*spMagnt Magnate Civilization
\*spMagntD This planet contains a previously unknown colony of a race long thought to be purely mythical, or destroyed by the New Orions.
\*spRpRot Corrosive Atmosphere
\*spRpRotD A large amount of corrosive material is in the atmosphere and soil of this planet, increasing the cost to maintain structures, and reducing the effectiveness of bioharvesting. This material is deadly to all forms of life, and corrosive to most materials. However, the chemicals contained in the atmosphere are of unique origin and of incredible value to research. The atmosphere has enchanced the formation of valuable mineral deposits and allowed them to remain untouched./p/p

Increases Maintenance Cost by 150%/p
Decreases Population Growth by 75%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 75%/p
Increases Research DEA Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spSntPl Hostile Planet
\*spSntPlD The life forms on this planet all share a collective mind and greatly resent outside life forms.  The planet itself seems to do everything possible to make your people's lives miserable./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Increases Unrest by 25%/p
Decreases Amount Planet can be Terraformed by 50%/p
Decreases Bioharvesting Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Mining Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Government Efficiency by 20%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spSplnt Splinter Colony
\*spSplntD A lost colony of your race has been located!  They are pleased to rejoin your empire after countless cycles./p/p

Maximum Population is between 1.5 and 3
\\Alien Devices Table
\*spAln02 S42
\*spAln02D S42
\*spAln03 S43
\*spAln03D S43
\*spAln04 S44
\*spAln04D S44
\*spAln05 S45
\*spAln05D S45
\*spAln06 S46
\*spAln06D S46
\*spAln07 S47
\*spAln07D S47
\*spAln08 S48
\*spAln08D S48


\\Monster Breeding Table
\*spMns02 S49
\*spMns02D S49
\*spMns03 S50
\*spMns03D S50
\*spMns04 S51
\*spMns04D S51
\*spMns05 S52
\*spMns05D S52
\*spMns06 S53
\*spMns06D S53
\*spMns07 S54
\*spMns07D S54
\*spMns08 S55
\*spMns08D S55

\\Event Table
\*spEvt01 S56
\*spEvt01D S56
\*spEvt02 S57
\*spEvt02D S57
\*spEvt03 S58
\*spEvt03D S58
\*spEvt04 S59
\*spEvt04D S59
\*spEvt05 S60
\*spEvt05D S60

\\Guardians
\*spDarHW Darlok Guardian
\*spDarHWD Your explorations have uncovered the devastated system of Nazin,
once home to the people of the Darlok empire. A Guardian of the New Orions
now occupies the system to keep curiosity-seekers at bay.
\*spBulHW Bulrathi Guardian
\*spBulHWD Your Task Forces have arrived at the remains of the
Ursa system. This once-proud home of the Bulrathi now lies in ruin, with
a Guardian of the New Orions standing watch and destroying those who would
dare to come here.
\*spMrrHW Mrrshan Guardian
\*spMrrHWD Task Forces report the discovery of the shattered Fieras system, rumored to have been the home system of the Mrrshan civilization. A Guardian of the New Orions now prowls within its bounds, striking swiftly at intruders.
\*spElrHW Elerian Guardian
\*spElrHWD You have stumbled upon the ruined system of Draconis, which legends
say was the seat of the vast empire of the Elerians. Now a hollow,
smoldering shell of its former glory, a lethal Guardian of the New Orions
moves between the worlds of the system, searching for trespassers.
\*spAlkHW Alkari Guardian
\*spAlkHWD The scattered, broken hulls drifting through Altair reveal that you have discovered the lost home system of the proud Alkari fleet. Now, the only active ship in the system is a Guardian of the New
Orions, a reminder of what happens to those who dare to oppose their power.
\*spPharm Pharmacopoeia
\*spPharmD This region has an unusual abundance of rare medicinal plants and herbs.  As a result, the population tends to be healthier and more productive here, as well as simply living longer.  The herbs are also a boon to trade and research efforts./p/p 

Increases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Rare Bioharvest Value by 40%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 50%

\*Starve Starve
\*Piracy Piracy
\*Subjugat Subjugated
\*LongWar War Fatigue
\*PopNoMv Overcrowded
\*UnderSge Under Siege
\*OthRevlt Other Planet in Revolt
\*UnresNBC War Atrocity
\*HiUnempl High Unemployment
\*TechAdvU Technological Advance
\*MilPres Military Presence
\*UnExcess Imperial Military Spending High
\*GovChange Government Change
\*UnDeficit Imperial Military Spending Low

\\New Specials
\*spSInst Seismic Instability
\*spSInstD A region of this planet sits upon a major tectonic fault line.  Earthquakes and other seismic disturbances are common, and all buildings have to be specially constructed, not to mention frequently repaired or rebuilt, increasing their cost dramatically.  Also, mining in some areas is totally out of the question, and fears of a major disaster adversely affect trade and recreation./p/p

Increases Construction and Maintenance Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Mine Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2

\*spFPln Friendly Planet
\*spFPlnD This planet has achieved a sort of mass sentience, which has learned to communicate with others.  The planet is curious and eager to learn about other intelligent life forms.  It is willing to help create the perfect environment for members of your race to live here, but requires that heavy industry be kept to a minimum./p/p

Can be Terraformed up to Paradise/p
Decreases Terraform Cost by 60%/p
Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Population Growth by 25%/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spSoRa Intense Solar Radiation
\*spSoRaD The atmosphere of this planet blocks much less of the sun's radiation than is normal, significantly reducing both bioharvesting and population growth, and playing havoc with planetary sensors, while providing a small boost to industry from the cheap and plentiful solar power./p/p

Decreases Galaxy Sensor Range by 50%/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spOrDe Orbital Debris
\*spOrDeD A large quantity of debris clutters up the orbit of this planet, making it difficult for ships to land or take off, and significantly reducing your ability to do any serious construction in orbit.  The only good news is that some of the debris is quite rich in valuable minerals, which should help your mining efforts./p/p

Decreases Shipyard Capacity by 1/p
Increases Mining Efficiency by 35%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2

\*spLPst Ancient Listening Post
\*spLPstD This planet contains ancient monitoring devices left by some long-forgotten race.  The technology is too alien to be reverse-engineered by your scientists, but the equipment itself appears to still be in decent working order./p/p

Increases Galaxy Sensor Range by 500
\*spPsych Rare Psychotropics
\*spPsychD Growing wild on this planet are plants and herbs with potent mind-altering effects. Use of these drugs reduces unrest sharply on the planet, and increases trade profits, but at the cost of rendering the local populace much less productive than normal./p/p

Decreases Unrest by 50%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Population Industry by 1/p
Decreases Population Research by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 75%
  
\\ List of disasters
\*spPak12 Rapid Decay
\*spPak12D Large amounts of corrosive substances in the atmosphere of this planet complicate production and mining, /p each by 15%. /p Interesting for research, + 5%.
\*spPak2 Eco Trap
\*spPak2D Visitors to this planet have to beware of it environment./p Although it is not toxic, it does contain retroviruses that make the body dependent on substances that only exist on this planet./p Spaceport effect -80%, /p recovery effect -95%, /p but research + 10%.
\*spPak3 Elliptical Orbit
\*spPak3D This planet has an extremely elliptical orbit and therefore exceptionally strong seasonal climate differences./p Terraform formation costs +200%, /p Agriculture -25%, /p Population growth -5%.
\*spPak4 Strong Magnetic Fields
\*spPak4D There are strong, changeable magnetic fields on this planet which mainly hinder production -25%. /p Military effect (DEA) -10%, /p and research -50%.
\*spPak5 Global Storms
\*spPak5D Huge storms rage continuously on this planet. /p Agriculture -25% /p and population growth -25%. /p Recreation -25%.
\*spPak7 Volcanic Activity
\*spPak7D There is unusually strong volcanic activity on this planet, which takes up a lot of space and money./p maximum population -1, /p terraforming costs + 50%. /p mining slightly improved by 5%.
\*spPak6 Tectonic Activities
\*spPak6D This planet is often shaken by strong tectonic activity./p Reduces population growth by 20%. /p Reduces Recreation by 75%, /p but increases mining by 5%.
\*spPak8 Stratosphere Ring
\*spPak8D This planet has large rings around its equator, /p, which hinders research with -25% and agriculture with -10 %./p However, an attraction for tourists: + 10% Recreation.
\*spPak9 Toxic Gases
\*spPak9D Toxic gases are generated in the interior of this planet, which regularly escape into the atmosphere./p Population growth -30%, /p Recreation -95%. /p Military defense + 5%.
\*spPak10 Meteor Shower
\*spPak10D This planet often falls victim to meteorite strikes. /p Population growth -10%, /p Recreation -75%. / P Research and mining each gain 5%.
\*spPak11 Sensitive Ecosystem
\*spPak11D The planet's ecosystem reacts very sensitively to external influences. Pollution + 50%.

\\ List of wonders
\*spWun2 Adapting Ecosystem
\*spWun2D The ecosystem of this planet adapts perfectly to every change./p Environmental pollution -50%. /p Research + 25%.
\*spWun3 Cave System
\*spWun3D The entire planet is crisscrossed by a complex cave system./p maximum population + 2. /p military defense + 50% /p and mine effect + 15%.
\*spWun4 Natural Energy Sources
\*spWun4D This planet has many natural energy sources to offer, /p which makes production easier (+50%), /p and reduces pollution (-10%).
\*spWun5 Natural Wonder
\*spWun5D There are natural wonders and attractions on this planet. The recovery increases by 100%. /p The trading income by 20%.
\*spWun6 Abnormal Geology
\*spWun6D There are geological and geothermal anomalies on this planet. This interests researchers who work 50% more efficiently, /p increases mining by 60%.
\*spWun7 Favorable Axis Inclination
\*spWun7D This planet has a particularly good axis inclination. Outstanding agricultural yields are possible: Bioharvesting DEA's 50% more efficient /p and research increased by 20%.
\*spWun8 Artificial Planet
\*spWun8D This is an artificially created planet of an extinct prehistoric civilization. Our researchers are already sitting in the colony ships to investigate the nature of the planet./p Research DEA +150%. /p Attraction for tourism: Recreation DEA +100%. /p Optimal adaptation to agriculture and ecology. Agriculture + 100% and pollution -50%. /p Widespread underground cave system - improves infrastructure and living space./p Industry +20%, /p maximum population + 1 /p and better military defense. Military-DEA +50%. /p However, the planet seems to have hardly any minerals: /p Mining-DEA -50%.

\\List of Magnate Civilizations
\*spZiv1 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv1D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It is apparently a traditional craft culture./p It has advantages in production.
\*spZiv2 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv2D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It appears to be a traditional warrior culture./p It has defense benefits.
\*spZiv3 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv3D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It is apparently a innovative culture./p It has advantages research.
\*spZiv4 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv4D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. Art and entertainment in particular are particularly inviting in this culture./p Effective recreational DEAs.
\*spZiv5 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv5D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It is apparently a traditional farming culture./p Improved agricultural yield.
\*spZiv6 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv6D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It is apparently a traditional merchant culture. /p More profit from the spaceports.
\*spZiv7 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv7D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It appears to be an `ecologically perfect culture./p Reduced environmental impact.
\*spZiv8 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv8D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. It appears to be a traditional mining culture./p Improved mining.
\*spZiv9 Prewarp Civilization
\*spZiv9D There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. This culture fits perfectly into our empire./p Makes governance easier./p More effective government DEAs.
\*spZivN Prewarp Civilization
\*spZivND There is a prewarp civilization of our species on this planet. This culture is difficult to integrate into our empire./p Disadvantages in almost all areas./p It will take some time for the military to eliminate the unruly forces.